<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul  7 14:30:24 2003</date>
  <content>
POULTRY GROWERS RATTLED

Snow Hill, Md. -- Jeanne Shockley stands with her hands on her hips, 
squinting in the midday sun as her husband arrives in his pickup truck, the 
tires kicking up dust clouds as it brakes to a stop. She called him in from 
the fields because the electricity went off again in one of the long, 
low-slung corrugated metal sheds behind her, and inside, the temperature is 
rising. It won't take long for this to become a problem for the nearly 
20,000 growing chicks inside. Without power on hot summer days, it's nearly 
impossible to keep chickens from overheating. When they're chicks, giant 
heat lamps keep the birds at a constant 88 degrees. As they get bigger, 
industrial-strength fans blow through the chicken houses, and an overhead 
fogging system intermittently mists them with cool water. "The whole idea of 
the situation here is to grow 'em till they're fat," said Virgil Shockley, 
who raises more than half a million birds each year on Maryland's Eastern 
Shore for Tyson Foods. After 42 days, the birds will weigh 41/2 pounds and 
will become rotisserie roasters for supermarkets, one of the many 
specialized products that have helped the industry combat lagging 
consumption of chicken, bloated supplies and competition from foreign 
imports.

This will be one of the last flocks the Shockleys raise for Tyson. The 
nation's largest poultry company is pulling out of Maryland, starting the 
process at its Berlin factory over the holiday weekend by reducing the 
workforce. Until now, trucks brought an estimated half-million chickens to 
the plant every day. This week, Wednesday deliveries will cease and the 
number of birds processed the rest of the week will begin to shrink. Farmers 
such as the Shockleys, who are hired to raise the chickens, wonder whether 
the three remaining poultry companies that operate in the state -- Perdue 
Farms, Allen Family Foods and Mountaire Farms -- will fill the void. 
Weighing heavily on their minds is whether, and how, Maryland's new governor 
will keep his campaign promise to make Maryland once again friendly to 
business. Their concern is, of course, poultry. Worth $552 million a year, 
chickens represent the largest segment of the state's $1.6 billion farming 
industry. When a giant such as Tyson shuts down a processing plant, it sends 
ripples across the state.

Gov. Robert L. Ehrlich Jr. (R) has said he thinks less regulation and more 
cooperation is the way to promote business and stimulate the economy. 
Environmentalists fear he is poised to let the farming community slide on 
the critical job it needs to do to stop polluting the Chesapeake Bay 
watershed. For poultry farmers, the fear is that market forces will prove 
greater than anything the governor could do to help them, spelling doom to 
the family farms of Delmarva. "If you don't have poultry on the Shore, then 
you don't have farms," said Virgil Shockley, a third-generation crop and 
poultry farmer. When he found out that Tyson was leaving, Shockley called 
the company and asked whether they wanted him to grow chickens for their 
Temperanceville plant in Virginia. The answer was no. He started dialing 
everyone he could think of -- the county economic development board, other 
commissioners, agriculture specialists, other poultry companies. By the time 
he got to state officials, the message was already clear: Something needed 
to be done to ensure that Tyson's departure wasn't the beginning of the end 
of the poultry industry in Maryland. "Who else do I need to call?" Shockley 
asked Agriculture Secretary Lew Riley. "Nobody," Riley replied. "You've done 
enough."

</content>

</doc>
