<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Jan 29 22:33:59 2004</date>
  <content>

Birds were dying on an island off the coast of Florida, and people 
didn't know why. A group of conservationists wondered if the culprit might be 
a pesticide sprayed into the air to wipe out mosquitoes. The explanation 
quickly came from an unlikely source in Wisconsin.
For several years, Warren Porter, a professor of zoology at the University of 
Wisconsin-Madison, has been working with faculty and staff across campus to 
develop a computer model that could predict how animals, living on a real 
landscape anywhere on Earth, would respond to specific changes in the environment. 
The model could answer questions, such as how warmer temperatures would alter 
the activity patterns of squirrels in southern California or how removing the 
forest canopy in Yellowstone National Park would affect the elk that took 
cover under it during winter.
"If we fail to answer questions like these, we will continue to lose species 
- and their genomes, the biological libraries that have accumulated 
information for billions of years - from this planet," says Porter.
But many of the models that had been designed to address ecological concerns, 
he adds, were inadequate: They didn't take into account the complexity of 
factors involved in the interaction between animals and their environment. To 
achieve a more sufficient model, Porter needed to integrate animal morphology, 
physiology and behavior with features of the climate, topography and vegetation 
of a particular area. 
"Models are always an approximation to reality," he explains. "You design 
them to ask specific questions. As the questions become more complex, the models 
become more complex. As computers have gained more power, we have been able to 
continue to add complexity and to solve very difficult problems."
At the heart of Porter's integrated model is an understanding of energy 
transfer between animals and their surroundings. For instance, the animal's 
physical properties - body size, fur thickness, body temperature and breathing rate - 
help determine how much energy it needs to survive. The animal's behavioral 
patterns, such as how often it reproduces or how active it is, also are 
important factors. 
To apply this information in a real context, scientists must also determine 
how much energy is available based on environmental factors, including 
rainfall, temperature, vegetation, topography, sun exposure and time of day or year. 
The model, which incorporates remote satellite sensing and large-scale global 
climate models, can determine this.
Because Porter's model integrates all this information on animal physiology 
and behavior and climate conditions in a predictive model, the scientist says, 
"it can help us understand what the critical processes are that affect life 
processes on earth and how specific changes in environmental conditions may 
modify or even terminate those life processes." </content>

</doc>
