<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 10 00:26:08 2003</date>
  <content>You've undoubtedly heard of having therapy. But you may never 
have heard of having a therapy session with a rabbit. 
But that's exactly what Northfield Elementary School teacher Pam Bernardini 
offers once a week. She heads off with her rabbit Jillian, as well as a 
fifth-grade student from the school, to visit the Mayo Healthcare facility in 
Northfield to brighten the day of the facility's senior citizen residents. 
Jillian is certified to provide animal-assisted activities and therapy to the 
elderly and disabled. 
"I've had rabbits for the past 15 years or so," Bernardini said. "I had heard 
about the positive effect pets can have on senior citizens, so three years 
ago I went to Middlebury to attend a Pet Partners training course." 
Pet Partners, established in 1990 by the non-profit Delta Society, based in 
Portland, Ore., is a program that establishes guidelines for person-animal 
volunteer teams to qualify them to enter hospitals, nursing homes, and other 
facilities. 
The nationwide program registers teams that successfully complete health and 
temperament screening and volunteer training. Pet Partner animals include 
dogs, cats, rabbits, guinea pigs, domesticated rats, horses, and potbellied pigs. 
"I took the day-long course with my Flemish Giant rabbit Emma, to learn how 
to become a therapy rabbit," Bernardini said. "I worked with Emma on the things 
that we learned, and a year later we returned to Middlebury to become tested 
and certified." 
After passing the test, the rabbit became a regular visitor at the Mayo 
Healthcare facility in Northfield. 
Emma died last year and Bernardini adopted Jillian, an English Lop rabbit 
from Saco, Maine, a month later. English Lops are big rabbits with extremely long 
ears that alone are conversation stoppers. 
The teacher immediately began training the new pet, and on Sept. 13th she 
took Jillian to be tested for Pet Partners certification. Rated on temperament, 
appearance, grooming, obedience, and the performance of specific tasks, Jillian 
scored 35 out of a possible 36 points. 
Bernardini has resumed her schedule of visiting the Mayo nursing home once a 
week to work with the residents. 
"Sometimes people who are shy and reserved seem to identify with a rabbit 
more than with a dog or another animal," Bernardini said. "A therapy pet often 
opens up conversations about pets that the residents once had, and they become 
very attached to them. It's a change in their day." 
Bernardini also sees a positive effect on the children in her class, who take 
turns accompanying the teacher to the nursing home. 
"It is good for 10-year-old kids to recognize the importance of volunteering 
their time to work with others. They enjoy meeting the senior citizens and 
talking to them." 
Mayo Healthcare Activities Director Kim Marcotte agreed that the visits 
benefit everyone. 
"The rabbit has a very calming effect on the residents," Macotte said. "There 
is also wonderful interaction between the generations. 
Children and animals bring life to an institution, and the combination of the 
two make the visits extra special for the people here." 





</content>

</doc>
