<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jan  7 14:14:39 2004</date>
  <content>
Terrorists are targeting our pigs and potatoes. So argues the U.S. 
government, which has been putting our money where its fears are. The Bush 
administration has spent billions of dollars to prevent foreign agents from 
introducing diseases into livestock and crops. From Holsteins to hamburgers, 
though, our food supply doesn't seem any the safer for it.

Mad cow disease is today's headlines. One infected cow in Washington state 
has revealed the weaknesses of our food-supply system and the unwillingness 
of industry and government to respond to a genuine public health threat. 
Agro-terrorism experts, by contrast, are worried about tomorrow's headlines.

"We don't want to get so self-important that we think the only way to do 
damage to our country is by attacking human beings," Arthur Kaplan, a 
University of Pennslyvania bioethicist, told Minnesota Public Radio last 
year. "You could certainly bring this country to its knees by attacking its 
food supply."

"We're not going to run out of food because of a terrorist attack," said 
agro-terrorism researcher Anne Kohnen. "But the loss of markets overseas 
could be devastating." Agriculture is 13 percent of the United States gross 
domestic product and agricultural exports total $140 billion annually: a fat 
bull's-eye for terrorists.

American livestock, concentrated in certain areas (such as pigs in the 
Midwest) is particularly vulnerable. An outbreak of hoof-and-mouth disease, 
such as the one that devastated the British cattle industry, could cost the 
U.S. industry $24 billion. And this figure, according to Harley Moon, 
University of Iowa emeritus professor of veterinary pathology, 
underestimates the full damage because it doesn't include indirect costs 
like lost tourism revenues.

This all sounds alarming. But it's largely hypothetical. The only case of 
agro-terrorism in the United States was the result of domestic actors: a 
religious cult that infected several Oregon salad bars with salmonella in 
1984. Nor have been there been many cases of agro-terrorism overseas.</content>

</doc>
