<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul  7 13:47:11 2003</date>
  <content>
FOOD POISONING EATS AWAY MUM'S BODY

A mother of four has, according to this story, lost both legs, nearly all of 
her fingers and part of her nose after contracting a rare type of food 
poisoning. Debbie West, 37, believes she became sick from eating salami. She 
nearly died and was on life support in a Brisbane hospital for five weeks. 
The story says that Mrs West, who runs a Northern Territory crash repair 
business with her husband Nick in Katherine, fell ill in mid-March. She was 
diagnosed with hemolytic uremic syndrome, know as "hamburger disease" 
because it is usually contracted through eating uncooked meat. Doctors are 
at a loss to explain why a healthy woman in her 30s has been struck down by 
the disease.

Mrs West was rushed to Royal Darwin Hospital after becoming cold and turning 
purple. "All her organs started to shut down and so doctors induced her into 
a coma," Ms Cowie said. "Her body was under so much stress that they 
couldn't allow her to breath on her own so they ventilated her. Her kidneys 
weren't working, so she was put on dialysis."

Mrs West was flown to Brisbane's Princess Alexandra Hospital. As a side 
effect of the syndrome, she suffered severe blood clotting and surgeons were 
forced to carry out a series of amputations. She had her legs cut off from 
10cm below the knees and lost all the fingers on her right hand and parts of 
her fingers on her left hand. Doctors are hoping skin grafts will save what 
is left. Mrs West also has had the tip and septum of her nose amputated. 
"How she is alive is amazing. Nobody expected her to live through this," Ms 
Cowie said. "I can't help thinking that she has survived because of all the 
people behind her. "She has her bad days where she thinks it's unfair. But a 
lot of the time she looks to the brighter side of it and now she's just 
concentrating on having the operations, doing the rehabilitation and getting 
home."

</content>

</doc>
