<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Feb 10 22:25:48 2004</date>
  <content>
So was he fat or svelte or maybe a tad chubby? Was it really a slip on the
ice or could it have been something else - even, dare it be said,
something he ate?

Now there are confidential documents passed to the news media, and still
more dueling authorities, not to mention the ticklish matter of the mayor
and the doctor's widow and the promised steak dinner.
...
The latest twist is the publication in The Wall Street Journal on Tuesday
of details from Dr. Atkins's confidential medical report. The report
concludes that Dr. Atkins, 72, had a history of heart attack and
congestive heart failure and notes that he weighed 258 pounds at death.
...
Dr. Fleming was not a treating physician, and, according to Ms. Borakove,
did not say he was. A critic of the Atkins diet, he passed the report on
to a group he was acquainted with, the Physicians Committee for
Responsible Medicine, which promotes a vegetarian diet and denounces the
Atkins plan.

The Physicians Committee gave the report to The Journal. Ms. Borakove said
that a television station in New York apparently also has a copy, because
it called her last week. (The Physicians Committee furnished a copy
yesterday to The Times.)
...
Dr. Neal Barnard, president of the Physicians Committee for Responsible
Medicine, made it clear that it was not Dr. Atkins's health alone that
interested him. "I'm concerned about the Atkins machine trying to play the
card that Atkins was healthy and thin into old age," he said. In his view,
the Atkins diet "was and is an imminent public health threat."

Dr. John McDougall, a member of the Physicians Committee and an internist
who had debated Dr. Atkins, said there was no doubt that Dr. Atkins had
lost weight after his cardiac arrest, but before that was a different
story. "I knew the man," he said. "He was grossly overweight. I thought he
was 40 to 60 pounds overweight when I saw him, and I'm being kind."</content>

</doc>
