<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Apr 23 07:29:37 2004</date>
  <content>
The American habit of eating large amounts of meat is a major threat to
human health, the environment, small communities and farmers, according to
speakers at recent conference at the Bloomberg School of Public Health
(JHSPH) entitled "Eating for the Future: Can Public Health Rise to the
challenge?"

Scientists from diverse fields met at JHSPH to discuss whether humans need
meat in the quantity it is consumed in the United States, how our levels
of meat consumption affect American health and whether meat production
actually pollutes our environment.
...
On campus, the diet choice for students with regard to meat is diverse.
Many students eat a traditionally American amount of meat, such as
sophomore David Burgess who said "I eat meat at every meal." Others don't
feel meat is a necessity but eat it frequently, such as sophomore Karen
Lopez, who said "I don't need to eat meat every day. I do eat meat every
day, but it's not a necessity."

In sharp contrast to these views on meat consumption are the views of
senior Michael Brown, who is informally know as "Vegan Mike" by his
friends and acquaintances.

Brown summarized his views on meat eating, saying "the reason I don't eat
meat is that I think that raising animals in a factory farm environment
increases unnecessary suffering. I'm also a big fan of the fact that my
diet is cholesterol free." Brown, who has been a vegan since his freshman
year, and a vegetarian since he was 15 years old, also said that "the laws
regarding free range chicken are ridiculously loose," when asked about the
classification developed to give consumers an alternative to factory-
farmed livestock. While he supports attempts to reduce the suffering of
animals that are farmed for meat, he is still fundamentally opposed to the
slaughter of animals for food, saying "I don't feel that there is a humane
form of killing."



</content>

</doc>
