<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 13:49:53 2003</date>
  <content>

Last weekend, an American soldier killed a
rare Bengal tiger in its cage in the Baghdad zoo.

The caged tiger’s capital offense: biting a drunken G.I. when he
baited the animal by sticking his arm in its cage in an attempt to
feed it. The tiger reportedly tore off one of the G.I.’s fingers
and mauled his arm, before another soldier shot it in the head
three times.

Fatal encounters with carousing Americans troops aside, by the
year 2150 zoos and test tubes will likely be the only places that
Bengal tigers and all other man-eating predators will survive,
according to natural history writer David Quammen in his new
book, “Monster of God: The Man-Eating Predator in the Jungles
of History and the Mind.”

Quammen eschews “zoological melodrama” or “predator
pornography,” as he dubs the pulpy genre that encompasses
most true-life tales of encounters between humans and the
carnivores that occasionally eat them. His book is less monster
bloodbath than an effort to understand how humans and their
sometime predators still (barely) coexist today, and what exactly
will be lost if the big cats, bears and crocodiles go extinct.
When you’re in the Russian Far East, one native Udege man
tells you that he’s personally killed four Siberian tigers. There
are only a few hundred of these tigers left in the world. You
write that hearing this was like a splash of “cold water,” but
that since you’ve been traveling to investigate alpha-predator
populations that share land with humans, you’ve learned that the
“the world is full of cold water” and you’ve often found yourself
“chilly and wet.” What do you mean by that?

I started the book project partially because I was very interested
in what big predators meant to the people who live closest to
them, who live in the highest jeopardy.
Which humans have the most to fear from these alpha predators?

The people who suffer the most inconvenience, the most danger,
the most misery from big predators, the ones who pay the costs
of big predators, are generally the poor and the dispossessed of
land. They’re native people who live very close to the landscape
with a very small margin of safety.

Are there any good examples of that kind of rearrangement?

Only a very few pilot projects or beginning programs that need
to be built.

One of them is in the Northern Territory of Australia, where
Aboriginal people are being allowed to begin harvesting crocodiles
again.

Those people live out there in crocodile habitat, and if anybody
is going to be killed by a saltwater crocodile, they’re sort of the
first in the crosshairs. But now they’re also being allowed to
harvest crocodile skin.

</content>

</doc>
