<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Feb 12 22:41:33 2004</date>
  <content>
It was a billboard on a crosstown Manhattan bus that got me thinking. The
rolling PSA said something like this: "1 in 500 Americans have AIDS. Only
1 in 250 know." Instantly, my mind responded: 1 in 2 Americans will die of
heart disease. And this: Every seven seconds, an American dies of cancer.

From there, the list grew to:
...
* Former Surgeon General C. Everett Koop said in 1988, "Eight out of the
ten leading causes of death in America are what you are eating."

Need I go on? There's a self-induced health holocaust/mass suicide going
on that dwarfs any other health crisis in America...and the fallout isn't
only affecting our bodies, it's destroying our planet, funneling ever-more
taxpayer dollars to multi-national corporations, and hijacking our humanity.
...
March 20 also happens to be the 20th anniversary of the annual Great
American Meatout (http://www.meatout.org/) during which non-vegetarians
are encouraged to "kick the meat habit (at least for a day) and explore a
wholesome, nonviolent diet of fruits, vegetables, and whole grains."
...
 FEAR OF A VEGAN PLANET

Like so many other aspects of American life, we've relinquished control of
our eating habits to the corporate pirates and their well-paid
indoctrination, eating animals is as "normal" as breathing while the
consequent animal cruelty required to sustain this lifestyle is, at worst,
considered a necessary evil on all sides of the political spectrum.

It's quite a psychological quantum leap to no longer perceive that cow as
a soulless source of protein, but this is precisely the type of emotional
and cultural advance that may spur further introspection into our other
illogical habits, i.e. operating health facilities on a for-profit basis,
renting oneself out as a wage slave eight hours a day, and believing
there's a difference between Republicans and Democrats. The choice is ours.

Veganism welcomes all and requires no political label or pedigree. When
you go vegan, we each make a difference (at least) three times a day.

As Dylan sang: "I'll let you be in my dreams if I can be in yours."
...
 Mickey Z. is the author of two upcoming books: A Gigantic Mistake:
Articles and Essays for Your Intellectual Self-Defense (Prime Books) and 
 Seven Deadly Spins: Exposing the Lies Behind War Propaganda (Common
Courage Press). His most recent book is    The Murdering of My Years:
Artists and Activists Making Ends Meet.  He has been a vegan for nearly
nine years and can be reached at mzx2@earthlink.net.
</content>

</doc>
