<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Jun 15 23:18:06 2003</date>
  <content>
DISEASES BY DESIGN 

From Buzz to Bowwow
In his research, Xu induced tumors in flies by genetic screens in mosaic 
animals (a technique not possible in mice) to remove a tumor-suppressing 
gene from a small number of the insects' somatic cells. As in patients with 
cancer, the flies carried the mutation in some cells, and tumors 
consequently developed, Xu says. He then saved the flies from tumorigenesis 
by introducing a human LATS1 (large tumor suppressor) gene into a model 
lacking the fly homolog. His lab also generated mice deficient for LATS1; 
tumors developed in these mice as well.

The work showed that an invertebrate tumor suppressor is also a tumor 
suppressor in mammals, Xu says. It also uncovered evidence that LATS1 is a 
negative regulator for enzymes that drive the cell cycle, he adds. Once 
initial studies are finished on mice or other small organisms, researchers 
sometimes turn to larger models, such as cats or dogs. Besides the 
advantages of size and longevity, diseases that affect humans will sometimes 
spontaneously develop. Haskins works specifically with these kinds of cat 
and dog models, running an NIH-funded resource that makes the models 
available for research.

The animals "come to us because they have been sick, so they're relevant 
models," he says. He oversees colonies of cats and dogs with 25 different 
genetic diseases, including lysosomal storage diseases, congenital heart 
disease, skin disease, erythrocyte enzyme disorders, congenital deafness, 
and X-linked severe combined immunodeficiency. His research focuses on 
applications of gene therapy for lysosomal storage diseases, which are 
caused by inherited genetic defects that result in an enzyme deficiency. 
Haskins has successfully prevented clinical manifestations of one such 
disease, mucopolysaccharidosis VII, a rare and inherited degenerative 
disorder that is generally fatal in both dogs and humans.

</content>

</doc>
