<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Dec  4 14:59:13 2003</date>
  <content>
Why Target Greenpeace?


The American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) works in courts, legislatures and 
communities to defend and preserve individual rights and liberties 
guaranteed by the Constitution and laws of the United States. The People for 
the American Way Foundation advocates legal and social justice and the 
fundamental rights and freedoms of the Constitution.


Editor’s note: The following is an excerpt from the amicus brief filed by 
the ACLU and PFAWF. Click here to read the whole brief.


For two hundred years, the United States government has refrained from 
prosecuting advocacy groups whose members occasionally engage in peaceful 
civil disobedience to convey a constitutionally protected message.


The prosecution of Greenpeace indicates a sea change in that policy. Until 
now, only individual members of those groups have been prosecuted for their 
nonviolent, albeit unlawful, acts of civil disobedience. Greenpeace asserts, 
and there is reason to believe, that the government has selectively 
prosecuted it because of the content of its message. Selective prosecution 
violates the First Amendment and equal protection rights of Greenpeace; it 
also threatens every advocacy group whose message may offend the government 
of the moment.


The government’s radical departure from two hundred years of history invites 
the closest scrutiny. It has chosen to prosecute Greenpeace, an organization 
that regularly criticizes government policies, for the civil disobedience of 
its members. Using an arcane statute designed to deter the even more arcane 
practice of sailor-mongering, the government apparently seeks to silence 
Greenpeace, despite already having prosecuted and punished the individual 
Greenpeace "climbers" who performed the acts of protest aboard the vessel 
Jade.


This prosecution threatens the very existence of Greenpeace, and because it 
appears to be based upon the content of its message, imperils the core 
values of the Constitution to which the ACLU and PFAWF are dedicated.




</content>

</doc>
