<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Apr 27 06:58:19 2004</date>
  <content>

 The situation we face here is that the public and 3 of 4 parliamentary 
 parties support a battery farm ban. The fourth party, the conservatives, 
 in government, want to defend battery farming to the end. Is it 
 possible, if we put all energy and imagination into it, to exert so much 
 pressure onto an unwilling government, to ban an industry under these 
 circumstances, which is in itself quite powerful and big. Time will tell.
 
 The date for the parliamentary-debate of the battery farm ban has been 
 moved from the 20th to the 27th of April, i.e. next Tuesday. The 
 Conservative Party delegation has agreed to meet me 15 minutes before 
 the debate to be handed over all the petitions we have collected since 
 beginning of March (which are 5000). We have a little surprise for them 
 then. In any case, here is what happened between 14th April and today.
 
 1) On 15th April, a weekly magazine published a debate between me and 
 the agricultural minister, albeit this debate was only done on the 
 phone, arranged by the journalist. I critisized the law, he only wanted 
 to brand me and animal rights as radical.
 
 2) On 15th April also, the by far biggest weekly magazine in Austria 
 arranged a debate between the head of the government comission on the 
 animal issue, the battery farmer of Austria's largest battery farm 
 (450.000 hens), the agricultural minister and me, believe it or not. The 
 comission spokeswoman critisized the government but was very held back 
 in her arguments. The battery farmer was shocked to see me on the table 
 and said I belong in prison and not here. He would have refused to come 
 had he known I was here, he said. He claimed to love his birds and that 
 his way of keeping them is in their best interest. The minister doubted 
 that I as a vegan are in a position to debate the keeping of farm 
 animals. He said consumers should decide, not the law. I said that only 
 vegans can really represent the animals' interests, because only they 
 have not their own interests in the animals, i.e. they do not suffer a 
 collision of interests between theirs and those of the animals. We had 
 broken into 5 battery farms owned by the battery farmer on the table and 
 had brought him to court, in answer he had brought charges against me, 
 so the two of us were not too friendly with each other. But eventually, 
 it became a hot debate between the minister and me on battery farming. 
 The whole thing lasted 2 hours and was supposed to be published 
 yesterday, but was delayed for a week. I hope its not the Conservatives 
 succeeding in trying to hinder it.
 
 3) Today, just now, we have our 54th demo for a battery farm ban since 
 21st February, when we started with the demo campaign. In our latest 
 siege of the ministry of agriculture on Wednesday 21st, the minister 
 actually came out and confronted the activists. He claims we should not 
 protest outside his ministry, as he is not in the position to ban 
 battery farming, only the government can do that.
 
 4) The flyposting is running on a high. So far, 1500 placards have been 
 put up everywhere. 2 people have been arrested while flyposting, quite a 
 new police tactic. It has not been known that ever anybody has been 
 arrested for such an offence. Also, as there are presidential elections 
 this Sunday, the Conservatives have started paying watch groups to guard 
 their placards and chase activists putting up anti-conservative posters. 
 A number of confrontations were had, but all went ok, i.e. so far all 
 activists escaped unharmed.
 
 5) For the presidential elections, we had asked all candidates on their 
 opinion on battery farming and the animal issue. The conservative 
 candidate was the only one trying to evade anwering our questions. She 
 said she finds the law as it is sufficient. We put as much energy as 
 possible into spreading this view, through demos and posters and 
 leafletting etc. She reacted last Sunday 19th by putting out a press 
 release saying that the law, indeed, should be tightened. Obviously she 
 feels the pressure, although she did not want to say exactly in which 
 way the law should be tightened. Yesterday, activists tried to disrupt 
 her last public rally before the elections tomorrow. Police intervened, 
 but some disruption was achieved and our banners were visible to 
 everybody. Lets hope she is not our new president after this Sunday.
 
 6) But yesterday we succeeded in our biggest coup as yet. On Thursday, 
 the agricultural chamber had organized a visit with experts to the first 
 Austrian battery farm with enriched cages. Their press release said how 
 wonderful this farm is, and what a compromise, with happy healthy birds. 
 As it happened, in the night after this visit, and BEFORE their press 
 release went out, activists visited the very same farm in the night and 
 got good footage of fotos and videos of the farm and its awful 
 conditions, of dead rotting birds in the cages and of birds without 
 feathers. So, we were in the position to counter their PA immediately 
 with our own PA that showed pictures of the very same farm which were 
 only 5 hours old!! They must have been steaming, as well as wondering 
 where in their midst the whistle blower might be!!
 
 7) In preparing new actions, I have spoken to journalists from state TV. 
 They told me that our campaign is a big issue in the internal media 
 world and they admire us for how much pressure we have managed to 
 create. Nice to hear.
 
 8) I have managed to persuade all big Austrian national animal welfare 
 and animal rights groups to pay together an advert, which is an appeal 
 to the prime minister to ban battery farming, signed by 50 prominent 
 Austrians from arts and science. On next Tuesday, the day of the 
 parliamentary debate, this advert will be published half page in the 
 conservative daily newspaper. If it is perceived well, I might get the 
 groups to finance publishing the same advert in a number of other 
 newspapers, especially since many newspapers drop costs by more than 50% 
 and up to 100%.

</content>

</doc>
