<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Sep  7 07:04:10 2003</date>
  <content>
Though much of big science has centered on breakthroughs in
biotechnology, nanotechnology and more esoteric questions like the
age of our universe, a quieter story has been unfolding behind the
scenes in laboratories around the world ? one whose effect on human
perception and our understanding of life is likely to be profound.

What these researchers are finding is that many of our fellow
creatures are more like us than we had ever imagined. They feel pain,
suffer and experience stress, affection, excitement and even love ?
and these findings are changing how we view animals. 

 Strangely enough, some of the research sponsors are fast food
purveyors, such as McDonald's, Burger King and KFC. Pressured by
animal rights activists and by growing public support for the humane
treatment of animals, these companies have financed research into,
among other things, the emotional, mental and behavioral states of
our fellow creatures.

Studies on pigs' social behavior funded by McDonald's at Purdue
University, for example, have found that they crave affection and are
easily depressed if isolated or denied playtime with each other. The
lack of mental and physical stimuli can result in deterioration of
health. 
... 
So what does all of this portend for the way we treat our fellow
creatures? And for the thousands of animals subjected each year to
painful laboratory experiments? Or the millions of domestic animals
raised under the most inhumane conditions and destined for slaughter
and human consumption? Should we discourage the sale and purchase of
fur coats? What about fox hunting in the English countryside, bull
fighting in Spain? Should wild lions be caged in zoos?

Such questions are being raised. Harvard and 25 other U.S. law
schools have introduced law courses on animal rights, and an
increasing number of animal rights lawsuits are being filed. Germany
recently became the first nation to guarantee animal rights in its
constitution. </content>

</doc>
