<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec  1 03:15:30 2003</date>
  <content>

The state of animal farming in this country is abysmal. The small farm and 
slaughterhouse have been almost entirely replaced by the vertically integrated 
meat and animal products conglomerate; environmental disaster and unintentional 
cruelty to animals in the name of efficiency have become de facto standards 
in much of the industry. Chelsea Purvis' recent guest column ("Sustainable 
Farms Offer More Humane Option," November 18, 2003) does an excellent job 
describing the horrible conditions of mainstream animal farming. What lies outside the 
scope of Purvis' column, however, is that elements of the environmental far 
left have long campaigned for lifestyle-based non-solutions that fail to 
address the problem in a comprehensive manner.

Groups such as People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) and others 
have taken advantage of the situation to vociferously promote veganism (and, 
as a less acceptable alternative, vegetarianism) amongst socially conscious 
consumers. PETA and its allies have an ulterior motive grounded in extreme 
ideology: the belief that any form of animal domestication is automatically immoral; 
the leaders of PETA believe that the only "ethical" contact between humans 
and animals is no contact at all. PETA's philosophy would leave us without not 
only household pets, but also antibiotics, the smallpox vaccine and most of the 
rest of modern medicine.

The literature of the vegan movement loves to quote Socrates: "the unexamined 
life is not worth living." Socrates is indeed correct, but vegan propaganda 
simply replaces one brand of ignorance with another. I am a pragmatist, and I 
believe that the general public will never give up meat, milk, eggs and other 
animal products. Indeed, trends of the past few years have shown that the 
American public's appetite for beef has only grown along with its waistline; though 
veganism and vegetarianism continue to rise, so does meat production.</content>

</doc>
