<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Feb  9 08:23:35 2004</date>
  <content>
I'm an upbeat person. At PETA, I'm often referred to as "Bruce Poppins,"
because I tend to ignore the bad and accentuate the good, sometimes a
bit quixotically, I will admit. Basically, I figure that worry and
pessimism are a prescription for burnout, not empowerment. If we lose
our sense of humor and optimism, we're bound to be less effective as
activists. Labor organizer Joe Hill told us that mourning was not an
effective method of change ("Don't mourn. Organize!"), and Emma Goldman
declared, "If I can't dance, I want no part of your revolution." But the
strongest impact on my outlook is the closing song of the best movie
ever made, Monty Python's The Life of Brian: "Always look on the bright
side of life." If you haven't seen this flick, put this article aside
and proceed to the nearest video store.

When I look at the world around me, I am filled with vicarious pain at
the level of suffering in the world, but also with hope at the number of
selfless people working to make it a better place. As I pondered a list
of ten, I came up with about 25 things that give me an amazing amount of
hope, and struggled to limit them. So I decided to confine myself to the
things that have blossomed for me in the past two years.

Vegan Video Brigades
Praise be to Eddie Lama. From Lawrence, Kansas, to Asheville, North
Carolina, to Seattle to San Francisco to Minneapolis to Washington to
more and more cities, activists are showing people how meat is
made-taking TV/VCRs, generators and literature, setting up at metro
stops, outside concerts, at fairs, and so on. To my great delight,
PETA's Meet Your Meat seems to be the video of choice. Of course, PETA
is happy to supply a free two-hour loop to anyone who would like a copy
to show. We also have details of how to do this event on the "Great ways
to promote vegetarianism" link at GoVeg.com. Watch the video, narrated
by actor Alec Baldwin (a sign of hope himself!) at www.MeetYourMeat.com.

Farmed Animals are People Too
Animal behaviorists are finally studying society's most neglected
animals-rats, mice, and farmed animals (chickens, pigs, cows, and fish),
and publishing their findings. So we now know that rats and mice dream,
play, and have a sense of fun, and that chickens, pigs, fish, and cows
are every bit as interesting and intelligent as any dog or cat. In 2003,
The New York Times and The New Yorker both did stories discussing the
fact that chickens score better on cognitive function tests than dogs or
cats, and pigs do even better, showing mental acumen beyond that of a
three year-old human child. We learned that fish have long-term memory
and can use tools, abilities once thought by anthropologists to
distinguish humans from other primates. Once people start to see
chickens, fish, rats, mice, and other animals as interesting and
deserving of respect, some basic protections are sure to follow, and
fewer and fewer people will eat them or torment them in labs.

The Christian Vegetarian Association and Father John Dear, S.J.
There've been Jewish vegetarian groups for years; finally, the religion
that comprises about 90 percent of Americans has a vegetarian group of
its own. The Christian Vegetarian Association's "What would Jesus eat?"
pamphlet (from ChristianVeg.com) is excellent, and can be placed in the
literature area of your nearest Christian church (you don't have to
belong or even be Christian to do this). Similarly, the first piece of
literature by a member of the Catholic clergy to invoke animal cruelty
as a reason to adopt a vegetarian diet, Christianity and Vegetarianism
by Fr. John Dear, S.J., also came out about a year ago (available from
PETA for free to anyone who wants to place them in Catholic churches).

</content>

</doc>
