<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Jan 17 18:16:31 2004</date>
  <content>
When the news broke on December 23 that a cow infected with bovine 
spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), a.k.a. mad cow disease, had been discovered 
in Washington state, meat producers and merchants moved into crisis-control 
mode. The disease, which literally eats holes in its victims’ brains, has 
infected some 180,000 cattle in Britain and is blamed for the deaths of 
nearly 150 people there. The American meat industry needed to convince the 
public that its beef was still safe to eat — especially since dozens of 
countries had immediately banned imports of the stuff.

Washington lobbyists with the cattle industry’s main political advocacy 
group, the National Cattlemen’s Beef Association (NCBA), fanned out to 
contact members of Congress and Agriculture Department officials — many of 
them at home for the holidays — to strategize a response. Association 
spokespeople were deployed in all 50 states to make the case to the media 
that the public was in no danger. A special Web site focusing on BSE — 
created years ago for just such a crisis — went up on the NCBA’s official 
site, beef.org, according to spokeswoman Michele Peterson. Perturbed by all 
the images on TV of obviously sick cows taken during BSE outbreaks in 
Britain, the association hired its own crews to film sleek American cattle 
grazing contentedly in lush pastures, then sent the footage to the national 
networks, cable news shows and local stations.

“This is all really a nonissue,” insists Dan Murphy, a spokesman for the 
American Meat Institute, the meatpacking industry’s trade group, which has 
also been busy downplaying public fears. “There is no threat to public 
health. Beef is safe. The flames have been fanned by misguided media 
coverage, and by activists with agendas — the kind of people who want to 
turn us all into vegetarians or denounce corporate globalization and the WTO 
or whatever.”

Beef is a $70 billion business in this country, and the people who run it 
are no slouches. Their skill at working both public opinion and politicians 
would make the NRA proud. But the industry’s many critics say it often uses 
its clout to stifle detractors and thwart regulations aimed at making its 
products safer — all in the interest of keeping the fat in its profits.

Beef producers can be notoriously intolerant of “activists with agendas” — 
as Howard Lyman learned. Lyman, a 65-year-old former rancher turned vegan 
activist, appeared on The Oprah Winfrey Show in 1996 and predicted that mad 
cow disease would eventually break out in the U.S., thanks to the cattle 
industry’s practice of feeding potentially infected rendered cow parts back 
to other cows. An appalled Oprah promised she would never eat another 
hamburger. That prompted a group of Texas cattlemen to sue her and Lyman 
under a state law making it illegal to criticize food products without a 
basis in “reliable scientific inquiry.” Texas is one of 13 states that has 
passed similar “food libel” laws since the early 1990s — constitutionally 
questionable statutes that meat interests helped push.

“These laws are meant to stifle dissent,” says Lyman, who won his case after 
years of litigation. “These people have a lot of money invested in 
controlling the media.”

The meat industry isn’t focused only on influencing public perception; it 
also uses its substantial political power, working the halls of Congress and 
the White House to beat back unwelcome rules and regulations.</content>

</doc>
