<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Feb 12 14:02:48 2004</date>
  <content>
Ten months after his death, diet guru Robert Atkins is at the centre of
more controversy. A medical report showing he was obese when he died has
been seized on by Atkins opponents with their own views to promote. At
stake is control of the $40bn-a-year diet industry and the profits of
America's food giants

FOR A MAN WHO changed millions of lives, Robert Atkins?s own ended in an
awful mess. Last April he slipped on an icy pavement, banged his head,
suffered (possibly) a heart attack, then went into a coma from which he
never emerged. He died within a week.
...
To enemies of the Atkins diet it looked like a heinous cover-up at the
expense of the ill-fed and the credulous, and yesterday these enemies had
their chance to gloat. It turns out that Atkins died obese, with a history
of heart disease and a score of 35 on a standard index that put him 10
points over merely overweight. ?To us,? says a spokeswoman for a group of
American doctors called Physicians? Committee for Responsible Medicine
(PCRM), ?the significance is we?ve been saying for years and years that
the Atkins diet is a diet that?s likely to cause heart disease.?

But what is the PCRM? Where did it get its information about Dr Atkins?s
corpse? And is this argument really about a global public health
emergency, or something altogether simpler? Determined dieters who?ve
spent small fortunes trying weight-loss programmes from both ends of the
medical opinion spectrum may have an idea of the answer.

The PCRM is a fiercely anti-meat, pro-vegetarian brains trust that has
opposed the Atkins diet for years, apparently with the best of intentions.
It obtained its information on Dr Atkins?s body from Dr Richard Fleming, a
Nebraska-based cardiologist, outspoken critic of the Atkins diet and
author of two high-profile books on how to minimise your risk of heart
disease without a high-protein diet. 
...
This feud is about business. This is not to say it is not also about
health, but it does emphasise with the concision of a fine haiku that in
America, and increasingly here too, health is business.</content>

</doc>
