<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu May 29 07:48:48 2003</date>
  <content>
 
  Elder Abuse and Animal Cruelty 
     
 On January 20, 2001, an anonymous caller to the Washington, D.C. Humane Society reported that her neighbor's daughter had thrown a dead dog into the trash dumpster. Animal control officers arrived at the scene to discover that the dead dog was only the tip of the iceberg. They also found an emaciated and disoriented 90-year-old woman. The floor of the house was covered with trash and dog feces, parts of the ceiling had caved in, and mildew covered the walls. 
Reports indicated that the daughter often left her elderly mother alone for several weeks at a time. The animal control officers rescued the remaining dogs and contacted adult protective services, which arranged to have the woman transported to a hospital. The two agencies coordinated their actions to meet the needs of victims of two different types of abuse?yet all of whom required emergency care. If it hadn't been for the report of a dead dog, the suffering of both human and animal victims would have continued unnoticed. 

Animal cruelty or neglect can often be a warning sign of other forms of abuse, including elder abuse. That's why The HSUS has joined forces with the Department of Health and Human Services' Administration on Aging to share information on the animal cruelty/elder abuse connection. We're coordinating our efforts around Older Americans Month, the period set aside each May to honor the country's senior citizens. 

The informational campaign is clearly needed. According to the National Elder Abuse Incidence Study*, "approximately 450,000 elderly persons in domestic settings were abused and/or neglected during 1996." When the cases of elderly self-neglect were added, the numbers rose to more than 550,000. 

What's more, according to the study, ?data show that family members were the perpetrators in nine out of ten (89.7 percent) substantiated incidents of domestic elder abuse and neglect. Adult children of elder abuse victims were the most likely perpetrators of substantiated maltreatment (47.3 percent). Spouses represented the second largest group of perpetrators (19.3 percent)." 

When a family member abuses an elderly relative's pet, the motivations may be complex. The perpetrator may neglect or abuse an elder's pet as a form of control or retaliation, out of frustration over their caretaking responsibilities, or as a way to extract financial assets. 

</content>

</doc>
