<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jul  7 12:01:21 2004</date>
  <content>
On Friday, June 25, 2004, I set about to  put together a radio show that I 
have done live at the Reno Hilton for the past  11 months on KPTT 630 Radio, a 
local ESPN affiliate.  The Reno Rodeo was to have its  next-to-the-last 
performance in town on this date to record crowds.  Thinking that the subject was 
very  topical and thought-provoking, I did some research about how animals are 
treated  in rodeos across the country.  I  stumbled across a website at 
_http://www.sharkonline.org/_ (http://www.sharkonline.org/) . 
I learned of  documented abuse and mistreatment of animals in rodeos, and 
wanted to find out  more, as well as hear from both sides.  I telephoned the 
owner of the website, Steve Hindi, and invited him on  the show.  I then learned 
that the  animal welfare coordinator for the Professional Rodeo Cowboys 
Association, Cindy  Schonholtz, happen to be in town and I was able to track her down 
and invite her  onto the show.  She immediately  agreed to appear in person 
on the show, and got directions on how to get  there.  I then informed her that 
I  would also have Steve Hindi from SHARK (Showing Animals Respect &amp; 
Kindness)  on the show with her. 
At this point she  started backpedaling and told me that she would have to 
clear it with her  superiors at the PRCA.  Within an  hour, she called back and 
canceled her appearance.  I then got a call from my boss, General  Manager 
Dane Wilt of Lotus Radio in  Reno, who was very upset.  He demanded to know whose 
idea it was to  put an animal rights activist on the air.  I should point out 
here that Lotus Radio has 5 radio stations in Reno,  including 94.5 The 
Mountain, a country FM station, which turns out to be the  official radio station 
of the Reno Rodeo for the past 4 years running.  Since Miss Schonholtz had just 
canceled  and I wanted to have both sides on the air, coupled with the fact 
that Dane was  very upset, I told him that I wouldn't put Mr. Hindi on the air 
and he hung  up. 
First thing Monday  morning, Dane called me into his office.  He also 
requested the presence of office manager Tammy Jo Baxter, as he  often does when very 
serious conversations are about to take place.  He started out this way "Lee, 
there is  absolutely no possible way that you can justify what you did on 
Friday.  The rodeo is our partner.  You have shown no regard for our  
relationship with them, etc, etc.  You will never be on the air on KPTT again.  Ever." 
I then tried to  explain my reasons for doing the show to no avail.  I even 
apologized, saying I used poor  judgment by not consulting with him first.  He 
was determined to remove me from the air, saying that my apology was  
worthless because it didn't come fast enough.  He went on to say that he couldn't 
trust  me to be on the air ever again.  Since I am also the sales manager of KPTT, 
I asked how he could trust me  to call on clients if he couldn't trust me to 
be on the air.  He said that that was different, and I  disagreed.  I told him 
then that if  he really didn't trust me, I didn't need to be there, and so I 
resigned.  I reminded him that all of this fuss was  over a show that NEVER 
EVEN AIRED.  It didn't matter.  He wasn't changing his mind, so I  assured him 
that I was serious about resigning. 
Since this occurred,  I have informed a few of my clients about what 
happened, and they are furious,  some already demanding answers and threatening to 
cancel many thousands of  dollars worth of advertising.  The  Reno Hilton is also 
a rodeo partner, but they have supported me.  Their President &amp; CEO Tim 
Maland has  been very understanding.  We are  negotiating putting my show on 
another station. 

END OF  STATEMENT 

</content>

</doc>
