<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Nov 30 08:34:08 2003</date>
  <content>
PLAGUE OF ESCAPEES Divers in July found about 500 foreign Atlantics among 
native coho in a tributary of the Chehalis River, scarcely 50 miles from the West 
Coast's premier river, the Columbia. The fish got loose from a fish hatchery 
operated by Cypress Island, a Norwegian-owned company operating salmon farms 
in Puget Sound. 
More than three months passed before authorities tried to corral the aliens. 
About 400 remain on the lam. 
Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife records show 10 years of escapes 
from the hatchery. Its operation is "pretty slipshod," said Greg Cloud, permit 
manager for the Washington Department of Ecology. 
Hatchery manager Dan Rotter said repeated vandalism of fish screens may have 
allowed the escapes and acknowledged he has not "kept close enough watch on 
that." The company has spent $50,000 rebuilding its screens and installing 
security fences, he said. 
More than 1 million Atlantics have escaped farm pens in Northwest waters, 
some spawning in rivers on Vancouver Island. They have turned up in Washington's 
Dungeness and Nisqually rivers and in the Bering Sea -- 1,000 miles from the 
nearest farm. Fishermen have caught them in Alaska's Copper River, revered for 
native runs with deep rosy flesh. 
Ron Ginetz, chief of aquaculture for the Canadian Department of Fisheries and 
Oceans, wrote in an internal 1991 memo that "it is only a matter of time 
before we discover that Atlantics are gaining a foothold in B.C. or in Washington 
state." 
Ginetz now works for the British Columbia Salmon Farmers Association and says 
he no longer thinks Atlantics will take hold in the Pacific. It's a foreign 
environment for them, he says. Millions of fry were introduced in Canada and 
Washington decades ago to establish them as game fish, without success. 
But now Pacific salmon are much weaker, and grown Atlantics get loose year 
after year. Should they colonize the Pacific coast, they could compete with 
natives and undermine costly recovery programs. 
DEPLETING THE OCEAN 
FOR FEED Like wolves or lions, salmon feed on flesh. On farms, they swallow 
it in pellets made from ground, cooked and compressed fish such as menhaden and 
jack mackerel. But salmon are so voracious it takes three or more pounds of 
raw feed fish to raise each pound of fillets sold in the supermarket. That 
leaves oceans with a net loss of life. 
"We're taking food away not only from salmon in the wild, but also from other 
predaceous fish, marine mammals and seabirds," says Jane Lubchenco, an Oregon 
State University marine biologist who advises world leaders on ocean health. 
"What we're doing is going into a food web, tearing out the middle and acting 
surprised when the top comes crashing down." 
Not only Norway is swarming with escaped Atlantic salmon. They are also 
swimming free in Oregon's back yard. </content>

</doc>
