<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Jan 17 11:42:06 2004</date>
  <content>
I have, in the past, driven behind a fish farm lorry for half an hour along 
the long slow roads of the Outer Hebrides. European money has improved 
stretches of them. You suddenly find yourself on a double-width, unnaturally 
expensive-looking surface, with unnecessarily large gravelled verges, and you give 
thanks to Brussels for its structural funds and its love affair with the poor 
outer margins of the Continent, before returning to the narrow, indigenous strip 
of tarmac, somehow paid for in the distant past by the Western Isles council.
That is one of the moments when the reality of modern fish-farming hits home. 
The old road is not the lovely, moneyed euro carpet. It is bumpy and, at each 
bump, the large plastic containers on the lorry in front of you are given a 
little jerk. They contain dead, mature salmon, being driven from the farm to 
the processing plant. But the fish are swimming in their own blood and, at each 
bump, the blood slops out of the containers, on to the back of the lorry, and 
sprays the car behind.
You have to keep your wipers going to see through the blood. The whole front 
of your car is sticky with it afterwards. It is like a horror film, weirdly 
overstated in its crudity. These blood-bumps are like the evidence of a body in 
the boot, a horrible slopping-out of a hidden fact.
Why is this so disgusting? Partly, I think, it is a question of deceit. Go 
into your average supermarket and look at the images with which salmon is sold: 
fresh, Scottish, beautiful and, above all, clean. You won't find any pictures 
of windscreens coated in blood, nor, as I have seen, of salmon still alive and 
thrashing in containers filled to the brim with their own and other fish's 
blood. Perhaps only in eggs and chickens is there a greater gulf between the 
realities of production and the deceptions of the chill cabinet.</content>

</doc>
