<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Feb 24 16:07:41 2004</date>
  <date>Monday, February 23, 2004 12:16 PM</date>
  <content>
 People have set up an organization to help reduce the suffering of
 all these animals in Romania.  They are smartly dividing their
 efforts into two parts - one for rescue and one for humane education.
  Each to utilize 50% of all manpower and financial resources so as
 not to die off from  the 'tail chasing' deaths so many rescuers
 face due to exhaustion.
 They could still use ideas and prayers from everyone.
 
 
 
 Dear 21st Century Animal Resource,
 
 I am so impressed with you and 21st Cares!  I want to introduce the
 Romania Animal Rescue, Inc. to you.  We were founded last year as a
 result of a Romanian hiking tour.  My friends and I were horrified at
 the suffering and neglect of thousands of stray street dogs in every
 city and town in Romania!  We formed RAR, now a US 501 c 3
 corporation, to help legitimate organizations and citizens in Romania
 to set up spay/neuter facilities and life care for infirmed animals
 of Romania.  We have been successful in finding a partner to work
 with in Galati, and she is wonderful.  We have been able to set up
 our first shelter and clinic there, thanks to my representative Dana
 Costin from ROLDA.  
 
 I need some advise from you as to how you would go about getting the
 word out to the civilized world about what is going on in Romania. 
 The govt. has no compassion for these animals, and has massive
 slaughter campaigns whereby they send out killing squads to poison,
 club, or kick the dogs to death.  This is not the solution to the
 problem, obviously, or these dogs would not keep coming back and
 causing this over-population crisis.  Often when the word gets out
 about the horrible condition of the strays, the Romanian govt. is
 embarrassed and has a slaughter campaign to clean up the dogs and
 pretend that they have solved the problem "humanely" (out of sight,
 out of mind, you know?).  In most cities, the govt. taxes the
 citizens and says it is spaying/neutering dogs with the $, but we
 have checked these dogs and found that they are in tact.  The
 authorities just keep the $, and the people are frustrated with
 having to pay the taxes and angry with the dogs, and so the neglect
 and abuse is rampant.  I have been told that Romania has the highest
 stray dog population of any country in the world, and I believe this
 to be the case.  
 
 Our shelter has a spay/neuter release program, and we have over
 10,000 dogs in our city alone to care for.  I am being asked for help
 throughout Romania, but have decided I can get the most done by
 focussing on one successful program at a time.  With our program, we
 only keep dogs incapable of street life at our shelter for life care,
 (crippled, blind, etc.).  It is a sanctuary for dogs - a clean,
 spacious and loving environment.  We have parasite medications that
 we use to keep them happy and healthy, and feed the best food we can
 find - which is another problem - and we want to start making our own
 healthy dry dog food at a reasonable price for us and the people of
 Romania.  Right now dog food costs as much as it is in the US-
 sometimes more - and is often out of date and spoiled.  Many problems
 there...
 Any help you can advise?
 Sincerely, and sorry to ramble on, but I am interested in those of
 you with knowledge and experience helping us.
</content>
</doc>
