<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Dec  5 16:32:44 2003</date>
  <content>
Read all about the essential vitamins and minerals you need now?and where to 
get them
Let's get something straight right away: This isn't one of those articles 
promising that there's a Fountain of Youth in this vitamin or that mineral. We've 
been around long enough to know there's no such thing. But what you do need 
to know is that many of the problems commonly associated with aging can be 
prevented, if not completely eliminated, if you adjust your nutritional intake to 
the needs of your changing body.
Speaking of changing bodies, did you know that with each passing birthday the 
human stomach produces less hydrochloric acid needed to digest food and 
properly absorb adequate amounts of certain key nutrients? By age 50, this 
dwindling supply of acid causes a vitamin B-12 inadequacy in at least one in four 
Americans; by age 75, it affects about 40 percent. What are the telltale symptoms 
of getting too little vitamin B-12? Memory lapses. Joint pain. Fatigue. 
Tingling hands and feet. Sounds a lot like aging, doesn't it? "People often say, 
'You're just getting old.' But many of the classic signs of aging overlap with 
the symptoms of nutritional inadequacy," says Jeffrey Blumberg, Ph.D., of the 
Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging at Tufts University in 
Boston. "Just because you feel that you're aging doesn't mean it's because 
you're aging."
But don't go blaming your stomach for every midlife complaint. Fact is, you 
may be coming up short in the vitamins department?just like millions of others 
who have passed the half-century mark?even if you're eating a perfect food 
pyramid.
So, how do you meet those needs? In many cases, a daily "senior formula" 
multivitamin supplement is all you need to fill the void. In other cases, even 
that multi may not be enough. Here's what you need to know:
Vitamin B-12
We talked about the necessity of getting enough B-12. Here's a case where 
that senior formula multivitamin has you covered. You can also get additional 
B-12 in your diet by eating meat. But because this vitamin is "bound" to protein 
(making it hard for your body to absorb), even if you eat plenty of beef, 
chicken, and fish, it's hard to get enough B-12 by diet alone</content>

</doc>
