<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Jan  8 23:32:05 2004</date>
  <content>
Since the Dec. 23 announcement that bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE)
was traced to a cow in Washington state that has entered the U.S. meat
supply, news sources have focused almost invariably on one question: How
will this affect meat sales?

An alarm has been sounded, but for whom and for what? The answer stinks
like rotten meat, but few seem to be catching a whiff.
...
I've not heard one interviewee take the opening "Is meat safe to eat?" by
answering, "Actually, even before this incident, meat was unsafe to eat,
for many reasons other than BSE. Not only because of the food-borne
illnesses that sicken 38.6 million Americans annually (and kill 2,700),
but even more so because of the 1.5 million deaths from heart disease,
cancer and stroke every year."

The role of animal fats and meat in these conditions has been
overwhelmingly established. As Neal Barnard, M.D., president of the
Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine, has declared, "The beef
industry has contributed to more American deaths than all the wars of this
century, all natural disasters and all automobile accidents combined."
...
Unfortunately, the media are acting almost solely as a forum for debate
about the impact of BSE on profits instead of the effects of meat
production on human, animal and environmental health. This is not helping
one iota to raise consciousness from what may well be the United States'
most ghastly complacency.

If this crisis inspires no one to probe beyond the financial health of a
rapacious industry, we are afflicted with a sickness more malevolent than
Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.

Listening to unabashed market analysis that dwarfs matters of human health
and animal suffering, as corporate interests and government officials
scramble to soothe a remarkably unruffled consumer, I think not of "mad
cows." (What a clever naming convention, as if the cows are to blame!)

I see a mad world, and I feel a lonely sense of grief for its lack of
humanity and common sense.</content>

</doc>
