<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr  5 22:46:14 2004</date>
  <content>
The General Assembly finds that the numbers of unwanted cats and dogs in 
North Carolina has reached crisis level. Unwanted animals frequently become strays 
and suffer from a lack of food, shelter and veterinary care. In addition to 
these humane concerns, stray animals are a public nuisance and present a 
serious public health problem as many are not vaccinated against rabies. In 2001, 
over 227,778 cats and dogs were turned into shelters or picked up by local 
animal control authorities and euthanized. Unwanted animals also create a 
substantial financial burden for the counties and municipalities that must collect, 
house, and ultimately euthanize the animals. Limited financial resources have 
made it difficult for local governments to provide adequate animal shelter 
facilities.
The General Assembly finds that existing State and local animal welfare 
programs have not been effective in either stabilizing or reducing the numbers of 
unwanted companion animals in the State. Factors affecting the increase in 
unwanted animals include the State's population growth and the inadequate funding 
of State and local animal welfare programs. The General Assembly finds, 
however, that the primary cause of the increase in unwanted animals is uncontrolled 
breeding. Lack of education regarding the reasons to spay or neuter an animal 
and the lack of financial resources on the part of many of the citizens of the 
State contributes to the problem of uncontrolled breeding. The General 
Assembly finds that many county and city animal welfare programs and nonprofit 
humane societies have implemented programs that have greatly increased the numbers 
of homeless pets adopted, Adoption alone, however, is not adequate to 
significantly decrease the number of animals being destroyed. The General Assembly 
finds that the most viable solution to the pet overpopulation problem in this 
State is increase the availability of low cost spay and neuter services. It is 
the intention of the General Assembly to establish a companion animal program 
that will provide financial assistance to local governments for low-cost spay 
and neuter services, adequate sheltering facilities, and other services for 
companion animals.</content>

</doc>
