<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 12 11:32:46 2004</date>
  <content>
There once was a pet pig who sang to the moon and, best of all, escaped the
fate of her porcine peers. Piglet's story is Jeffrey Moussaieff Masson's
powerful introduction to his exploration of the emotional lives of billions
of pigs, cows, chickens and other animals destined for slaughter and
rendering into meat.

In previous books, the bestselling author (When Elephants Weep, Dogs Never
Lie About Love) has examined the complex natures of animals we hunt,
exploit, abuse and, in the case of dogs and cats, share our lives with. In
his new book, he turns his attention to the most numerous category of 
animal
in the world. Over 40 billion chickens are killed worldwide each year, for
instance. "The suffering of almost all farm animals is unique, particular,
mostly beyond language to describe or explain," Masson writes. "If we give
it no thought, and yet eat them for our meals, are we not morally blind,
ethically dumb, and humanly remiss?"

The Pig Who Sang to the Moon is Masson's offering of intellectual food for
that thought, and his skill at serving it up produces an informative and
compelling narrative. He reveals the depth of the interior lives of farmed
animals, and highlights just how much they suffer from the brutality of
intensive farming and from being deprived of every expression of their 
basic
instincts and sensibilities. "Not what you are eating, but whom you are
eating is the question on my lips," Masson writes.

In discussing each kind of farmed animal, Masson harks back to the feral
ancestors it resembles. He also notes how similar they are to human beings
"in their ability to feel anxious, bored, sad, lonely or deliriously 
happy."
Pigs, whose transplanted heart valves can keep humans alive, are 
intelligent
creatures who wag their tails when happy and may die of terror on their way
to the slaughter they seem to sense is imminent. Their maternal instincts
are so strong that even sows confined to barren concrete stalls paw the
ground as if shaping straw into nests for their piglets.

But farmed pigs, according to Masson, are "fattened to immobility, tails
cut, teeth removed . . . forced to urinate and defecate in their sleeping
space, something no pig would ever do in nature." Some are so heavy that
their feet can barely support them. "The pig's life has been distorted,
perverted, deformed, contorted beyond recognition," he concludes.

So, he believes, has the chicken's life. Chickens are "treated as fast food
on legs, bred to be fried and eaten within seven weeks of emerging from the
egg." They are crammed into wire cages that damage their feet and claws.
They are deprived of all natural light, space to flap their wings and earth
to take the dust baths that clean their feathers.
There is no comfortable way to tell the story of farmed animals, and
Masson's pain permeates every chapter. At the same time, his extensive
research, eloquence and reasoned approach to solutions combine to make this
book toweringly important, and to legitimize Masson's personal mission as
the animals' ambassador to the carnivorous world.

</content>

</doc>
