<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar  4 11:42:58 2004</date>
  <content>
Police arrested a Wheatfield area woman after officials found more than a 
dozen dead or severely malnourished horses on her Jasper County farm. 
?They (county officers) said I wasn?t feeding the horses, but they wouldn?t 
let me feed them before I was taken to jail,? Deborah Turoci said from the 
back door of her home along Indiana 49 on Wednesday afternoon. 
Turoci, 51, was arrested on charges of cruelty to animals, a misdemeanor, and 
failure to dispose of dead animals, a felony. 
Seven of the horses were dead, and county highway workers had to use heavy 
machinery to remove the carcasses because some were frozen to the ground, 
authorities said. 
If convicted, Turoci could face from six months to three years in prison and 
a $10,000 fine. She was released from jail on $5,000 bond. 
Turoci lived in the house alone except for about 20 cats, police said. She 
also kept five dogs. Jasper County police Chief Deputy Terry Risner said the 
dogs were not fed properly and one had apparently eaten part of one of the horse 
carcasses. 
As she talked with a reporter Wednesday, cats peered out from behind storm 
door glass. A ?beware of the dog? sign hung on the door and behind the house 
were a large pickup and a horse trailer. There were no horses on the property 
where she said she has lived for 14 years. 
Police searched her farm north of County Road 1400N on Friday after receiving 
complaints from neighbors, Risner said. Officials had ordered Turoci to bury 
or remove six dead horses a week earlier and to properly care for the others. 
But Risner said Turoci made no effort to dispose of the dead animals, and 
allowed a 
7-month-old colt to die without euthanasia. 
Turoci said when some horses died while the ground was frozen she couldn?t 
bury them. She said her tractor also broke down. She said two died the same time 
Feb. 14 or 15, which is usual. 
The surviving horses were taken to an undisclosed animal rescue shelter, 
police said. Veterinarians believe the animals can be saved. </content>

</doc>
