<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Mar 29 14:00:39 2004</date>
  <content>

---------------------------------

NEW MAD COW REGULATIONS STILL MAKE US MAD
In response to the discovery of the first case of Mad Cow Disease in the
U.S. last December, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) has announced
it will increase testing of the nation's cattle up to 480,000 cows per
year. Consumer groups, including the Organic Consumers Association and
the Consumers Union, say these new projections for testing are
completely inadequate, given that the U.S. Cattle industry slaughters 35
million animals annually. The government and large beef corporations
fear more tests since they know Mad Cow disease has now spread to more
and more cattle in North America. However, many ranchers in Kansas,
California, and other states, desperate to regain their export markets,
say they're willing to test all cows, as Japan and other nations have
demanded. http://www.organicconsumers.org/madcow/nytimes032204.cfm

---------------------------------

EARTH FRIENDLY LABELING LIES
Consumers are quickly learning that government oversight of product
labeling is all too loosely regulated. To add to the already existing
confusion, the Hudson Institute's Center for Global Food Issues (CGFI),
an agribusiness and biotech front group, has announced it will now be
labeling qualifying products as "Earth Friendly". This designation will
be placed on genetically engineered foods and factory farmed meat and
dairy products.. The corporate-funded CGFI claim they have a right to
label products as such, given their "scientific" opinion that certain
aspects of GE crops and densely packed feedlots are better for the
environment than organic agriculture.
http://www.organicconsumers.org/organic/labels031904.cfm

---------------------------------

SCARY FISH FACTS
The U.S. Food and Drug Administration has released new safety guidelines
for fish consumption, due to ever-increasing levels of mercury
contamination. The fish containing the highest levels of mercury are:
shark, swordfish, king mackerel and tilefish. The guidelines suggest
eating up to two meals a week (totaling 12 ounces) of fish that are low
in mercury such as shrimp, canned light tuna, salmon, pollock and
catfish.
http://www.organicconsumers.org/foodsafety/fish032204.cfm

---------------------------------

GETTING JUNK FOOD OUT OF SCHOOLS
With the Bush Administration's reduced funding for education, many
school districts have been forced to seek other sources of income,
including widespread installation of junk-food vending machines. School
districts can make up to $100,000 per year under these contracts, but as
a result of increased access to unhealthy foods, the childhood obesity
and diabetes epidemics are on the increase. In response, two dozen
states are now considering banning junk food vending machines in
schools. The National Soft Drink Association is contesting this ban,
claiming that high levels of junk food consumption are okay, and placing
the blame on schools for not teaching the kids to exercise more.
http://www.organicconsumers.org/school/obesity031904.cfm

---------------------------------

REGULATING ROCKET FUEL LEVELS IN WATER
California has become the first state to consider regulating the levels
of allowable toxic perchlorates in drinking water. The pollutant has
been found in increasing levels in waterways around the U.S.,
particularly in areas near military bases and test sites (the toxin is
most commonly originates in rocket fuels). Perchlorates cause severe
neurological and thyroid dysfunction and are currently unregulated. In
related news, the U.S. Department of Defense is insisting to Congress it
should not be forced to comply with any environmental regulations, as a
matter of national security.
http://www.organicconsumers.org/foodsafety/water032204.cfm
</content>

</doc>
