<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Feb  7 01:10:08 2004</date>
  <content>
February 2004 issue - Back in 1997, investigative journalists Sheldon
Rampton and John Stauber wrote a book called Mad Cow U.S.A.: Could the
Nightmare Happen Here? Their answer was a resounding--and prescient--yes.
They based their certitude on the fact that the meat industry held
inordinate sway over the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), which was
supposed to be ensuring the safety of the meat supply.

One of the first USDA task forces on Mad Cow disease in 1990 consisted,
among others, of "key representatives from the agribusiness industry,"
Rampton and Stauber wrote. The National Milk Producers Federation, the
National Cattlemen's Beef Association, the American Sheep Industry
Association, and the National Renderers Association were all on board.
There was "not even token representation by a consumer organization," the
authors wrote.
...
Consumers Union noted that even today "rendered cattle remains can be fed
to swine and chickens, and that rendered swine and chicken remains can, in
turn, be fed back to cattle."

Stauber has a simple solution. "The feed rules that the United States must
adopt can be summarized this way: You might not be a vegetarian, but the
animals you eat must be," he wrote.

But the meat industry, still hidebound, stuck to its guns. "One of our
philosophies is minimal government involvement and letting the industry
address these things," Terry Stokes, the head of the cattlemen's
association, told The New York Times on January 1.

For its part, the American Meat Institute denied there were any health
concerns. "This case poses no risk to consumers," said J. Patrick Boyle,
president of that organization.
...
Just three weeks before the first confirmed Mad Cow case in the United
States and more than two years after the corporate scandals erupted, Bush
was still blaming the government for getting in the way of business.
Speaking at an event at a Home Depot in Baltimore, Bush said that
"excessive regulations" hurt all businesses, and he vowed to ease up.

But as the case of Mad Cow shows, regulation is not a problem; the lack of
regulation is. A policy beholden to corporate interests has resulted in a 

How many Mad Cows is it going to take to change that philosophy?</content>

</doc>
