<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Mar 30 09:54:34 2004</date>
  <content>

PCRM LAUNCHES NATIONAL CAMPAIGN CALLING FOR END TO AMERICAN CANCER SOCIETY 
"CATTLE BARONS' BALL" EVENTS

Washington - The Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine (PCRM) is 
calling on the American Cancer Society to put an end to its "Cattle Barons' 
Ball" events - beef-themed fundraisers promoting the very disease the 
cancer research and prevention giant is committed to curing. The 
fundraisers feature Western and cowboy themes, including "chuck wagons" 
loaded with beef and other meats. More than 30 are held each year, mostly 
in the South and Southwest, almost two-thirds of them in Texas and Florida.

PCRM Nutrition Director Amy Joy Lanou, Ph.D., has written to the local 
organizers of the ACS-sponsored Cattle Barons events across the country 
urging them to either cancel or find new themes. As part of its campaign - 
"Cancer: It's What's for Dinner at the Cattle Barons' Ball" - PCRM has 
launched a nationwide e-mail write-in effort calling on American Cancer 
Society CEO John Seffrin, Ph.D. and ACS chapters to call off or re-theme 
these events. An e-mail "postcard" can be sent to Dr. Seffrin by going to 
PCRM's Web site www.AmericanCancerSocietyPromotesDisease.org/letter.html  
Dates and full contact information on all upcoming Cattle Barons' Ball 
events are here as well.

"It is irresponsible of the American Cancer Society to sponsor events that 
promote beef consumption," said Lanou. "For more than 20 years, major 
scientific studies have linked beef and other meats with increased risk of 
cancer, particularly colorectal cancers."

More information on the link between cancer and meat consumption, PCRM's 
e-mail "postcard" urging the American Cancer Society to cancel or re-theme 
its Cattle Barons' Balls, and the dates, locations, and contact information 
on all upcoming Cattle Barons' Ball events can be found on PCRM's Web site: 
www.AmericanCancerSocietyPromotesDisease.org.



</content>

</doc>
