<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jan  7 17:25:31 2004</date>
  <content>Staggering off the challenging ski
slopes of Heavenly Mountain in Lake Tahoe, Nev., the depleted body goes in
search of replenishment. Looking around the watering holes on offer at
this casino-crazed resort, beef seems to be the sustenance of choice in
restaurants decked out to look like forests, MTV sets, or shopping mall
buffet stations. There is almost total silence, aside from the fire engine
wails of snow-exhausted children, as diners hunker down over ribs, massive
steaks, and burgers you need a jaw hinge to consume. Well, heck, beef is a
manly food, instant protein, a basic nourishment, pure and simple. And
despite the first U.S. case of mad cow disease, it's clear these legions
of diners must be confident of its purity.

After all, President Bush is still eating beef. On Jan. 2, though having
been on a successful hunt for quail at Falfurrias, Texas, he declared, "As
a matter of fact, I ate beef today, and will continue to eat beef." Scott
McClellan, a White House spokesman, announced that despite the mad cow
scare, the U.S. food supply was safe and public risk from the discovery of
the disease was low.

For this particular Brit, those positive proclamations rang too many
apprehensive bells. In May 1990, the British minister of Agriculture in
John Major's Conservative government appeared on television
enthusiastically encouraging his 4-year-old daughter Cordelia to bite
greedily into a hamburger. British beef, he claimed merrily, was
"completely safe."

Just five years later, in another May, the first recorded victim of
variant Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease died. Like most of the other 119 British
victims as of December 2002, Stephen Churchill was pitifully young -- 19.
In December 1995, the year of his death, Prime Minister John Major
declaimed, "There is no scientific evidence that BSE can be transmitted to
humans or that eating beef causes it in humans."

According to the Human BSE Foundation, around 1 million cattle are
estimated to have been infected with bovine spongiform encephalopathy
since the disease was first diagnosed in 1986.
...
Given the global nature of the food business, it seems unwise to assume
that one instance of BSE in Washington state is a lone occurrence. But
knowing what the British have gone through, with the wholesale slaughter
of cattle, the loss of farmers' livelihoods and, worse, the dreadful loss
of life through the human variant of the disease, let's hope that this is
the case.</content>

</doc>
