<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Jan 25 09:05:22 2004</date>
  <content>Bruce Chesebro is waiting for his monkeys to get chronic
wasting disease. Researchers at Rocky Mountain Laboratories here injected
a slurry of infected deer brain tissue into the brains of small,
black-eyed macaque and squirrel monkeys a few months ago.

Other monkeys drank a fruit drink mixed with the tainted brains. Today,
the monkeys sit in a room sealed off from most human contact while
scientists like Chesebro wonder if one of the world's most mysterious
vectors is eating little holes within their primate brains.

He and his colleagues are part of one of the nation's oldest and most
respected research programs into the bizarre family of brain-wasting
diseases called transmissible spongiform encephalopathies or TSEs. Here,
in a mountainous corner of Montana, researchers at the National Institutes
of Health's Rocky Mountain Labs have been quietly shedding light on TSEs
since 1961, helping to explain the suite of always deadly ailments which
includes chronic wasting in deer and elk, mad cow diseases in cattle and a
similar disease in humans called Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.

Their work has taken on a new urgency since mad cow disease was found in
the United States and everyone from consumers to Congress is demanding to
know more about these killers ? and how likely people are to catch them.

But what Chesebro has to say may be unsettling: He thinks mainstream
science may have been running down the wrong road for decades on TSE
research. While conventional wisdom holds that TSEs are caused by an
infectious protein, Chesebro thinks it is just as likely ? maybe even more
so ? that these diseases are really caused by some hearty ??ubiquitous
virus'' science has yet to identify. A virus present in everyone's body,
including yours.
...
?We've never seen a spontaneously infectious protein,'' Chesebro said.
??No one has ever generated it in the lab.''</content>

</doc>
