<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Mar 23 22:12:53 2004</date>
  <content>
Question: What are the different animal welfare groups operating in the 
Roseburg area and what services do they provide? -- M.F. of Roseburg 



Answers: The New Beginnings SPCA, the Saving Grace Pet Adoption Center and 
the Umpqua Valley Humane Society all work to improve the lives of dogs and cats 
and to ensure that pets are loved and wanted.


Members try to find homes for homeless cats, dogs and rabbits. However, the 
group is limited in the number of animals that can be taken in. New Beginnings 
also provides vouchers to low-income families to help pay for the cost of 
having a pet spayed or neutered. In addition, the group cares for feral cats. 
Donations of pet food is accepted both for the feral cat program and to provide to 
low-income residents.

The group hopes to be able to establish a no-kill shelter, where animals 
would not be euthanized simply because they were unwanted or had behavioral 
problems. Under the group's philosophy, an animal should be put to sleep only if it 
has a serious health condition that is contagious to other animals or if the 
animal is suffering and can't be cured. New Beginnings can be contacted at 
464-4313.

Saving Grace was established by a group of animal lovers in 2001 with the 
intent of taking over operation of the Douglas County animal shelter at 943 Del 
Rio Road in Winchester. Former Sheriff Jim Main became concerned that cats and 
dogs brought to the shelter were being euthanized almost as soon as they were 
brought in.

Under private operation, the shelter could keep animals longer and could try 
to place dogs and cats with other shelters located in Western Oregon. The 
county was not able to do that. The shelter takes in strays, along with animals 
given up by their owners. The group is looking to expand the shelter so that 
more dogs and cats can be kept there.</content>

</doc>
