<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Oct 11 08:55:28 2003</date>
  <content>

The parents of a 25-year-old animal rights activist wanted on suspicion of
bombing two Bay Area businesses have contacted a prominent San Francisco
attorney in hopes of persuading their son to surrender to charges that, if
proved, could put him in prison for up to 30 years.

The family of Daniel Andreas San Diego of Schellville in Sonoma County
issued an appeal Friday urging him to contact attorney Jim Collins and
surrender immediately to federal authorities.

Collins is a criminal defense attorney who has been involved in a number
of high-profile cases, most recently one involving three off-duty San
Francisco police officers accused of assaulting two men on Union Street
when they refused to hand over a take-home bag of fajitas. 
...
An animal rights group calling itself Revolutionary Cells claimed
responsibility for the blasts in anonymous e-mails and said the two
companies were targeted because of their ties to Huntingdon Life Sciences.
The New Jersey company conducts drug and chemical experiments on animals
for other firms, including Shaklee's parent company, Yamanouchi Consumer
Inc., and Chiron.
...
In a statement e-mailed to The Chronicle, Edmund San Diego and his wife,
Heike, asked their son to contact Collins to pave the way for his surrender.

"We continue to be bewildered by the situation as it unfolds and still
know little more than what we read or see in the press," the couple said. 
...
The suspect worked for two years at In Defense of Animals, a nonprofit in
Mill Valley, when he was about 19 years old, said group founder Elliot
Katz, a veterinarian.

"He was a very gentle human being who cared very deeply about animals,"
Katz said. "He seemed like he was totally nonviolent. He wouldn't hurt a
fly, let alone a human being." 
...
Danielle Matthews, a spokesperson at Stop Huntington Animal Cruelty in New
Jersey, cast aspersions on the FBI probe, while distancing her group from
San Diego. "We've never heard of him, and those East Bay bombings were
carried out anonymously. Other than their repeated failings in the past,
we don't have any indication that the FBI are more on target this time."

--</content>

</doc>
