<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Mar  1 11:10:44 2004</date>
  <content>
BIRDS of prey, including species such as the osprey and peregrine falcon, are on the increase in Scotland, according to figures obtained by The Scotsman. 
A report into the number of raptors, compiled by the Royal Society for the Protection of Birds (RSPB), found numbers rising - despite 19th-century practices to eliminate predators from country estates still being "firmly entrenched amongst a proportion of Scotland's 21st-century land managers". 
The latest Bird of Prey Persecution Report for Scotland has found many raptors which were previously driven to national and regional extinction have made significant recoveries in recent years. Species have experienced population increases either through natural re-colonisation or concerted re-introduction programmes by humans. 
A total of 27 birds of prey were confirmed as being killed as a direct result of persecution in 2002, according to the study. 
Fifteen of the 27 raptors were poisoned, including seven buzzards, two golden eagles, two white-tailed eagles, one red kite, one sparrow-hawk and two peregrine falcons. In addition, two crows, three rooks, two magpies and 20 unidentified birds were found poisoned. 
The remaining 12 were killed as a result of what the RSPB terms "direct" persecution, meaning they were either shot, caught in cage or spring traps or died as a result of their nests being destroyed. Those killed by direct persecution included three peregrines, eight buzzards and one red kite. 
Many of those raptors killed were predominantly found in areas of game-rearing interest, the report shows. 
For red kites, the figures represent a massive reduction on the persecution figures for the previous year, in which there were an unprecedented ten confirmed cases of poisoning for the species. 
However, although the report shows a change in fortunes for the red kite, the apparent improvement is largely undermined by RSPB figures yet to be published for 2003. 
Although it will not report on last year's raptor persecution incidents until the beginning of 2005, the organisation already knows that ten red kites were killed last year. 
Also of particular note for 2002 was the killing of two white-tailed eagles. This equals all the known white-tailed eagle poisonings for the entire 25 year re-introduction programme since it began. The loss of breeding adults is the most damaging form of persecution that the long-lived, slow-breeding eagles can suffer. 
In order to prevent the continuation of raptor persecution, the RSPB report recommends that better enforcement of wildlife legislation and strengthening of the law to protect those species affected should remain a priority. 
It also calls on the Scottish Executive to fully implement the Nature Conservation Bill, which contains stronger measures to deal with wildlife crime in Scotland. 
Keith Morton, RSPB Scotland's investigations officer, said: "In some areas, a 19th-century attitude seems to still exist, whereby any predatory bird becomes a target. This is an outdated and deplorable attitude. We plan to assist the police with every criminal case we hear about and hope to see the tough new laws against this kind of activity used to the full to discourage it from happening any further." 
RSPB Scotland's Adam Harper added: "All birds are protected under the Wildlife and Countryside Act of 1981. As of last spring, wildlife was given even greater protection and wildlife criminals could now face prison. The Scottish Parliament is also currently looking at enhanced legislation with the Nature Conservation Bill." 
Commenting on the 2002 report, Alex Hogg, the chairman of the Scottish Gamekeepers Association (SGA), said: "I really feel that since the SGA was set up the poisoning incidents have been reducing and have fallen every year." 

</content>

</doc>
