<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jul 07 10:25:32 2004</date>
  <content>
  
Second monkeypox outbreak hits US
 
 
Pet chinchilla may be carriers 

Seven people in the Los Angeles area have seriously ill from monkeypox - a rare smallpox-like disease, US health officials say. More than 50 possible cases are being investigated. 

The disease, which is not usually fatal to humans, has previously been discovered in Wisconsin, Illinois and Indiana in mid-May.  Most of those affected had contact with prairie dogs - a type of wild rodent which lives in burrows on the western US plains, and sold as pets. 

A senior official with the Center for Infectious Diseases (CDC) told reporters seven people were in hospital out of "50 cases of serious illness...under investigation. This appears to be a different strain than the one in the mid-west."  

The death rate from monkeypox in Africa has ranged from 1% to 10% of cases. No one died from the mid-West cases.

Health authorities believe the source of the infection was a chinchilla, which has not previously known to be susceptible to the virus. Pet shops, distributors, and breeder farms are being investigated.

A concern is that the virus could spread to other rodents - especially wild mice and rabbits - and become uncontrollable if established in native species, the CDC says. 

It has issued instructions to doctors and vets on how to detect symptoms of monkeypox among patients and what measures to take when handling it. 

Monkeypox is caused by a virus known as an orthopoxvirus and is from the same family of viruses as  smallpox. 

The World Health Organization (WHO) reports on its website that the most recent big outbreak occurred in the Democratic Republic of Congo in 1997. 

Protection against monkeypox was much greater when people were vaccinated against smallpox. 

But with the eradication of smallpox in 1980, vaccination also ended, the WHO notes. 

 </content>


</doc>
