<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 26 19:18:43 2004</date>
  <content>
"It?s not 100-percent foolproof. It?s more that mad cow is incredibly
unlikely to be in the kosher food supply," said Rabbi Eliezer Eidlitz,
founder of the Kosher Information Bureau (kosherquest.com) and a leading
national authority in matters of kashrut, or Jewish dietary law.

Mad cow disease turned up in a Washington state Holstein in late December.
The cow was a ?downer,? an animal too sick to walk to the slaughter. The
Department of Agriculture recently banned downers from slaughter for beef,
but that was a moot point for the kosher industry, which has never allowed
their use.
...
No kosher beef has tested positive with mad cow, as bovine spongiform
encephalopathy (BSE) is colloquially called, even during the epidemic in
England in the 1990s. One cow with the disease was found in the Golan in
Israel in 2002, but it never made it into the food supply. An infected cow
can transmit the disease to humans as the variant Creutzfeldt-Jakob
disease, a highly debilitating and always fatal brain-wasting disease.
...
Kosher cattle are slaughtered young ? 18 to 24 months ? before they can
acquire any illnesses or blemishes that would render them treif
(nonkosher). All cases of mad cow have been discovered in cattle over 3
years old (though the prions ? the abnormal protein that cause BSE ? might
be present in an incubative state in younger cattle).

Dairy cows ? where most cases of mad cow have appeared ? are not used for
kosher beef, because during their milk-producing years they have been
subjected to lactation-increasing procedures that make them more likely to
have a health issue that will disqualify them as kosher meat.

Kosher slaughter precludes the use of stun guns to the head, a
preslaughter procedure that could loosen and spread brain or nerve matter
? where BSE is most likely to reside. The stripping devices used in
nonkosher meat processing make it likely that spinal chord or other nerve
tissue will end up in ground or processed beef, while kosher processors do
not use such mechanisms.
...
Of course, if the mad cow furor gets any worse than it is now, people who
have gotten a quick and not-so-pleasant education in the meat industry
might opt for something even safer than keeping kosher ? vegetarianism.
</content>

</doc>
