<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb 11 02:21:24 2004</date>
  <content>
A national wildlife group is asking Interior Secretary Gale Norton to turn 
her legal eye on Alaska's aerial wolf control program and find that it violates 
federal law. 
Defenders of Wildlife submitted a 15-page petition Monday requesting that 
Norton find that the Airborne Hunting Act of 1971 does not allow the use of 
aircraft to kill wolves to boost game populations. 
The Washington, D.C.-based group also is asking that Norton amend the federal 
law to say: "A state may not issue permits, or engage in any otherwise 
prohibited activity under the Airborne Hunting Act, for the purpose of manipulating 
any wildlife populations." 
Alaska currently has a state-sponsored aerial wolf kill program under way in 
two areas of the state. The game board will consider expanding the program to 
other parts of the state at a meeting in several weeks. 
"Because the programs are for the purpose of enhancing hunting and other 
recreational opportunities, unrelated to protecting wildlife, they violate the 
Airborne Hunting Act," the group said in its petition. 
The group is turning to the federal government for relief after another 
animal rights group, Friends of Animals, failed in state court to put a stop to the 
program in the McGrath area in the Interior and around Glennallen in 
Southcentral. 
"Our efforts to address this issue with Alaska's leaders have fallen on deaf 
ears, leaving us no choice but to turn to the federal government for help," 
Defenders of Wildlife spokesman Joel Bennett said in a statement. 
Republican Gov. Frank Murkowski remains supportive of the wolf control 
program, despite a national campaign from Friends of Animals, with about 200,000 
members, to boycott Alaska's $2 billion-a-year tourism industry. 
Alaska voters banned aircraft-assisted, land-and-shoot wolf hunting in ballot 
measures in 1996 and 2000. But the Alaska Legislature last year passed a law 
allowing private citizens to participate in state-sponsored predator control 
programs. 
The program aims to kill 40 wolves near McGrath and about 140 in the Nelchina 
basin this winter to give young moose a better chance of surviving. In both 
areas, residents have long complained that bears and wolves eat too many moose, 
driving down the moose population and leaving too few to hunt for food.
</content>

</doc>
