<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 25 06:49:46 2004</date>
  <content>
While at Radnor High School, Josh Balk could list the vital statistics of
virtually every baseball player in the major leagues. From batting
averages to home run records, Balk, who is still the all-time leader in
strikeouts and wins at Radnor High, lived baseball. 

Today however, Balk, has memorized some other statistics. Rather than
giving predictions for the Cubs? chances next year, he can detail the
cruelties endured by animals on factory farms.

"Egg-laying hens are caged so tightly they can?t even flap their wings,"
Balk says. He continues, "It would be illegal to castrate a dog without
painkiller in the U.S., yet this is exactly what happens to tens of
millions of cattle and pigs each year with no legal repercussions whatsoever."

Balk, 24, the son of Jim and Wendy Balk of Radnor, works for Compassion
Over Killing (COK), a non-profit animal advocacy organization based in
Takoma Park, Md.
...
After attending a talk by Miyun Park, the president of Compassion Over
Killing, Balk decided to become vegan, a vegetarian who does not eat eggs
or dairy products.

Park hired Balk a year ago to head the organization?s vegetarian outreach
efforts, and he now works to let as many people as possible know their
message: "We can help stop animal cruelty with every bite we take," Balk
says. "We have no nutritional need for meat, eggs, or dairy, yet we cause
immense amounts of suffering when we buy these products."
...
Campaigns conducted by Compassion Over Killing include an exhibit at the
National Mall on "Factory Farming in America," a free "Vegetarian Starter
Guide" program, a restaurant outreach program, a campaign against the use
of animals in the circus, vegetarian leafleting and investigations into
cruelty.

Balk said COK works to end animal abuse, primarily focusing on cruelty to
animals in agriculture. COK helps make vegetarian eating as easy as
possible with free vegetarian starter guides, recipe booklets, restaurant
guides, and web sites like TryVeg.com.

For information about COK people can visit the Web site atwww.cok.net or
calling (301) 891-2458.</content>

</doc>
