<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Feb 17 09:01:38 2004</date>
  <content>
    As a representative voice of more than 85 Cape Cod residents who publicly 
support the graduate students' opposition of the Tufts University School of 
Veterinary Medicine's (TUSVM) bone healing experiment, I would like to share 
with you our perspective on the controversy that recently swept through your 
campus ("Grafton campus community deals with aftermath of controversial animal 
deaths" Tufts Daily, Feb. 9). 
    Just hours before attending a New Years Eve fundraiser for TUSVM's 
Oncology department we learned of the plight of five research dogs with surgically 
broken legs. Prior to hearing the evening news, none of us had scrutinized the 
kinds of research our donations might be supporting. As supporters and patrons 
of a school considered an ethical leader in the humane treatment of animals, 
we had simply taken it for granted that our dollars were being spent on the 
research of naturally occurring disease and injury. After hearing the news we 
immediately began to reevaluate our previous misconception. 
    Although it was learned that the Oncology fundraiser had no apparent 
direct ties to the experiment in question, several attendees continued to express 
concern that their donation's might be diverted to animal research methods 
that they themselves might not agree with. Consequently, the research dogs' story 
prompted us to begin a discussion of our views on the subject of responsible 
animal research. 
    Whereas, we are not all scientists, together we possess extensive 
experience caring for a wide variety of animal species with varying degrees of good 
health, illness and injury. Accordingly, it doesn't take a scientific degree to 
know that it should be possible to measure the healing of canine bones 
through the same methods as are used with humans, or that rehabilitation 
possibilities do exist for two or three legged dogs "bred specifically for research" 
("Dogs now gone: Tufts destroys five research canines" </content>

</doc>
