<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr 19 10:00:24 2004</date>
  <content>
...and they're after Rich Cookson, who, covered in a variety of ghastly but 
dog-friendly scents, has offered himself up as prey for a day's drag-hunting in 
the New Forest. But does this non-fatal alternative to bloodsports still 
carry the same thrill of the chase?
19 April 2004 
I have rarely smelt this bad. My legs and hands are covered in a mixture of 
vegetable oil, artificial rabbit scent, dog biscuits, canine saliva and a 
chemical that smells uncannily like chicken tikka masala. It's also an unseasonably 
hot day, and running up this hill isn't making me smell any sweeter.
Dragging along behind me, on a piece of twine, is a sock that's been stuffed 
with pebbles and rags, and liberally doused with the oil, rabbit-juice and 
curry powder. Wherever I run, it leaves an invisible trial that, somewhere in the 
woods below, seven sharp-nosed hounds are following to track me down.
It may be distinctly low-tech, but this malodorous sock-on-a-string is at the 
heart of a country sport that could see a massive surge in popularity if the 
Government makes good its election promise to ban hunting with hounds. 
Drag-hunting is similar to conventional hunting in many respects, except that hunters 
and their hounds follow an artificial scent laid by a runner or a pony, 
rather than chasing live animals such as foxes or deer. On the face of it, this 
"cruelty-free" brand appears to offer a neat compromise between animal-welfare 
campaigners and hunting supporters - but many die-hard hunters simply don't see 
it that way.
There is one other important distinction, especially for me as today's 
quarry: I won't be mauled by a pack of hungry dogs and then shot, when they 
eventually track me down. At least, that's what they told me back at the car...






 


__________________________________________________________________________
</content>

</doc>
