<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr  5 18:18:13 2004</date>
  <content>
"Commercial hunting of baby seals is back and even bigger than when it
stirred a global outcry two decades ago.

"Horrified by the clubbing of infant harp seals, animal rights advocates
swayed public opinion against the hunt. Environmentalists joined the
campaign, fearing that the species was being depleted. World sales
collapsed. Even Canada reacted with revulsion and began stiffening
regulations on the kill.

"Now, Canada has lifted the quota to a rate unheard of in a half century,
buoyed by new markets in Russia and Poland, and changing environmental
calculations. A recovering market has turned into a quiet boom.

"Here on ice patches of the Gulf of St. Lawrence, the hunt looks nearly as
brutal as ever. For as far as the eye can see, dozens of burly men bearing
clubs roam the ice in snowmobiles and spiked boots in search of silvery
young harp seals. With one or two blows to the head, they crush the skulls,
sometimes leaving the young animals in convulsions. The men drag the bodies
to waiting fishing vessels or skin them on the spot, leaving a crisscross 
of
bloody trails on the slowly melting ice."

We learn that animal rights campaigns in the 1970's and 1980's shut down
American and European markets and forced a virtual collapse of the hunt,
"But over the last six years, Canada's seal hunt, by far the world's 
largest
and commercially most valuable, has undergone a gradual revival that has
virtually escaped world attention. That trend is making an extraordinary
jump this year, when the federal government will allow the killing of up to
350,000 baby harp seals, or more than one in three of all those born,
largely for their valuable fur.
That is an increase of more than 100,000 from recent years, and the largest
number hunted in at least a half century."

Abolitionists, who oppose welfare reforms, arguing that they stand in the
way of the ultimate goal of animal liberation,  might be buoyed by this
line:

  "Meanwhile, tougher hunting rules, including stiffer regulations to avert
skinning the seals alive, have muted the effort to stop the hunt and eased
the consciences of Canadians."

And there is more information suggesting that calling for an end of what
seems to be the most egregious cruelty may not have a positive impact on 
the
overall suffering:

"Embarrassed by all the publicity accusing Canada of inhumane treatment of
animals, the government banned killing whitecoats -- the youngest pups up 
to
12 days old. Now only the seals who have shed their white coats and become
"beaters," at about three weeks old, are killed in these waters for their
black-spotted silvery fur. The killing of those young seals has so far
raised fewer hackles, although critics say hunting methods have not been
substantially changed."

We learn that seal products remain banned in the United States but that
there are new markets in Eastern Europe and China.
</content>

</doc>
