<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Feb  5 09:06:18 2004</date>
  <content>
The security firm Securicor has announced it will not renew its contract with 
Huntingdon Life Sciences (HLS) because of on going protests by animal rights 
activists. The company, which has guarded the gates at HLS for three or four 
years, has seen its regional offices and management become the target of animal 
rights activists in recent weeks. 
It is a double blow for bosses after HLS parted company with another security 
firm, ADT, which was subjected to demonstrations outside its offices. 
HLS chief executive Brian Cass denounced the decision saying protests against 
the business have involved, 'a few ladies with placards and a bit of noise'. 
Caroline Bailey of Stop Huntingdon Animal Cruelty (SHAC) said: "This is a 
victory for SHAC. Any firm which does business with HLS can expect to be targeted 
by us. As far as we are concerned, they deserve everything they get." And she 
warned the promise not to renew links with HLS will not save Securicor in the 
short-term. Bailey said: "Our campaign will continue as long as they are 
guarding the gates." And in fact several activists got together and decided to pay 
a visit to Securicor yesterday. Delighted at the news that they were going to 
sever the contract with HLS, they went to ask if they would bring the date 
forward and terminate all involvement with the company immediately. 
HLS, which tests drugs and chemicals on dogs and other mammals, has had a 
number of associated companies terminate contracts after sustained pressure from 
an organization called SHAC, which stands for Stop Huntingdon Animal Cruelty. 
Last March, Deloitte &amp; Touche quit as auditors for the business, and the 
company has moved its listing to the US to prevent intimidation of its 
shareholders. The company was at one point also forced to use the Bank of England as a 
"lender of last resort" after other businesses pulled banking facilities from </content>

</doc>
