<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon May  3 19:18:54 2004</date>
  <content>
Please don't assume that someone else has answered this email or helped out.  
There are times that things get posted on here and not one response comes 
back.   The more ideas, the more people advise, the better!! THANKS!!!

I've gotten a call from a woman that lives in Shawnee and is in a difficult 
situation with a neglected nursing mother dog.  I'm hoping some of you that 
live in the Shawnee area may be able to help her, especially if you are familar 
with the animal control/shelter system there.  Also, I know some folks on  
this list (not in Shawnee) have a lot of experience with domestic animal issues 
in the area related to animal control and/or abuse.  If you can offer  help or 
advice in any way, please contact Amy Wilson at (405) 255-4749.

The problem:  Amy found a very emaciated dog in her neighborhood, took the  
dog to a vet who said the dog was malnourished and dehydrated and probably 
hadn't eaten for days.  A neighbor came to Amy and said that the dog was his, and 
that she was nursing a litter of puppies.  Amy asked the man to  prove the dog 
was his, and he showed her the puppies--who immediately took to nursing from 
the mother.  Amy offered to give the man money for dog food, feed them 
herself, or buy the dog and puppies from him, all of which he refused.  She checks 
daily on the dog, which never has any food or water,  and the mother dog shares 
a yard with a large boxer who apparently eats any 
food she puts over the fence.

Amy contacted animal control for help.  They were rude and unhelpful in 
several ways, and she wants to advance on animal negligence/cruelty charges  
but the animal control offices will not do anything.

Obviously a nursing dog is in immediate need of good nutrition and plenty of  
water, so that need is dire.  In addition, some form of legal action needs  
to be taken to remedy the complete lack of support for animals in this area.

</content>

</doc>
