<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Aug 22 02:14:03 2003</date>
  <content>
  
Chinchillas are endangered due to exploitation of the 
animal for fur. Protected wild populations continue 
to decline. Its habitat is threatened by human land 
alterations in north central Chile. Without funds, research 
and conservation wild populations will be extinct in 
the near future. 

Chinchillas are originally gray in color with a small 
squirrel-like body, large mouse-like ears and a bushy 
tail. The characteristic that they are best known for is 
their plush fur. Where humans have one hair from each 
follicle, a chinchilla has more than 50 hairs from a 
single follicle. An adult chinchilla weighs between 400 
and 500 grams. Two species of chinchillas are recognized 
as: Chinchilla brevicaudata (Blue Bolivian Chinchilla), 
and Chinchilla lanigera (Lanigera). 

Exploitation for the fur trade to markets in Europe and 
North America started by the onset of the 19th century and 
demand for the pelts continues today. Requiring a hundred 
pelts per coat, this fur is among the most expensive and 
rarest in the world. "In 1928, a coat made of Bolivian pelts 
cost half a million gold marks". In 1992, a chinchilla fur 
coat cost $22,000. 


The chinchilla population declined steadily because of 
hunting and trapping. At the end of the nineteenth century, 
the once abundant animals had become endangered. Humans were 
hunting and trapping the animal for its fur faster than 
the animal could repopulate themselves resulting in scarcity 
of the species. By 1918 Chile had laws against trapping the animal.
Now that populations have increased, poaching has increased
again as well. As the latest fad pet in the U.S., wild 
chinchilla from Chile or Bolivia have become a prize possession.
An individual chinchilla can fetch $700 from frenzied buyers.
Often half of the chinchilla smuggled out of these countries die 
enroute to the States. Steps must be taken to stop the decimation
of the wild populations before they truly become another
creature hunted to exinction.

  
  
</content>

</doc>
