<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan  5 23:14:26 2004</date>
  <content>
Nothing, not an impending gala nor the chill of winter, can tempt Betty
Jean Bavar to dig out her once-beloved mink coat. "I don't know if it's a
reaction to popular sentiment toward the killing of animals or just that
my lifestyle is much more casual today," said Ms. Bavar, 61, who lives in
Baltimore. "I only know that I have stopped wearing fur."

Her daughter, Adrienne Bavar, however, tells a different story. "I don't
have a problem wearing fur," she said. "I'm not like, `Oh, my God, I have
on a dead animal.' " Ms. Bavar, 29, a public relations consultant in New
York, owns a fur-lined army jacket and wore a white mink stole on her
wedding day last year. Her friends agree that fur is fine, she said, so
long as it is not showy or dated, conjuring an image of Joan Collins in
her "Dynasty" days.
...
There are indications that the fear of ostentation and concerns over the
slaughter of fur-bearing animals that troubled the baby boomers do not
afflict many younger women. On the contrary, style-conscious women in
their late 20's and 30's seem to wear fur unabashedly, heeding fashion
more than conscience.
...
Other students of consumer attitudes suggest that flaunting pelts can be a
badge of rebellion. "Wearing fur is a quick way for you to feel superior
to your mother," said James Twitchell, the author of "Living It Up: Our
Love Affair With Luxury."
...
But Ingrid Newkirk, the president of People for the Ethical Treatment of
Animals, disagreed that the animal-rights movement has lost a generation.
"There are plenty of young women who are revolted by the idea of fur," she
said. She suggested a visit to her organization's Web site to read the
testimonials of young women expressing a revulsion for fur.

Ms. Newkirk conceded that by offering new, relatively inexpensive styles,
the fur industry has successfully tempted some younger women. Indeed,
today there is a widening selection of furs with casual styling or fur
used as an accent on bomber jackets, vests, hoodies and the like. Many
furriers also offer skins that masquerade as something else. "A lot of the
fur we make looks like velvet or a yarn that's been knitted to resemble a
sweater," said Melissa Gellman, a spokeswoman for J. Mendel, a purveyor of
luxury furs and fur accessories. The company's slogan, "This Is Not Your
Grandmother's Fur," refers to innovations like sheared mink passing itself
off as velvet.

At prices below $5,000 for full-length rabbit coats, or several hundred
dollars for coats with fur collars, sweaters trimmed with fur and fur
scarves and hats , many women have found that fur is an affordable
indulgence, compared with a traditional sable coat, which can run into the
tens of thousands. "You can get a rabbit coat for $80," Ms. Newkirk of
PETA lamented, "basically the price of a few packs of cigarettes."

Of equal concern to animal-rights activists, she said, is the adoption of
fur as a status symbol. "Our major struggle at the moment is to get out
the message to people in the hip-hop community," Ms. Newkirk said, "people
for whom fur is a prized acquisition in much the way the Cadillac was two
generations back."</content>

</doc>
