<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar  7 08:03:43 2004</date>
  <content>



How did the politics of Alaska wildlife get so divisive? 
These days we've got legislators on opposite sides of the philosophical 
divide trying to dictate that: 
? The best use of all Alaska big-game animals should be food. 
? The Board of Game should be restructured to give a larger say to 
"nonconsumptive" wildlife users, i.e. animal lovers. 
Has the entire process been taken over by extremists on opposite ends of the 
debate who share only one thing, a fundamental lack of understanding about 
Arctic and subarctic ecosystems? 
One group wants a moose behind every willow bush. 
The other wants wolves so plentiful as to make wolf viewing an easy and 
marketable activity. 
Neither is feasible, let alone realistic. 
Alaska is a far northern landscape. A short growing season restricts the 
diversity and productivity of plant life, limiting the number of herbivores it can 
support. The small number of prey species -- even counting Alaska's caribou 
herds, which look large because they cluster -- dictate that there will be food 
for only a limited number of predators. 
Man can manipulate this environment. Nonconsumptive users who think nature 
operates in some sort of sensible balance, are simply wrong. Look no further 
than Anchorage. The city is overrun with moose for one simple reason: It's a 
predator-free zone. 
Motor vehicles kill plenty of moose here every year, but they do not kill 
anywhere near as many as wild predators take. Still, you may have noticed you 
can't count on finding a moose in Anchorage anytime you want. Visiting tourist 
friends might drive around town for days and not spot a moose. 
It is worth noting that if we decided Anchorage moose should be consumed, we 
wouldn't feed many people. 
Unless we wanted to kill all 1,000 or so in one big bloodletting -- after 
which no one would ever see a moose in Anchorage again -- we might be able to 
remove 200 moose a year from this population. But cars already get more than 100. 
So the number of moose that hunters could shoot would be fewer than that. 
I'd like to shoot an Anchorage moose. I like moose meat, and the doggone 
critters are always getting up on my deck to eat our willows. It would be easy and 
convenient to dump a winter supply of meat right there outside the door. It's 
an Alaska village resident's fantasy. 
But I'm not sure it's the highest and best use of Anchorage's moose. I 
actually think it might be better if instead of using Anchorage moose to feed people 
-- the roadkills go to charity -- we started using Anchorage moose to feed 
wolves. 
I'm truly sympathetic with all those nonconsumptive users who want to see a 
wolf. That's tough to do in Alaska, and we could make it easier. We could 
create wolf-viewing areas by picking a place to dump the carcasses of moose killed 
on Anchorage roads or by wildlife officials. 
Yes, I know, there are those who might find this sort of animal feeding 
distasteful, but people feed wild birds all the time just to get the chance to see 
them and think that's wonderful.</content>

</doc>
