<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 13 00:24:29 2003</date>
  <content>
I'm asking for your support in a poll of the "most overgrazed livestock 
allotments" in the U.S.  Run by my friend Larry Walker 
(http://rangenet.org/directory/walkerl), the poll is intended as a means 
to increase public awareness about the damage done by ranching to our 
public lands and also to focus attention on the government agencies that 
manage these lands.  Although all of the nominated allotments are worthy 
of the "most overgrazed" title I'm rooting for 3 of them.  (If you're 
not interested in reading the scenarios about the allotments, just skip 
to the voting instructions at the end.)

1) Diamond Bar Allotment (NM): In addition to all the threats to 
wildlife, including the endangered Gila Trout, the allotment is the 
subject of ongoing legal action.  The rancher permittee was thrown off 
the allotment in the late 1990s because he disagreed with government 
imposed cattle reductions and consequently refused to sign his permit. 
The allotment has been closed ever since.  This spring he put his cattle 
back on the allotment in defiance of the closure.  Despite protests by 
activists, the government has not acted against him (might have 
something to do with the Bush administration being sympathetic to 
ranchers).  Public attention focused on this allotment might motivate 
the government to act.

I first visited the allotment in 1997, then returned last July to 
photograph the recent damage that the illegal grazing had done.  I have 
a photopage as supporting evidence for the "overgrazed" condition of the 
allotment (http://rangenet.org/directory/hudakm/diamondbar/index.html)

2) Rock Creek/Mudholes Allotment (UT): Another allotment with ongoing 
legal action.  In 2000, rancher Mary Bulloch failed to comply with a 
government order to remove her cattle because of prolonged drought. 
After the government impounded her cattle, Bulloch arrived with about a 
dozen rancher friends who stole back the cattle.  For this reason and 
also because some trespass cattle remain on the allotment, Bulloch has 
accrued over $77,000 in fines and penalties.  Her case goes to trial in 
late November.  The more attention focused on the allotment the less 
chance that the government will cut a deal with Bulloch, perhaps 
massively reducing her fine and letting her once again grazing cattle on 
the allotment.  
</content>

</doc>
