<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 29 10:23:04 2004</date>
  <content>
Melton and Scadden said that the Harvard initiative will not focus solely on 
human embryonic stem cells, but will include research on adult stem cells as 
well as basic research on animals. Indeed, embryonic stem cells offer great 
promise in basic biology because scientists can use them to learn how the entire 
body develops from a single cell.
In the medical world, the Harvard initiative also represents a vote of 
confidence in a futuristic approach to 
Melton and Scadden said that the Harvard initiative will not focus solely on 
human embryonic stem cells, but will include research on adult stem cells as 
well as basic research on animals. Indeed, embryonic stem cells offer great 
promise in basic biology because scientists can use them to learn how the entire 
body develops from a single cell.
In the medical world, the Harvard initiative also represents a vote of 
confidence in a futuristic approach to medicine known as cell therapy. Since the 
earliest days of the healing arts, patients have been treated with drugs, whether 
gathered from plants or manufactured in a pharmaceutical lab. But for a range 
of degenerative diseases, doctors envision a day when patients are given 
powerful cells that can build a healthy brain, heart, or other tissues.
"This is a new way of approaching medicine," said Scadden. "The current 
arrows in the quiver just aren't going to solve the problem."
medicine known as cell therapy. Since the earliest days of the healing arts, 
patients have been treated with drugs, whether gathered from plants or 
manufactured in a pharmaceutical lab. But for a range of degenerative diseases, 
doctors envision a day when patients are given powerful cells that can build a 
healthy brain, heart, or other tissues.
"This is a new way of approaching medicine," said Scadden. "The current 
arrows in the quiver just aren't going to solve the problem."</content>

</doc>
