<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Oct 22 17:33:11 2003</date>
  <content>Call it White House meets Wild Kingdom.

Conservationists are angry over a Bush administration proposal that would
allow the importation of animals listed on the United States' endangered
species list, a move they say will further cripple the species' dwindling
populations.

The fate of exotic animals and their treatment at the hands of hunters,
animal shows or leather-goods merchants has been raised in recent weeks
after Roy Horne of Siegfried and Roy, a wildly popular Las Vegas show
featuring live tigers, was critically injured when one of the animals
mauled him on stage before a live audience.

And then there was 31-year-old Antoine Yates who was discovered keeping a
350-pound Bengal tiger and an alligator in his Harlem, N.Y., apartment.
Police had to shoot the tiger with tranquilizer darts to subdue him and
remove him to a sanctuary.

Both cases illustrate the nation's fascination with wild and exotic animals.

The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service is proposing a relaxation of
regulations that prohibit the transport of live animals considered
endangered in other countries. That would mean hunters and merchants who
trade in animal skins, tusks and other body parts would be able to go
after their prized prey unquestioned.
...
 "There are a lot of other ways to bring in revenue rather than to place a
price tag on endangered species to allow them to be killed or captured,"
said Wayne Pacelle, senior vice president of The Humane Society of the
United States.

HSUS says the international commercial wildlife trade is worth billions of
dollars every year and has been responsible for the decline of wild
populations of a number of species of animals and plants.
...
However, Pacelle said of hunters, "There is a far larger universe of
people interested in watching wildlife in their native habitats than there
are wealthy trophy hunters who want to shoot endangered species. This is a
relatively small subset of the American population."

--</content>

</doc>
