<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat May 31 21:12:10 2003</date>
  <content>
 (31 May)

reviews
Book

The Big Fix: How the Pharmaceutical Industry Rips Off American Consumers
The Big Fix opens with feisty 77 year old Melva McCuddy from Ohio struggling
to find more than $6000 a year to pay for her multiple medications. We learn
that she travels across the United States border to Canada, where her breast
cancer drug, tamoxifen, is eight times cheaper than in her local pharmacy.
Then we meet her son and grandson, both with medical troubles of their own,
and discover that the family has three generations without any insurance
cover for pharmaceuticals, and three generations forced to rely on handouts
from their doctors. "The worst thing," Melva told the audience at the book's
launch in Washington DC this month, "is being forced to beg doctors for free
samples."
Written in a plain, clear, direct style, and with its research funded in
part by the AFL-CIO-the umbrella labour organisation in the United
States-The Big Fix is an attempt to educate working Americans about the
dirty tricks of the pharmaceutical industry. With the soaring costs of drugs
and health care set to become the biggest domestic issue in next year's US
presidential election, the book is certainly timely.

Anyone familiar with the industry's antics won't find much that's new in The
Big Fix. It is, however, a remarkably accessible round-up of the best
evidence and the sharpest analysis about key issues, including drug pricing,
patent battles, excessive profiteering, misleading marketing, disease
mongering and doctor-drug company entanglement. Author Katharine Greider has
distilled much scientific research, interviewed many key academics and
activists, and made her way through bulky reports from Congressional
hearings and other investigations.

One of my favourite lines is a comment that comes originally from a drug
company marketer quoted in the magazine Pharmaceutical Executive. The
marketer is discussing the "brilliant" way in which a new condition called
"erectile dysfunction" had been "branded" to help build a market for new
drugs. "We're creating patient populations just as we're creating medicines,
to make sure that products become blockbusters."
</content>

</doc>
