<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 12 19:32:53 2004</date>
  <content>When communist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu was shot 
dead Christmas Day in 1989, it could have been good news for the bears -- he 
had shot hundreds of them. And now the government finds so many bears around 
that hunters are being asked to shoot them again. 

The government announced last week that it would allow hunters to shoot 300 
of Romania's estimated 5,300 bears this year. 

Local environmentalists oppose the move. They say the bear population has 
been overestimated. 

?A bear usually covers between 15 to 20 kilometres in a single night and 
could be counted up to three times by different forest wardens,? says Laszlo 
Szabo- Szeley, president of the environmental group Aves. 

Szeley believes that the brown bear population of Romania has fallen 60 
percent over the last three to four years. The bears are being hunted down already, 
he says. ?It's probably partial or complete extinction of this species in the 
next decade.? 

Aves has launched a campaign to save the Carpathian brown bear. But 
environmentalists face strong opposition from officials. 

Hunting was the privilege of the elite in communist times, and the situation 
is not very different now. Prime Minister Adrian Nastase is also president of 
a hunters' association. Agriculture minister Ilie Sarbu who handles 
environmental matters shot himself in the thigh in a hunting accident Dec. 27. 

Romania is drawing hunters from all around. Over recent years an increasing 
number have come from Germany, Spain, Italy and Austria in expensive group 
tours to hunt stags, brown bears and wolves. Romania is one of the last European 
countries with plenty of what hunters call game. 

The country earned more than six million dollars from hunting expeditions 
last year, officials say. Foreign hunters will spend thousands of dollars to 
shoot a bear. 

?We expect at least the same earnings in 2004 because Romania is an 
interesting hunting place for those who want to bag something really exotic,? says 
Arpad Sarkanz who owns a company providing hunting services. </content>

</doc>
