<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan  5 13:53:50 2004</date>
  <content>
While preparing dinner one night last February, Supriya Kelkar didn?t
think twice before tearing open a package of Lipton SideKicks Broccoli and
White Cheddar Pasta mix.

Kelkar, a vegetarian, had read the package?s label in the supermarket
earlier. Among the ingredients listed on the package were pasta, salt,
cornstarch, cheddar and blue cheese, whey, broccoli, MSG, spices,
autolyzed yeast extract, maltodextrin, and natural flavors.

What came next shocked Kelkar.

?I had a taste of the pasta, and I immediately sensed something ?meaty,??
she told India-West.

So she called the 800 number of Lipton?s customer service to ask if the
product contained meat as one of its ?natural flavors.? She was told by a
representative that it was safe to assume that it did. Kelkar, 23, a
vegetarian since her teens, decided to write a letter to complain.
...
Tejas Mehta, a CPA living in Anaheim, Calif., was a regular customer at a
Marie Callender?s restaurant there. ?I used to go there regularly for
Lions Club meetings,? he recalled, ?and I used to eat the same Fettucini
Alfredo due to the lack of vegetarian choices.?

He asked a waitress to check that the dish was vegetarian, and she
?specifically confirmed? that it was, he said. Mehta, an adherent to the
strictly vegetarian Jain religion, had heard from an acquaintance that
some restaurants added chicken stock to their Alfredo sauce to keep it
moist, so he asked the waitress to doublecheck. His fears were confirmed
when she returned from the kitchen. ?It had been non-vegetarian all
along,? he told India-West.
...
A 2003 national Harris Interactive survey question sponsored by the
Vegetarian Resource Group concluded that about six percent of the United
States population never eats meat (which translates to about 5.7 million
people), while a Time magazine poll last year set the number at closer to
10 million. ?A look at the increased number of vegetarian products now
available is evidence that the interest in vegetarian foods has exploded
in the last few years,? states the VRG?s report, which is posted on their
Web site, www.vrg.org.
...
Efforts to legislate the identification of meat in products have not made
much progress; in 1999 Veggie Lawyers, a group of law students at George
Washington University, petitioned the FDA to change their regulations and
persuaded hundreds of citizens to write to the FDA in support; their
campaign fizzled out in mid-2001.

But one lawmaker has renewed efforts to identify meat on product labels in
an attempt to help not just vegetarians, but also consumers with allergies.

Nita M. Lowey, a Democratic Congresswoman from New York?s 18th district,
introduced H.R. 467, also known as the ?Food Ingredient Right to Know
Act,? in the House of Representatives Jan. 29, 2003.
...
A spokesman for the People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals, the most
visible vegetarian advocacy group in the United States, said the group
deliberately does not issue a vegetarian label for foods. ?For PETA, it?s
not about dogma,? Bruce Friedrich, director of vegan outreach, told
India-West. ?We consider it of utmost importance to save the animals. To
focus on infinitesimal ingredients misses a few key points. We have
enormous respect for religious and dietary restrictions, but they tend to
place personal purity ahead of saving animals. That hurts animals.?

EarthSave, an organization founded in 1988 by one of America?s most famous
and influential vegetarians, bestselling author John Robbins (?Diet for a
New America,? ?Food Revolution?), is enthusiastic about a labeling
program. ?We?d absolutely encourage a label,? said EarthSave executive
director Caryn Hartglass. ?People have been talking about a label for a
long time. We certainly need one. But it needs significant interest from
the public.? She invites India-West readers to contact the organization to
show support for a labeling campaign (see sidebar). 
...
According to dietician Geeta Sikand, ?The industry is consumer driven and
in my opinion will respond to the consumers? needs. If consumers demand
for a label that states, ?contains no meat products? or ?contains no
animal products,? I believe the industry will respond. Vegetarians have a
right to know what is in the food they eat.?</content>

</doc>
