<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jun 22 11:13:30 2004</date>
  <content>


Federal Horse Slaughter Bill Urgently Needs Your Support!

NAVS Supporters,

The federal bill that would ban the slaughter of horses for
human consumption is in danger of being defeated without even a
vote. This bill, H.R. 857, was assigned to the U.S. House
Committee on Agriculture, which must review and decide whether
to recommend passage of this bill to the entire House, or to
"kill" the bill while still in committee.

Despite the sponsorship of more than 220 Representatives, the
Chairman of the Committee on Agriculture, Rep. Bob Goodlatte
(R-VA), is refusing to call for a vote on this bill. In
addition, he is pressuring current sponsors to withdraw their
support, citing overwhelming support by lobbying groups from the
meat industry, agricultural interests, and organizations
supporting horse use who benefit from having a market to sell
their unwanted horses.

Don't let economic special interest groups stop this bill from
being heard.

Please call your U.S. Representative TODAY. Ask that they
support - and continue to support - a ban on killing horses for
food in this country. It is a cruel and callous practice that
perpetuates unrestricted breeding because money can be made off
of "surplus" animals, especially those by-products of the
hormone replacement industry from pregnant mares used in the
manufacturing of Premarin and Prempro.

When you write or call, you can include one or more of these
points:

* Smarty Jones was the focus of national adoration two weeks ago
in his bid for the triple crown of horse racing. An earlier
triple-crown contender, Ferdinand, was recently slaughtered in
Japan for pet food.

* Since the early 1970s, it is estimated that as many as 6
million American horses have been slaughtered in the U.S. and
Canada.

* Horses are legally defined as "companion animals" in many
states.

* Most horses are bought at auction for the slaughterhouse and
the source of the animals - and their history - is obscured for
purposes of health evaluations; they are given drugs unsuitable
for human consumption, including deworming medication and
hormones in large quantities.

* According to state and national polls (as reported by Equine
Advocates), between 81 and 93 percent of Americans oppose the
slaughter of horses for food.

* The horses used to produce hormone replacement drugs for
millions of women each year produce unwanted foals as a
"byproduct" that must be disposed of to protect profits.

Horses play an integral role in America's heritage and culture.
Two weeks ago, the country was riveted to President Reagan's
funeral. The riderless horse was a poignant symbol of his
passing. Sgt. York, the 13-year old black horse, is an
ex-racehorse from New Jersey. What will be his final fate?

Please let your voice be heard on where American horses will
finally rest.

To see this bill, go to www.animallaw.com and select Search Laws
and Legislation, select the search legislation check box, under
jurisdiction, select Federal (US), and type "horse slaughter" in
the keyword field.

Your letters and phone calls can make a difference! To find your
federal representative, go to: www.house.gov/writerep/. If you
would like to call instead, identify your representative, then
visit your representative's website at
http://www.house.gov/house/MemberWWW.html for phone and fax
information.



</content>

</doc>
