<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Mar  8 23:14:05 2004</date>
  <date>Mar. 8, 2004   --</date>
  <content>

In a move worthy of Orwell's Big Brother, the Washington state legislature 
is being asked to fund a law enforcement database of "eco-terrorists" that 
would, in fact, track citizens engaged in lawful environmental advocacy, 
such as signing a petition to save old-growth forests, attending a rally 
for clean air, or simply joining a group like the Sierra Club or Defenders 
of Wildlife.

There is still time to stop this draconian and unconstitutional measure, 
but we need to act today! Contact your state representative and urge him or 
her to vote against any attempt to fund the Animal and Ecological Terrorism 
Act such as the current Senate Budget Bill (SB 6187), presently before the 
House Rules Committee.

The AETA invokes the language of terrorism to restrict our hard- won 
constitutional rights of free assembly and free speech.  It defines "animal 
rights or ecological terrorist organization" as "two or more persons 
organized for the purpose of supporting any politically motivated activity 
intended to obstruct or deter any persons from participating in an activity 
involving animals or... natural resources."

This dangerously broad definition of "terrorist" would catch anybody who's 
ever sent in $10 to save the pandas. It's a thinly disguised effort to 
quash environmental activism and intimidate citizens who want to speak out. 
  The sponsors of this legislation have certainly learned from Attorney 
General Ashcroft's repeated use of terrorism fears to justify the sacrifice 
of Americans' rights and liberties.

We need your help to show that even in times of elevated security concerns, 
Americans aren't willing to give up their most cherished freedoms. Contact 
your state representative TODAY and urge him or her to vote against any 
attempt to fund the Animal and Ecological Terrorism Act such as the current 
Senate Budget Bill SB 6187).

</content>

</doc>
