<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Sep  3 10:14:06 2003</date>
  <content>
Natasha Sawicki read about it on a vegetarian Web site. Jackie Miller
heard the news while on a cheese tour in Vermont.

What they discovered is probably the most overlooked, hidden animal
product in food otherwise considered vegetarian, says Boulder Co-op
Market cheese manager Chris Hill.

The mystery ingredient, still being discovered by many vegetarians ?
even in a veggie savvy place like Boulder ? is something called
rennet, also called rennin.

Rennin, according to the Barron's cooking guide, Food Lover's
Companion, is "a coagulating enzyme obtained from a young animal's
(usually a calf's) stomach." It's used to curdle milk in foods such
as cheese.

The knowledge made Sawicki, a vegetarian of five years, think twice
about so-called vegetarian foods. 
...
Discovering hidden animal products in food considered to be meat-free
is part of the lifelong, often complex journey of making conscious
food choices, vegetarians say.

It's not enough to stop eating hamburger, often followed by poultry
and fish. Those who embark on this path, largely motivated by ethics,
soon awaken to the fact that animal products and byproducts are found
in foods as seemingly innocent as chewing gum. (Some brands contain
stearic acid, an animal fat, or lanolin, the waxy fat from sheep's
wool.)

"The two biggest things people overlook are supplements with gel caps
and cheese with rennet," says Hill at the Co-op. "It's a real shock
to people."

The Boulder Co-op, an organic vegetarian market, stocks products from
at least 25 companies that offer either rennetless cheese, or cheese
made with vegetarian or microbial rennet. The refrigerated aisle is
flush with colorful cheese, including blocks of sharp cheddar,
triangles of Parmesan, tubs of fresh mozzarella, and packages of
sliced pepper jack. Haystack, a local maker of goat cheese, doesn't
use animal-based rennet, Hill says. 

</content>

</doc>
