<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Mar  9 08:42:32 2004</date>
  <content>
On Saturday, May 8th, the day before Mothers Day, there will be pet 
store demonstrations held throughout the State of Florida, in a 
massive effort to educate the public about puppymills.  We are 
notifying as many rescue groups and shelters as we possibly can, 
and asking if you all could possibly help the cause by arranging for 
demonstrations in your area or to attend a demonstration that has 
been arranged.  We had a fairly good turnout for the two recent 
demonstrations that were held down here.  Many of those that attended 
were either from rescue groups/shelters or had a horrifying 
experience with pet store puppymill puppies.  As you are probably 
well aware, new pet stores are opening up all over.   Here in Broward 
County, the numbers are unbelievable.  We know that there are many 
others throughout the state that feel as we do about pet stores and 
puppymills.

If we could some how pull this off, this could be the most eye 
opening event ever in Florida. But we can't do it without your help.  
You would have to contact your local police, city hall or code 
enforcement, to find out if a permit or letter of authorization is 
needed.  More than likely something is required.  They will probably 
want at least 1 weeks notice, but it would be better to check with 
them.  They will or should give you the do's and dont's as well.  
Some cities do not allow signs on sticks (no sticks) or bullhorns.  You 
certainly want to inform them that this is going to be a peaceful 
demonstration.  

It is important that we have an idea as to how many people are 
participating, and which part of the state they are in, so that we 
know which areas will be covered.  We are planning to contact the 
media here in south Florida and encourage you to do the same for 
your area.  We will attempt to also have it reported/announced on 
national news, providing we know which areas are demonstrating.   Can 
we count on you and your rescue organization, friends, neighbors and 
family?  

</content>

</doc>
