<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 22 14:49:13 2003</date>
  <content>
      Last of the lions 
     
        
      If people can't learn how to live with lions, we might well have to live without them. Stephanie Pain tells the sorry tale of a disappearing predator 
     
        
      "I'M SORRY, could you repeat that figure please?" The phone line was crackly and I thought I must have misheard. Laurence Frank said it again. "Around 23,000." That, it seems, is how many lions remain in the whole of Africa. It's a shockingly small number. But there is worse: "It's not just lions. Populations of all African predators are plummeting," says Frank, a wildlife biologist at the University of California, Berkeley.

      Twenty years ago the lion population seemed in good shape. There were no hard figures but conservationists guessed there were around 200,000. Inside parks and reserves they seemed to be thriving. What no one had noticed was that they were disappearing everywhere else, and so were other predators. Wild dogs once roamed over most of sub-Saharan Africa. Now there are between 3000 and 5500, living in a tiny fraction of their former territory. Cheetahs once ranged over most of Africa and central and western Asia: today there are fewer than 15,000. What shocks Frank most is that no one seems to realise how close to disaster these animals are. "People know about elephants, gorillas and rhinos, but they seem blissfully unaware that these large carnivores are nearing the brink."

      What has happened to send these populations of predators into free fall? The short answer is people. People with guns, spears, poison and snares. "People have always killed predators," says Frank. "But there's only so much damage you can do with spears and shields. Now everyone has got rifles and poisons." The slaughter began when Europeans arrived, and a century later, Africa's predators are in real trouble. They aren't yet in such desperate straits as those in other parts of the world, however. "Almost everywhere else, big carnivores have had it already," says Frank. "In Africa it's not too late to save the situation."


</content>

</doc>
