<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:16:43 2003</date>
  <content>A growing militant movement opposed to genetic engineering in 
agriculture and medicine is turning to violent and criminal sabotage - from 
the bombing of a Bay Area biotech company to the destruction of genetically 
modified crops. 
As a result, targeted companies aren't just taking extra security precautions 
but also altering business strategies. 
The violence, which the FBI says suddenly became more serious this year, 
stems in part from frustration that peaceful protests have failed to slow the pace 
of biotech's progress. 
"We've seen a drastic escalation in the use of violent tactics in the past 
year," said Phil Celestini, head of the FBI's domestic terrorism unit in 
Washington. 
A range of militant environmental, economic and animal-rights activist groups 
have used the Internet to organize around biotechnology, first in Europe and 
now in the United States. Many fear the technology will forever harm nature 
while others object to how animals are treated in drug experiments. 
A 25-year-old Californian, Daniel Andreas of San Diego, is wanted by the FBI 
in connection with some of the most recent attacks: the bombings in August of 
the biotech company Chiron Corp. of Emeryville, Calif., and last month of a 
nearby cosmetics manufacturer. Aside from a few shattered windows, little damage 
was done to either company. 
The group that claimed responsibility for the blasts, the previously unheard 
of Revolutionary Cells, vowed more bombings were to come. 
Authorities consider the bombings to mark a new chapter in anti-biotech 
militancy in 2003 that included the vandalism of a Chiron executive's car and the 
trashing of a biology lab at Louisiana State University last month. 
In France, an estimated half of the 100 plots of experimental biotech crops 
were destroyed this year, prompting some 1,500 scientists, including two Nobel 
laureates, to demand an end to the vandalism. 
Almost since James Watson and Francis Crick discovered DNA 50 years ago, 
scientists have been exploring ways to manipulate and exploit those building 
blocks of life for everything from boosting crop yields to germ warfare. 
But questions didn't arise about biotechnology's safety and impact on nature 
until San Francisco area scientists Herb Boyer and Stanley Cohen succeeded 30 
years ago in splicing genes from one species into another. Since then, 
opposition to biotechnology research, first in agriculture and later in medicine, has 
grown, especially in Europe.
</content>

</doc>
