<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 29 01:58:54 2004</date>
  <content>"Watch it," Nico Niessen warns a reporter and a photographer 
from The Star Press. "It's slippery."
Visitors to his dairy barn are normally taken into the milk parlor, office 
and feed alleys, where the floors are dry and clean.
But this particular tour also goes into the pens, lanes and ramps where the 
cows travel when they're not being milked or resting in their sandy stalls. 
Manure from 1,200 cows covers the concrete floors in those areas.
Fortunately, Niessen hands out plastic, throw-away boots to his unprepared 
guests. That protects their shoes and protects his cows from anything harmful 
the shoes might transport into the barn.
Cable-operated automatic floor scrapers slowly push squishy cow dung into 
drain trenches that flow into a 5-million-gallon storage lagoon outdoors.
"This is the swimming pool," Niessen jokes.
His cows discharge enough manure in a year to fill 750 above-ground swimming 
pools, each 52 inches deep and 24 feet around.
Niessen is one of dozens of European dairy farmers - mostly Dutch - who have 
moved to Indiana, Michigan and Ohio since the late 1990s, in part because 
there is an excess of manure in The Netherlands.
Together, the immigrants have started 11 concentrated animal feeding 
operations (CAFOs) in Indiana housing 12,625 dairy cows.
That represents more than eight percent of Indiana's dairy cow population.
Vreba-Hoff Dairy Development, Wauseon, Ohio, is steering the European farmers 
to the three states.
The company has developed three dozen dairy CAFOs for the newcomers and has 
at least 10 more in various stages of development. One of them is Dutch farmer 
Tony Goltstein's proposed Union-Go Dairy in Randolph County.
How many more will come?
"I think we're in the middle of it at this point," said Vreba-Hoff's Cecilia 
Conway, a U.S. citizen whose parents came to America from The Netherlands in 
1960. "There's still a lot of interest."
The public is making a stink over the new Dutch dairies in all three states 
because of their size, odors, manure spills, construction violations and other 
concerns.
After neighbors complained that Niessen's dairy stunk up their laundry when 
hung out to dry, the Henry County Planning Commission denied his petition to 
expand his herd from 1,200 to 1,900. Niessen hired a lawyer who sued the 
planning commission and the neighbors. The case is pending.
An organization called Environmentally Concerned Citizens of Randolph County 
formed last year to stop what it calls Goltstein's proposed "factory farm," 
which would house 1,650 cows. The future of that dairy remains up in the air.
The average dairy farm in Indiana has about 75 cows. The dairies being 
developed in Indiana by Vreba-Hoff range from 675 cows to Niessen's proposed 1,900 
cows.</content>

</doc>
