<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jun 15 23:53:14 2004</date>
  <date>Tue, 15 Jun 2004 14:41:18 -0400</date>
  <content>Our Treatment of Animals and the
Holocaust (New York: Lantern Books, 2002)--the groundbreaking book by
historian and Holocaust educator Charles Patterson, Ph.D.--is fast becoming
an international sensation.

Two years after its publication in the United States it has already been
translated into five languages (Croatian, Czech, German, Italian, Polish)
with more publishers around the world considering it for possible
publication.

The book's title comes from the Yiddish writer and Nobel Laureate, Isaac
Bashevis Singer, to whom the book is dedicated. He was the first major
modern author to describe the exploitation and slaughter of animals in terms
of the Holocaust. "In relation to them, all people are Nazis," he wrote,
"for animals it is an eternal Treblinka." (Treblinka was the Nazi death camp
north of Warsaw.)

ETERNAL TREBLINKA examines the common roots of animal and human oppression
and the similarities between how the Nazis treated their victims and how
human society treats animals slaughtered for food.

The first part of the book describes the emergence of humans as the "master
species" and how it has come to dominate the earth and its other
inhabitants. The second part examines the industrialization of slaughter (of
both animals and humans) in modern times, while the last part of the book
profiles Holocaust-connected Jewish and German animal advocates on both
sides of the Holocaust, including Isaac Bashevis Singer himself.

The Foreword is by Lucy Rosen Kaplan, the daughter of Holocaust survivors,
who is a former attorney for People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals
(PETA).

During the three years Patterson spent writing the book, three literary
agents tried unsuccessfully to place it (a couple of publishers said the
book was "too strong"). In all, 83 publishers declined to accept the book
before Lantern Books finally published it in 2002.

Almost immediately the book began attracting the attention of foreign
publishers, and soon translations were underway.

In April, 2003, the Roman publishing house of Editori Riuniti published the
Italian edition (UN'ETERNA TREBLINKA), and the following month "Vega!POL"
published the Polish edition (WIECZNA TREBLINKA).

In September the Publishing House Prah in Prague published the Czech edition
(VECNA TREBLINKA), which has been reviewed favorably by various leading
publications, including the literature/history/arts magazine ALTERNATIVA,
the quarterly DOKORAN, a bulletin of Czech Writers' Guild, and the LITERARNI
NOVINY, the most important and widely read literary newspaper in the Czech
Republic.

ETERNAL TREBLINKA has also been translated into German (scheduled for
publication by Versand Dienst GmbH, Frankfurt am Main in August) and is
being translated into Croatian for publication in Zagreb later this year.

Publishing houses in Spain, France, The Netherlands, Norway, Chile, India,
and Israel are also reviewing the book for possible publication.

Here's What They're Saying--

"I urge you to read ETERNAL TREBLINKA and think deeply about its important
message. " --Dr. Jane Goodall

"Compelling, controversial, iconoclastic...strongly recommended...a unique
contribution." --Midwest Book Review

"ETERNAL TREBLINKA should be on every list of essential reading for an
informed citizenry...for the compelling comprehensiveness of the
life-and-death story it tells." --National Jewish Post &amp; Opinion

"The whole effect is a very powerful document...No one who reads this book
will fail to be moved." --Anglican Society for the Welfare of Animals

"A must read! -- how mistreatment of animals leads to the dehumanization and
extermination of people as 'mere animals.' Well-written and respectful of
both Judaism and the Holocaust." --Rabbi Yonassan Gershom

"There are good books...entertaining, useful, informative; great
books...whose message reveals a fundamental truth previously unknown or
overlooked; and important books...that can save lives and ameliorate
suffering: ETERNAL TREBLINKA is all three." --Satya Magazine, New York City

"The moral challenge posed by ETERNAL TREBLINKA turns it into a must for
anyone who seeks to delve into the universal lesson of the Holocaust."
--Maariv (Israeli newspaper)

"Important and timely...written with great sensitivity and compassion...I
hope that ETERNAL TREBLINKA will be widely read." --Martyrdom and Resistance
(Holocaust publication)

"Every so often a book is written that has the potential to make an
incredible difference. ETERNAL TREBLINKA is one such book." --N. Glenn
Perrett

"Thorough and thought-provoking book" --Ha'aretz (Israeli newspaper)

"It is seldom that such a comprehensive work of scholarship springs from a
heart of compassion in the service of a noble and necessary idea. All the
ingredients of your thesis--that the oppression of animals serves as the
model for all other forms of oppression--have been available to thinking
people for generations, but it remained for you to pull them together."
--Helen Weaver, author of THE DAISY SUTRA

"Powerful, moving, gut-wrenching, brilliant--destined to be a classic"
--Aviva Cantor, journalist and author

"You must read this carefully documented book" --La Stampa (Italian national
newspaper)

"...promises to be one of the most influential books of the 21st century."
--Dr. Karen Davis, United Poultry Concerns

"It grips like a thriller." --The Freethinker (UK)

"This book is going to change the world."
--Albert Kaplan, Albert Kaplan &amp; Co., Johns Island, SC



================================================

</content>

</doc>
