<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Mar 27 14:36:23 2004</date>
  <content>
Missouri City Animal Control Supervisor Juan Acevedo is pictured outside of 
the shelter with a dog he picked up. - Photo by Andrea Cashiola

When it comes time for Fort Bend families to get a pet, they will likely take 
a trip to the pet store or the Humane Society. What they may not know is that 
healthy, adoptable pets are being destroyed daily in their own cities and 
county. 
At the Missouri City animal shelter last year, out of 838 impounded animals, 
mostly dogs, only 35 were adopted. 641 animals were euthanized, and only 32 of 
these were bite cases.
Juan Acevedo, the city's animal control supervisor, says the shelter has 
eight kennels, and can hold up to 20 dogs, depending on size and breed. 
Unfortunately, he says, the difference between a city facility and a non profit shelter 
like the Humane Society is the amount of time that animals can be held. 
Acevedo says that they can only hold the animal from three to five days. "We 
do hold on to adoptable animals as long as we can, and we do our best to find 
them homes," he says, but there is a capacity issue. "We've held dogs up to 
two weeks, as long as we have room," he says.
Acevedo, who has worked for the city for 11 years and previously worked for 
the Humane Society, says that when he gets in an animal that is adoptable, he 
tries his best to find it a home. "When a cute dog comes in, I let everyone 
know about it. Almost everyone who works for the city has adopted."
But, he says, there is only so much the three animal control officers can do. 
"Healthy, adoptable pets are euthanized daily," he says.
Also, the Missouri City animal control office is covered with flyers for lost 
or missing pets. So, if they pick up somebody's animal, they will be able to 
easily contact them.
One explanation for the small number of adoptions may be the shelter's lack 
of visibility. It is located behind the Missouri City City Hall and library at 
what is currently a dead end. So, many residents just don't know about the 
shelter. 
"I have neighbors who have no idea there is a shelter in Missouri City," says 
resident Cynde Chaney. "If people knew about it, maybe there would be more 
adoptions."</content>

</doc>
