<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 16:39:23 2003</date>
  <content>
1) Current Concepts - Chronic Constipation in the October 2, 2003 issue of the New England Journal of Medicine places no emphasis on a low-fiber diet nor says anything about dairy products as the cause of constipation. As far as dietary treatment is concerned, the article contains a single sentence suggesting an increase in fruits and vegetables.  This nine page article dedicates two pages to drug therapy and the rest to verbiage irrelevant to your practicing doctor's care for his patients.  When something as obvious as the connection between the food that enters your body and the "digested food" that leaves your body is neglected by one of the world's most respected medical journals, you can understand why your doctors rarely mention diet in connection with your problems, but prescribe bags full of drugs, and as a result, almost never solve your health problems.  For more information on curing constipation see my September 2002 Newsletter article - In Search of the Perfect Bowel Movement. 

Lembo A. Chronic constipation. N Engl J Med. 2003 Oct 2;349(14):1360-8.

2) Lifetime Risk for Diabetes Mellitus in the United States in the October 8, 2003 issue of the Journal of the American Medical Association reports that for individuals born in the year 2000, 33% of males and 39% of females will develop diabetes.  The risk for minorities is even higher with an estimate of half of Hispanic females developing diabetes.  Most of these diabetics will go on to have kidney and/or heart disease.  Who is going to pay for all of this?  Disease from unhealthy eating is the greatest threat facing the future of developed countries.  The solution is simple:  type 2 diabetes is due to rich food, lack of exercise, and the resulting obesity - change the obvious.

Narayan K. Lifetime risk for diabetes mellitus in the United States. JAMA. 2003 Oct 8;290(14):1884-90.

</content>

</doc>
