<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Jan  1 08:00:30 2004</date>
  <content>
When word flashed to the National Cattlemen's Beef Association last week that the first case of mad cow disease in the United States had been found on the West Coast, it was a red alert for an industry that had spent years playing down the threat. 

The association and its allies have spent millions in recent years to deploy lobbyists defending its interests on meat regulations, inheritance taxes and other issues. So when a crisis surfaced that struck directly at beef sales, it had a plan.

Washington lobbyists began tracking down members of Congress, who were home for the holidays, and discussing the response with officials at the Agriculture Department. Teams of experts in all 50 states were made available to the news media to get out the group's message. And the association posted a Web page, created years ago but held in reserve, to educate the public. 

"We were trying to get to the American consumer, where all our money comes from," said Chandler Keys, the association's vice president for government affairs.

The initial response was the first line of defense for an industry facing the largest test of its clout in years. It then embraced regulations imposed by the Agriculture Department on Tuesday, including an about-face on a provision the industry had long opposed and had defeated in the House earlier this year.

"Their barn is burning down," said Howard Lyman, a former rancher and lobbyist for the National Farm Union who is now an advocate for tighter regulations and a critic of the industry. "They are trying to put the best face on it."

--------------------------------  skip ------------------------------------. 

Critics of the industry say it was backed into a corner. 

"They are on the run now," said Marion Nestle, who will step down as chairman of the Department of Nutrition, Food Studies and Public Health at New York University in 2004 after 15 years. "Countries all over the world are saying they will not buy their meat. That's serious."

The association, which is more than 100 years old, represents most American cattle producers, as well as others associated with the beef industry, including restaurants and grocers. It has a long history of opposition to what it calls excessive government regulation.

"One of our philosophies is minimal government involvement and letting the industry address these things," Terry Stokes, the association's chief executive, said. "More regulation increases costs and makes it difficult for small- and medium-size producers to comply."

The association contends that the system in place to detect and guard against mad cow disease is effective, that this week's new regulations were an added precaution, and that anything new should be weighed critically. Officials often say any changes should be backed by science, though the industry and its critics often draw different conclusions from the available research. 

"We want to make sure that anything we do has a practical and real effect," Mr. Keys said. "We don't want to do things that are window dressing and political posturing. When you succumb to that kind of thing, it always bites you."

Whether it can maintain that stance amid the threat of Congressional hearings, legislation and other forms of oversight remains to be seen. Like many heavily regulated sectors, the cattle industry has strong ties to government, particularly to Republicans.

Cattle and livestock interests have given almost $22 million to political campaigns since the 1990 elections, with three-quarters going to Republicans, according to the Center for Responsive Politics, which tracks campaign finance. 

Many say the relationship improved with the election of President Bush, who is the former governor of Texas, the top cattle-producing state, and owns a ranch there. Mr. Bush was the top recipient of campaign money from the industry in his 2000 election and again this year, as well as from allies like the dairy and meat processing industries.

"I love those cattlemen!" Mr. Bush said when he met the association's president, Eric Davis, at a White House Christmas party, the association's newsletter says. Its Web site has a picture of the president at an industry conference.

Mr. Keys said the association itself traditionally steers clear of the risk involved in presidential contributions, lest it back the wrong candidate. But he says his organization is firm in its support for Mr. Bush and the Republican Party.

Critics of the industry, as well as those who have opposed it on issues, say it has been ruthlessly effective at knocking down or weakening regulation over the years. "They are able to exert a lot of pressure," Ms. Nestle said. "They are a very important American industry." 

Consumer organizations and animal rights groups that have supported proposals before the Agriculture Department and other agencies say they find themselves out-numbered by industry opponents. In Congress, lawmakers who have proposed legislation to regulate the industry say they felt the full weight of the industry's support.

So it was for Representative Gary L. Ackerman, Democrat of New York, who lost a battle to pass a measure to eliminate cattle that cannot walk from the food supply, the very measure the Agriculture Department implemented this week with the industry's blessing.

</content>

</doc>
