<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Mar 17 21:28:04 2004</date>
  <content>
It?s sometimes hard to recall that Berkeley was once just another American
town, whose citizens cooked, served, and ate what Americans everywhere did.
...
Rich developed her love for vegetarian cooking while attending Stanford.
"I made a lot of vegan things for the people in my co-op," she says, "but
tried to be creative 
 to make something more than ?co-op slop,? where you
throw stuff into a big wok and stir it around." She became interested in
raw food through her reading in "health philosophy," although over time
political, social, and ethical issues have become interwoven with her
purely health-oriented concerns. She honed her skills in food preparation
and presentation while operating an East Bay catering company, Artemisia
Foods, before taking the chef?s job at Caf? Muse this past winter. It?s
her first-ever restaurant gig.

Caf? Muse now features half a dozen raw dishes on its menu daily, along
with a variety of more conventionally prepared sandwiches, soups, and
salads. Hence, if you?re seeking a change from your standard deli sandwich
? even though in this "deli" you?d be lunching on organically raised
chicken, Niman Ranch pastrami, and dolphin-safe tuna salad ? you can
experiment with a pad Thai whose "noodles" are peeled from the flesh of
young coconuts, served with a Thai-style sauce made from pure?d Fresno
chiles, medjool dates, Celtic sea salt, garlic, and rice vinegar.

None of the ingredients in this or the other raw dishes are cooked above
110 degrees Fahrenheit ? which means, essentially, that they?re not cooked
at all. Foodies are familiar with this approach because of the success
achieved by Roxanne Klein in her eponymous (and profoundly upscale) Marin
County restaurant, Roxanne?s. And healthy-eating advocates have pursued
raw-food regimens of one kind or another for years, though most have
failed to reach a broader audience. 
...
The Berkeley dining revolution of 1971 has consolidated its gains around
the nation. Will Caf? Muse warrant a full chapter in Sarah Rich?s memoirs
30 years hence? Or will "raw food" be remembered as a passing craze, the
way foodies now look back on "fusion" and pink peppercorns? If commitment,
dedication, and deliciousness are the criteria for lasting success,
failure may find Caf? Muse, Adagia, and their nascent ilk a hard (and
decidedly raw) nut to Swallow.</content>

</doc>
