<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar  4 17:11:37 2004</date>
  <content>
Capping a six-year effort to correct a series of deficiencies identified in 
1998 by a professional accreditation committee, the Wisconsin Veterinary 
Diagnostic Laboratory (WVDL) has regained its full accreditation status, according 
to the chair of the board that oversees the lab. 
B.J. Cadman, chair of the Wisconsin Veterinary Diagnostic Laboratory board 
and a practicing veterinarian in Ridgeland, Wis., says the lab was informed of 
its reaccreditation last week by the American Association of Veterinary 
Laboratory Diagnosticians. The reaccreditation, Cadman says, is essential to ensuring 
that Wisconsin's agricultural community and food producers have direct access 
to the best animal health diagnostic services available. 
"This is a pretty significant step, and is something our board has been 
working on for a long time," Cadman says. 
The lab is a key part of the state's animal health infrastructure. It 
provides testing and diagnostic services for all types of animals, especially farm 
animals. In recent years, it has assumed a very visible role in the state's 
battle against chronic wasting disease, testing more than 35,000 animals for the 
disease last year alone. In the wake of the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks on the 
United States and the subsequent anthrax attacks, it has also assumed new 
responsibilities in the effort to thwart bioterrorism. 
The lab, which for many years was a part of the state Department of 
Agriculture, Trade and Consumer Protection - and was known as the Wisconsin Animal 
Health Laboratory - had been under funded and understaffed, and lacked effective 
leadership, according to a history of the lab. 
In 1998, when the lab's accreditation was reduced to "provisional" status, it 
"brought to a head some of the budgetary and administrative challenges which 
our laboratory had dealt with for the past 15 to 20 years," Cadman says. </content>

</doc>
