<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Dec  5 17:12:32 2003</date>
  <content>

When Jeffrey ?Free? Luers and Craig ?Critter? Marshall torched three SUVs
at Romania Chevrolet in Eugene, Oregon, in June 2000, they set in motion a
new era of monkey-wrenching.

While Luers awaited trial, 36 more SUVs burned at the same dealership.
Luers? 22-year prison sentence is a reflection of a society that values
corporate free enterprise, consumerism and property above the environment.

The communiqu? following the second Romania fire announced:

?Gas-guzzling SUVs are at the forefront of this imperialistic culture?s
caravan toward self-destruction. We can no longer allow the rich to parade
around in their armored existence, leaving a wasteland behind in their
tire tracks. We must strike out against what destroys us before we all
choke on smog.?

As many urban drivers replace passenger cars with SUVs, carbon dioxide
levels in the air have increased three-fold. The Surface Transportation
Policy Project (STPP) in August reported that two million tons, or 57
percent of all air pollutants in Los Angeles, California, come from
tailpipe emissions. Whether an oil tanker spill in Karachi or the proposed
oil exploration in the caribou breeding grounds of the Arctic National
Wildlife Refuge, America?s consumption of 25 percent of the world?s oil is
killing the environment and people alike.

While SUVs have become a legitimate anti-pollution target, does torching
them make a difference?

Since the Earth Liberation Front (ELF) began attacking SUVs, General
Motors has alerted its dealers to beware of the eco-sabotuers. Kroll,
Inc., a ?global threat management? company, has been advising SUV dealers
in security strategies and has recommended that they establish contact
with FBI terrorist specialists to share information. All American
Pontiac-Buick-GMC in Houston, Texas, hired 24-hour security and installed
a $100,000 video surveillance system in response to an incident on
September 3, when eco-vandals damaged two-thirds of the SUV inventory. The
president of the dealership commented, ?It?s definitely going to impact
our bottom line.? Unwilling to accept any responsibility for the nation?s
growing levels of auto-emission pollution, automakers and dealers are
instead practicing a siege mentality by offering up to $100,000 rewards
for ELF members. </content>

</doc>
