<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat May 31 18:01:42 2003</date>
  <content>

 Terrorism bill--A. 4884 (Smith)/S. 2996 (Kuhl)
 
 
 I happen to see former Assemblyman Marty Luster in
 the video store today. He 
 said he had appeared on a local talk radio program
 recently to talk against 
 A. 4884/S 2996. He said he thought that Kuhl would
 "take his cue from the 
 Asembly" and would wait until the bill had been
 passed in the Assembly to 
 unstar it in the Senate. He said he talked to Magee
 (chair of the Assembly 
 Agriculture Committe) and that Magee said he
 intended to bring the bill for 
 a vote in committee.  He also said he thought people
 ought to write to Smith 
 and ask him to withdraw the bill. I told him that I
 was mad at the NYCLU 
 because they had not responded to my letter or my
 phone calls, asking them 
 to come out against this bill. (Luster had been a
 lawyer for the ACLU years 
 ago.) He said he would call the NYCLU and try to
 talk to them. I asked him 
 if my interpretation (of the bill) that a person
 photographing their 
 neighbor treating a pet cruelly would make the
 photographer a felon was 
 correct and he agreed. (For the cruel neighbor, on
 the other hand, it's only 
 a misdemeanor.)
 
 Here's what I'd like people to do:
 
 1. Write to Smith and ask him to withdraw the bill.
 Send a copy of your 
 letter to Kuhl.
 
 Assemblyman Richard Smith
 619 LOB
 Albany, NY 12248
 Fax: 518-455-5560
 
 Senator Randy Kuhl
 310 LOB
 Albany, NY 12247
 Fax: 518-426-6976
 
 2. Send a letter to your assemblymember, opposing
 the bill, with a copy to 
 Magee. If you're really into this, sending a copy of
 your letter to all 
 members of the Assembly Ag. Committee would be even
 better. You can get 
 their names and addresses by going to
 http://www.assembly.state.ny.us
 
 Assemblyman William Magee
 641 LOB
 Albany, NY 12248
 Fax: 518-455-5237
 
 Remember, committee chair only bring bills before
 their committees that they 
 think will pass. It's rare that a bill doesn't pass
 out of committee. If 
 Magee is planning to bring this bill before his
 committee, it's because he 
 thinks it will pass.
 
 If you have any questions, feel free to e-mail me.
 


</content>

</doc>
