<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb 25 10:59:54 2004</date>
  <content>


The story goes like this: In early fall, a staff member noticed Marv hanging 
around the parking lot. Feeling sorry for him, she began to feed him. Pretty 
soon Marv managed to beg up to three cans of cat food a day. But as the weather 
grew cold, we worried about his safety. 

     So with a safe trap and a can of tuna fish in hand we set out to catch 
Marv. But what I didn't write about were the problems generated by another 
neighborhood cat. 

     From the posters that hang on every telephone pole in Marlborough's 
French Hill neighborhood, we now know that cat was Boris -- a beautiful 
long-haired silver and gray cat. 

     Back in November, Boris became a problem because instead of Marv, he 
wandered into the safe trap to eat the tuna fish. To keep him from the trap, we 
brought him into the office away from the food. Boris was friendly and clearly 
well-cared for. Believing he just got out by mistake, once Marv was caught, we 
let him go. Now we know that was a mistake. 

     But before I get too far into Boris' story, be assured that Marv is well 
and awaiting adoption at the Milford Animal Shelter. He's a little more 
social now and is slowly getting used to both cats and humans. 

     But, back to Boris. Presto Rubel, a former Winthrop Street resident who 
has since moved out of town, said she posted the notices after learning that 
Boris' owner, Bob Harter, had died. Harter, who owned the Winthrop Street home 
where Rubel and her husband lived, owned five cats, but Boris, she said, "was 
clearly his favorite." 

     Rubel describes Harter as "a well-traveled person, with a delightful 
sense of humor." And, she said, "he loved cats." 

     But unknown to Rubel, Harter died Oct. 15 of a massive heart attack and 
his beloved cats were cared for by a tenant. Rubel said she learned only two 
weeks ago of Harter's death when the tenant called to say she was moving and 
needed someone to care for the other cats. 

     It was then Rubel learned that Boris has been missing for two months. </content>

</doc>
