<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Feb 28 13:19:57 2004</date>
  <content>

WILD ABOUT ANIMALS E/I (13 -16) 
PROGRAM DESCRIPTION: This series is produced for children 16 and under 
(specific target audience is 13-16). The objective of the program is to educate and 
inform children by bringing them the most entertaining and interesting stories 
about the world's most fascinating animals. Each episode consists of at least 
four stories designed to teach children about exotic and unique animals from 
the wild, as well as educate them further about animals they see everyday 

Saturday, 02/28/04, 4:30-5PM (episode #26-03/04)
On this episode of "Wild About Animals," we go whale watching. We'll take you 
up close for a look at a 60,000 pound animal known as the humpback whale. The 
next story is about a talent agent with a purely canine clientele. Then, 
we'll travel to a town where spotting wild fox around town has become a common 
occurrence. And we'll hit the links to pay a visit with Hank, the llama, who just 
loves the game of golf.

Sunday, 02/29/04, 4:30-5PM (episode #25-03/04)
From black leopards to white tigers, you'll learn about the greatest land 
predators on earth on this episode. Next, we'll travel to the Southampton 
Princess hotel in Bermuda where we'll take part in a once in a lifetime dolphin 
experience. You'll learn why a zookeeper at the San Diego Zoo had to take over the 
motherly duties for a few fennec fox pups. And you'll learn all about 
different animals and more as we visit one of the most exotic petting zoo's you'll 
ever see.

Saturday, 03/06, 4:30-5PM (episode #27-03/04)
On this episode of "Wild About Animals," we'll meet a search dog that really 
has a nose for trouble. Then it's off to a wildlife park where untrained 
animals can be seen playing with people. Some people call them bison, some call 
them buffalo, we'll learn all about one creature that has often been 
misunderstood. And we'll go to a school where no one cares about reading, writing and 
arithmetic. That's because this is a school for dogs! 


WILD ABOUT ANIMALS E/I (13 -16) (CONT.)

Sunday, 03/07, 4:30-5PM (episode #26-03/04)
On this episode of "Wild About Animals," we go whale watching. We'll take you 
up close for a look at a 60,000 pound animal known as the humpback whale. The 
next story is about a talent agent with a purely canine clientele. Then, 
we'll travel to a town where spotting wild fox around town has become a common 
occurrence. And we'll hit the links to pay a visit with Hank, the llama, who just 
loves the game of golf.

Sunday, 03/14, 4:30-5PM (episode #27-03/04)
On this episode of "Wild About Animals," we'll meet a search dog that really 
has a nose for trouble. Then it's off to a wildlife park where untrained 
animals can be seen playing with people. Some people call them bison, some call 
them buffalo, we'll learn all about one creature that has often been 
misunderstood. And we'll go to a school where no one cares about reading, writing and 
arithmetic. That's because this is a school for dogs! </content>

</doc>
