<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Jun  3 14:37:37 2004</date>
  <content>-



Federal agents monitored activities from the parking lot while local
undercover officers loitered among the activists inside the campus
buildings. Vivisection laboratories readied themselves against incursions
as hardcore bands rehearsed for a benefit concert. One activist was
arrested shortly after delivering a stirring speech. The others --
possible "domestic terrorists" one and all -- were photographed entering
and leaving the event. Two other conference participants were arrested in
subsequent weeks.

The occasion for these dramatic happenings was not a building takeover,
banner drop, Black Bloc maneuver, or act of eco-sabotage. Federal, state,
and private security forces converged to police not actions but ideas at
the Student Animal Rights Organization (SARO) conference on animal
liberation, which included the first ever academic symposium on the
Animal Liberation Front (ALF).
...
Activists who undertake open or covert, legal or illegal investigations
or rescues often must struggle with the emotional consequences of
witnessing extreme suffering and may be haunted by the animals they were
unable to save. But, for those animals who are saved, open rescue
literally means everything. Conference participants were also able to
witness that aspect of open rescue, by means of a very different
videotape -- an Animal Planet episode that featured the rehabilitation
and release to a sanctuary of former foie gras factory inmates.

Time and again videotaped evidence collected by covert methods has been
the decisive factor in campaigns against cruelty to animals. Giving the
history of the SHAC (Stop Huntington Animal Cruelty) campaign, which has
eaten deeply into the profits of one of the worst vivisection operations
in the world and which seems likely to succeed in forcing the company out
of business, Kevin Jonas cited three key instances in which women went
undercover with hidden cameras and succeeded in bringing out footage of
extreme neglect and mistreatment. Those films have been used to motivate
activists, sway public opinion, and embarrass the company's customers
into cutting their ties with Huntington.



----------
</content>

</doc>
