<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Feb 27 13:24:36 2004</date>
  <content>

The Luis A. Ferre Science Park in Bayamon is a zoo, a space museum, and a 
great place to have a family picnic. If you are looking for a place where your 
kids can roam around, have some fun and even learn something along the way, this 
is the place to visit.
The science park is located on a rock hill on Road 167, off toll Highway 22.
From its perch, the museum offers a sprawling view of the city in all its 
urban chaos. But landscape appreciation of urban disarray is a thing for adults 
to enjoy, for kids there are plenty of rockets and monkeys!
Upon entering the park, most visitors work their way through the zoo and end 
their visit at the top of the hill alongside the genuine NASA rockets on 
display. But first things first, let's talk about the animals.
The Science Park has a good zoo collection that includes tigers, baboons and 
one very slow hippopotamus. The zoo grounds have winding paths that go past 
the animal cages and a small pond where geese and other type of awkward bird 
species lounge around while visitors have their lunch in gazebos around the 
water's edge. If you don't want to bring your own food, there is a food kiosk by 
the pond. Adults should not get very excited about this, the eating choices here 
are definitely geared to a younger age group. The menu includes such choice 
items as quick-bake pizza, hot dogs and pop-corn. Three standards of children's 
cuisine.
Zoos can be double edged swords since their maintenance has a huge effect on 
their young visitors. For most children, a well-kept zoo brings to reality an 
exotic animal world only previously available in the Discovery Channel.
On the other hand, an poorly maintained collection of animals in captivity 
wandering aimlessly inside their cages in lonely circles of desolation could 
hurl your young child into a vortex of pre-pubescent doom.
Although many of the animals appear to be sort of blue, they are well taken 
care of. As one caretaker explained, some animals are not sad, just indifferent.
The tigers are naturals at this indifference technique. But as any cat owner 
knows, felines spend more than 60 percent of their lives sleeping and 
wallowing in indifference, so while the tigers aren't very entertaining, their apathy 
is actually a good sign, they are normal!.</content>

</doc>
