<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 20 21:03:59 2003</date>
  <content>
In Seattle, a federal animal-research official suggests that the day might
come when experimentation on chimpanzees is ended. 
...
You are excused for thinking that Seattle was on the verge of another WTO
meltdown last week. Local media went out of their way to portray
animal-rights advocates as extremists who would use violence to disrupt a
conference of the American Association of Laboratory Animal Science
(AALAS) at the Washington Convention and Trade Center. Not only did
nothing happen, reporters missed a tectonic shift in the never-ending
conflict between researchers and activists over the use of animals in
biomedical research.

It's a debate that's always framed in absolutes. Researchers insist that
animal research is the crucial test bed for advancing human health.
Animal-rights advocates shout that such research is not applicable to
humankind and smacks of slavery, and worse. No wonder, then, that the
shouting on both sides of the argument stopped when a senior National
Institutes of Health official said that one day there might be a ban on
the use of chimpanzees in research in the U.S. 
...
THE BAN, if enacted, would be the first time the federal government
stopped the use of any species in biomedical research, according to
officials at the U.S. Department of Agriculture, which regulates the use
of animals in research, and the U.S. Fish &amp; Wildlife Service, which
regulates endangered species and research on wildlife. "This is definitely
a first, and it is significant in that respect," says Peter Singer, a
bioethicist at Princeton University and author of Animal Liberation, a
book credited by many as launching the modern animal-rights movement in
the U.S. "I think what it signals is that there are changes of the sort
that people in the animal-rights movement have been talking about for 30
years," Singer says. "It's not going to be an all or nothing thing. It's a
matter of making steady progress in changing peoples views."

Animal-rights advocates contacted by Seattle Weekly say they have never
heard such talk out of NIH?that the government would actually consider
banning the use of any animal in research.

Researchers were less willing to talk about the issue. Suzette Tardif,
associate director of the Southwest National Primate Research Center in
San Antonio, Texas, declined to comment on Strandberg's statement itself.
Her center uses chimpanzees in research. Asked what effect a ban would
have, Tardif said that chimps are the only species, aside from humans,
that contracts Hepatitis C, the leading reason for liver transplants in
the U.S. 

</content>

</doc>
