<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Jun 26 09:45:30 2004</date>
  <content>


Sacramento -- Strange things happen when stray animals fall into the
churning wheels of a state struggling to save a few bucks here and
there.

Dogs begin showing up at the Capitol. The seldom-seen wrath of the
California Potbellied Pig Association is aroused. And by the end of the
day, the state's most powerful man pauses, pivots and restores calm to
the land.

An overlooked cash-saving component of Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger's
proposed 2004-05 budget would have shortened the length of time dogs and
cats are kept alive at shelters. It also would have allowed the shelters
to destroy immediately what the state apparently feels are lesser pets:
hamsters, rabbits, turtles and even potbellied pigs.

Horrified animal-rights activists caught wind of the plan and mobilized
this week.

"I realized last night," Schwarzenegger said at a hastily called news
conference outside his office Friday, "that there was a mistake I made." 
...
"I'm writing a letter right now," said Jim Christensen, who with his
wife, Marcie, works to rescue abandoned pet pigs from Bay Area shelters.
The animals became popular in the early 1990s; the Christensens have two
of them.

"Animals are always secondary," Marcie sighed, reflecting on the state
budget. Schwarzenegger, she felt, was "looking to make a quick buck."

She envisioned a harsher life in this new, belt-tightened California.

"I know of some shelters right now that, if they are allowed to kill it
when it comes in, they probably will," she said. "The pool guy comes and
leaves the gate open, and the pig gets out. What if their bunny gets
out? What if their bird gets out?"

On it went. Animal shelters, too, tried to figure out what to do if the
Hayden Act came crashing down.

Sheri Cardo, public relations director of the Marin Humane Society,
thought shelters would try to continue to operate under its provisions,
even after a repeal. She noted that the Bay Area had long been a leader
in promoting "no-kill" policies for stray and relinquished animals. 



</content>

</doc>
