<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 10:20:22 2003</date>
  <content>
This Thanksgiving, will you serve turkey or tofurkey? A few years ago, you 
might not even have thought twice. But vegetarianism is on the rise and any 
number of thoughtful articles on animal cruelty, vegetarianism, and factory 
farming are making even dedicated meat-eaters think again about where and how their 
food is raised. To avoid fouling up your choice, whether bird, or un-bird, 
consider these tips and advice: 

* Organic may not be enough. Organic is increasingly big business, and many 
large organic farms resemble industrial farms in significant ways, 
manufacturing standardized product, in large quantities, built to ship over long 
distances. 
* Local can be better than organic. Many small farms are essentially organic, 
but don't always get certified and so therefore can't label themselves as 
such. Many also prize artisanal values over labels. Buying locally from such a 
farm, or from a greenmarket or specialty food store you trust, is often the best 
choice: It supports a small-scale agriculture, encourages biodiversity over 
standardization, and cuts down on the fossil fuels used in shipping across the 
country. 
* Cruelty-free is key. The world is rife with reports like PETA's on a 
Minnesota turkey farm: the farm manager was caught on tape bludgeoning birds with a 
stick and pliers and wringing their necks. More often, but hardly less 
cruelly, turkeys are kept in horribly cramped conditions: 10,000 birds in a 
windowless shed with less than three square feet per bird, the air filled with ammonia 
and responsible for many respiratory diseases, the waste-filled ground leading 
to foot ulcerations, the birds debeaked so they don't peck one another to 
death. Labels like "free range" and "free roaming," minimally verified by the 
USDA, assure little besides some access to open air. Birds are scientifically 
bred for breast meat; this practice has grown so advanced that such turkeys have 
trouble standing upright, develop lame and infected legs and hips, are not 
genetically diverse and are thus vulnerable to disease, and can only reproduce 
via artificial insemination. They can't fly and can barely walk. They're pumped 
full of antibiotics and fed not nuts, grains, and grass but high protein food, 
including slaughterhouse leftovers. Then they are stuffed into crates, taken 
to the slaughterhouse, and electrically stunned, often ineffectively. They die 
when their throats are cut, often after reviving from their electric stun. 
This is the center piece you buy for a few cents a pound. 

When picking a turkey... 

If you are leaning toward servin turkey, and you have the opportunity, visit 
or call some of the small suppliers, and confirm, either visually or by asking 
questions, that the farming and growing methods used are those you approve 
of. Make sure that no pesticides are used on plants and that healthy, 
non-engineered animals are raised according to their nature, rather than in an 
industrial manner, and are slaughtered humanely. Since most of us won't be able to get 
out to the farm, we suggest you: 

</content>

</doc>
