<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 22 15:38:37 2003</date>
  <content>
The African wild dog is one of the world's rarest carnivores, extinct in most of its former range. Despite recent efforts to conserve it, most of the deaths, even inside parks, are still caused by people, says Rosie Woodroffe, an expert on the species. The dogs now number somewhere between 3000 and 5500 and are declining almost everywhere.

The one bright spot is Laikipia in Kenya, where Woodroffe heads the Samburu-Laikipia Wild Dog Project. Wild dogs were eradicated in the district 20 years ago. In December 1998, Woodroffe heard reports of wild dogs moving in from Samburu to the north-east. By 2000, some dogs had settled in Laikipia and made dens. Now there are at least eight packs and more than 100 dogs. "This is amazing. In 1997 there were only six populations of this size known in the whole of Africa, mostly in southern Africa," she says. "These northern dogs are genetically distinct, which makes them a very important population."

Wild dogs are a big draw to tourists. At Laikipia they have mostly colonised communal land where the other top attraction, the lion, has been wiped out. The local Masai people recognise the wild dog's potential to lure tourists away from commercial ranches and spend some time at community-owned lodges. Even so, not everyone is pleased to see wild dogs return. Although they rarely attack cattle or animals kept in bomas they will go for sheep or goats left unattended or guarded by children, and individual herders can suffer big losses, says Woodroffe. "Several dogs have been shot, one speared, one I'm not sure about - and four killed on the road," she says.

At the moment, the best way to protect the wild dogs is by an early-warning system. Many of the dogs wear radio collars and are tracked by aircraft, so Woodroffe and her team know exactly where the packs are. If there's a risk of an attack on livestock, the team radioes the local community liaison officer, who jumps on his motorbike and sets off to warn those in the dogs' path.

</content>

</doc>
