<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Nov 28 21:51:42 2003</date>
  <content>
Before the Swedes banned the use of steel-jaw leghold traps, they held a 
fox-trapping campaign. Some of the foxes knocked out as many as 18 teeth as they 
frantically lashed out trying to escape. A few gnawed off their own legs to 
break free. Of the 645 trapped foxes, 514 were seriously injured. 
The fur trim on the hood of your parka could be the bloody corpse of a 
trapped fox. Or it could be faux fur. Which would you rather wear next to your face? 
Friday was "Fur Free Friday," since 1986 a day of protest against 
slaughtering animals for their fur. A Voice for Animals, a San Antonio advocacy group, 
staged a protest on Broadway. 
Here in South-Central Texas, fur is absurd. It's not as if some local Dr. 
Zhivago has to bundle his Lara in a mound of mink blankets for the trek across 
the snow drifts to Seguin. This isn't Chicago, let alone the steppes of Russia. 
But all of us, even if we live in the sunny South, should care about the 
inhumane way animals are raised, trapped and killed for their fur. 
Before I return to leghold traps, let's visit a fur ranch. Yes, they call 
them ranches! Disabuse yourself of any romantic notions of longhorn mink at home 
on the range, herded by little minkboys tossing tiny lariats. 
The male mink is a traveling man, with a range of about 25 miles, taking 
about a week to make a circuit of his turf. They are semi-aquatic mammals who hang 
out around lakes, creeks and marshes. A male grows to be 20 to 30 inches 
long. 
In a fur ranch, the mink will be kept in a cage, typically 10 inches wide by 
24 inches long. No wiggle room. No water to frolic in, no well-worn paths to 
cruise. Many experience psychological trauma with symptoms such as ulcers and 
cannibalism. 
When it's time for the kill, most mink are murdered by poison gas, lethal 
injection or breaking their little necks. They fare better than farmed foxes, 
which are most commonly killed by anal electrocution. 
To kill a chinchilla, ranchers hook one metal clamp to the ear and another to 
the genitalia, then zap electricity through the circuit. Chinchillas are 
small. A hundred of them are slaughtered to make a full-length fur coat. 
And people want to wear that next to their own skin? Ugh!</content>

</doc>
