<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr 26 10:33:45 2004</date>
  <content>
For Immediate Release

FUND FOR ANIMALS SAYS STATE IS DIRECTLY RESPONSIBLE FOR DEATH OF 13 
YEAR OLD HUNTER

AUSTIN, TX (April 26, 2004)  The Fund for Animals, a national animal 
protection organization which operates Black Beauty Ranch, a 
world-famous 1600 acre sanctuary in Murchison, Texas, has called on 
Governor Rick Perry to establish a minimum hunting age of sixteen. The 
call comes in response to the death of 13 year old Michael Lynn Russell 
who was shot and killed on April 19 while hunting with his 11 year old 
cousin on the Lone Star Hereford Ranch in Clay County. Texas has no 
minimum hunting age, and does not require hunter safety classes for 
children under 17.

In a letter to Governor Perry, program coordinator Norm Phelps called 
that policy so irresponsible that the Government of the State of Texas 
is directly responsible for the death of Michael Russell, since such 
tragedies are an entirely foreseeable result of DPW policy. Young 
children lack the patience, emotional control, and mature judgement to 
operate a firearm safely or take prudent precautions to assure their own 
safety in a hunting situation where close oversight by an adult is often 
impossible. The presence of his adult uncle did not protect Michael. 
Children are by nature excitable, impatient, and impulsive; that is part 
of being a child. In the excitement of a hunt, children  even the most 
responsible of them  cannot be counted on to exercise the caution and 
restraint that are the essential ingredients of hunting safety.

According to Fund for Animals president Michael Markarian, Nationwide, 
the hunting industry is trying to increase their revenues by recruiting 
children. But the state of Texas needs to just say no to corporate and 
bureaucratic greed that puts children at risk. Our childrens lives are 
more important than the sale of hunting licenses. If Texas had a minimum 
hunting age of sixteen, Michael Lynn Russell would be alive today.

</content>

</doc>
