<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 10:13:41 2003</date>
  <content>
Her impending divorce and its aftermath not only left Boulder school 
psychologist Lea White stressed and anxious, but it was making her cat, Winston, nuts.
The 8-year-old cat began acting out this spring in ways he'd never done. What 
he did is politely known as inappropriate elimination, and cat owners 
everywhere know what that means.
On the dog's bed. On the bathroom rug. On the carpet. Once he even went on 
White's foot! Even worse, White was attempting to sell the house, and she feared 
that Winston's frequent anointings would deter potential buyers.
Her other cat didn't behave this way. But Winston is a sensitive soul, 
extremely bonded to his owner. "My stress turned into my cat's stress," said White, 
50.
Her veterinarian prescribed Valium to calm Winston down. "I thought if I 
vegged him out enough he'd forget he was mad," White said. "But it was not 
working. Either I gave him so much he was like a vegetable, or I didn't give him 
enough to make a difference."
Something had to be done. And it's precisely at this point - when a pet's 
misdeeds become intolerable - that many cat owners throw in the towel and throw 
out the cat.
"If a dog has behavior problems, you call a trainer. But if cats develop 
behavior problems, most people think you can't do anything about it. Cats have 
always been considered untrainable," says Dr. Jean Hofve, a Denver veterinarian 
who specializes in treating felines. "So people just live with it until finally 
the cat is out on his ear or winds up in the shelter."
But Hofve and her business partner, animal behaviorist Jackson Galaxy, 
believe something can be done if pet owners will start thinking like cats.
Hofve and Galaxy recently launched Little Big Cat, a cat-behavior consulting 
practice. They look at both the physical and the emotional explanations for a 
cat's behavior and suggest holistic treatments that take those factors into 
account.
In Winston's case, that meant taking some very practical steps, like moving 
his litter boxes around and putting his food bowl in the places where he was 
spraying, and some less obvious ones, like getting him a toy he can chase and 
pounce on.
</content>

</doc>
