<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 26 07:57:39 2004</date>
  <content>
The business of social change is often a complex undertaking. There are many tactical approaches that can be used to pursue similar goals. These axioms are in evidence in a flap that's developed between The HSUS and People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) in our separate dealings with The Iams Company?the pet food company that is co-sponsoring Pet Fest America in six cities across the United States. 
PETA believes The HSUS should not co-sponsor an event with Iams because a PETA investigation turned up troubling information about the treatment of dogs at a contract research facility doing work for Iams. The story broke on March 25, 2003, with the posting of graphic images, including images of cats who were not included in the Iams-sponsored study. The HSUS, of course, strongly agrees that no animals should be subjected to de-barking, invasive surgery, forced feeding, or lack of socialization simply for nutrition studies. 

The HSUS looked into the matter, after PETA brought the issues to light, and asked Iams what corrective actions it would take. Iams was already in the process of investigating the circumstances; almost immediately, it terminated the project at the laboratory where PETA's investigation occurred. The company removed its 19 dogs back to its own facility and then adopted them out to employees. Iams conducted inspections of all remaining study sites, terminating a number of studies, and reasserted the importance of the company's humane care policies at the remainder. 

The HSUS has neither endorsed the past actions of Iams, nor the company's current practices. We are, however, working with the company to see that any animals under its care are properly treated. What's more, we are demanding that the company move away from laboratory tests that might cause harm to the dogs and cats, and put their resources into clinical studies that result in no harm. 

In short, The HSUS has chosen a different tactical approach than PETA. We have chosen the course of discussion and co-operation rather than confrontation. We did not invent this approach. It is similar to one first developed by Henry Spira, an animal activist highly regarded for his successful tactics, and we believe it can work in many circumstances. 

</content>

</doc>
