<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Mar 16 13:58:04 2004</date>
  <content>
CONCORD, N.H. -- Even after five years, Christy Pugh has no trouble
sticking to her vegetarian regimen. The secret to her success? Eating meat.

Pugh is one of a growing number of part-time vegetarians whose loose
adherence to the meat-free diet is transforming a decades-old movement and
the industry that feeds it.

"Sometimes I feel like I'm a bad vegetarian, that I'm not strict enough or
good enough," the 28-year-old bookkeeper from Concord said recently. "I
really like vegetarian food but I'm just not 100 percent committed."

These so-called "flexitarians" - a term voted most useful word of 2003 by
the American Dialect Society - are motivated less by animal rights than by
a growing body of medical data that suggests health benefits from eating
more vegetarian foods.
...
In recent years the market for vegetarian friendly foods has exploded,
with items such as soy milk and veggie burgers showing up in mainstream
groceries and fast food restaurants.

But even the diet's activists say that growth can't be attributed to
committed vegetarians, who are estimated at about 3 percent of the adult
U.S. population, or about 5.7 million people never eating meat, poultry or
seafood.

Charles Stahler, co-director of the Baltimore-based Vegetarian Resource
Group, credits the growth to flexitarians - vegetarians who dabble in meat
and carnivores who seek out vegetarian meals.

"This is why Burger King has a veggie burger. It's not because of us," he
said. "The true vegetarians wouldn't rush to Burger King anyway. It's
because of those people in the middle. They are the driving audience."
...
"There is a big interest in vegetarianism," she said. "But we can also
tell from our readership that these are not people who are following a
pure vegetarian lifestyle. These are people who are integrating a
vegetarian menu in their current diets."

A similar change occurred at the 30-year-old Vegetarian Times, considered
the standardbearer of vegetarianism. Though still meat-free, the once
mostly vegan magazine focuses less on activism and more on recipes with
broader appeal.
...
Bruce Friedrich, spokesman for Norfolk, Va.-based People for the Ethical
Treatment of Animals, said he doesn't see any harm in vegetarianism
focusing more on food than the issues that spurred the movement.

"From our perspective, if people influenced by health consequently cut
back on fish and meat consumption, that helps animals," he said. "If two
people cut their meat in half it helps as much as one person going
completely vegetarian."</content>

</doc>
