<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb  4 15:14:40 2004</date>
  <content>
An unlikely coalition of anti-immigrant and animal-rights activists is
angling to elect several of its candidates to the Sierra Club's Board of
Directors. For the second time in less than a decade anti-immigration
advocates have been operating under the radar and waging a campaign to
take over the nation's oldest environmental organization.

The Club's 750,000 members will vote for five new members for its
15-person governing board in March and the first three weeks in April. If
the anti-immigration candidates prevail, the Los Angeles Times reported in
mid-January, they will control eight of the 15 seats and the Club's $95
million budget. The results will be made public sometime after April 21. 
...
Animal-rights supporters, which make up a smaller part of the alliance,
are looking for the Club to officially discourage hunting and fishing
despite the fact that nearly 20% of the membership engages in those
activities. They also want the Club to take a position against the
practice of raising animals for human consumption.
...
In a speech to the 2003 Animal Rights Conference in Los Angeles, Watson
explained his strategy: "I'm on the Sierra Club board of directors right
now ... to try and change it ... We're only three directors away from
controlling that board. We control one-third of it right now. And, once we
get three more directors elected ... we can use the resources of [its]
$95-million-a-year budget to address some of these issues. And the
heartening thing about it is that, in the last election, of the 750,000
members of the Sierra Club, only 8 percent of them voted. So, you know, a
few hundred, or a few thousand people from the animal rights movement
joining the Sierra Club ? and making it a point to vote ? will change the
entire agenda of that organization."

Two other SUSPS-supported candidates collected signatures on petitions and
are on the ballot. They are Kim McCoy, described by Groundswell Sierra as
a Club member and animal rights advocate from Chicago who is endorsed by
Watson, and Robert van de Hoek, a member from Los Angeles. 
</content>

</doc>
