<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep  1 17:44:33 2003</date>
  <content>

An American flag draped the small white coffin. Police officers stood stiffly 
in a solemn tribute under towering pines. Flower arrangements adorned the 
open grave -- some with bone-shaped dog biscuits attached. Faro, a Norfolk police 
dog shot to death while apprehending a robbery suspect last weekend, was laid 
to rest Friday in a pet cemetery in Virginia Beach. His send-off drew 
attention to the region's working police canines, trained to waylay suspects, protect 
police officers, search for people and, in some cases, sniff out contraband 
or bombs. It also highlighted the strong bonds between police and the dogs they 
handle, which officers take home to their families after shifts on the 
streets. Early last Saturday, Faro was killed doing his job. Police gave this 
account of the incident: The 4-year-old German shepherd was one of two police dogs 
who responded with officers to an armed-robbery call in the 9300 block of 1st 
View St. around 4:30 a.m. Robbers had forced a man to the ground at gunpoint. 
At least two suspects fled as police approached. Faro stopped a man, Patrick 
Marcel Davis, 25, as he attempted to get into a vehicle. Davis pulled a gun from 
a pocket and shot the dog. Faro's handler, Officer Jerry L. Nowell Jr., 
ordered Davis to drop his weapon, but he did not. Nowell fired, striking Davis in 
the foot. Another police canine ``engaged'' the man, who fell to the ground and 
tossed his gun to the curb. Officers arrested Davis, who faces charges of 
killing a police service animal, robbery, abduction and weapons counts. 
Faro and handler Officer Jerry L. Nowell Jr.. Photo courtesy of Jerry L. 
Nowell Jr. 
Faro's funeral service began at the police K-9 Training Range near Norfolk 
International Airport. More than 30 police dogs, some from agencies around the 
state, sat in three rows with their handlers. Police from as far away as 
Roanoke attended, as did civilians. Top police officials praised Faro and his 
comrades. Norfolk's canines work for mere love and praise and, in return, give their 
all, said Lt. Wally Driskell. ``These dogs stand for everything that is good 
and loyal,'' he said. Acting Chief Shelton L. Darden lauded Faro as a hero. A 
bagpiper played ``Amazing Grace,'' and more than a few in the audience 
sniffled. A police motorcycle escort led the mourners in a procession to Garden of 
the Pines pet cemetery in Virginia Beach for graveside honors. Faro was buried 
next to Lobo, a police dog killed in the line of duty by a car in 1983, and 
Iron, shot while pursuing a suspect in 1997. 
K-9 officers place the casket of Faro while other officers salute during 
memorial service Friday. Photo by Hyunsoo Leo Kim / The Virginian-Pilot. 
An honor guard fired ceremonial rounds near the grave. More prayers were 
offered. Nowell accepted the flag from the coffin from members of an honor guard. 
Two buglers played taps. Officers shook Nowell's hand afterward. Faro's death 
was tough on his handler, other officers said. ``He said the hard part is when 
he goes home and sees the empty kennel in the backyard,'' Driskell said. 
``That's when it occurs to him that Faro's not coming home.'' 

    

</content>

</doc>
