<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jun 23 13:34:49 2003</date>
  <content>
ON THE CRUSADE FOR FARM-ANIMAL WELFARE

When animals are on the downhill slide, it usually means people are, too. 
Peter Presland's patch is the lower half of the South Island, "from 
Ashburton to the Antarctic," he jokes. The Dunedin-based animal welfare 
investigator – one of five throughout the country in MAF's special 
investigation group – spends a lot of time on the road, looking into his 
share of the 1000-plus complaints the ministry receives each year.

Eighty percent of these are minor, such as a lame horse. Of the serious 
cases, only 10 to 20 end up in court. He has been involved in two 
high-profile court cases in the south this year involving animals being 
neglected. "The farmer's state of mind and the condition of the animals are 
invariably linked," he says. "No one sets out to starve their animals." If 
the farm is shipshape, the problem is probably minor; if the farm's a mess, 
the farmer's life probably is too. "He might have had a serious health 
setback, or his wife might have left him. Whatever the reason, he gets to 
the point where he can't manage and doesn't want to get up in the morning. 
"He loses interest in everything, including his stock." No matter how bad 
the situation, Mr Presland always tries to work with the farmer so the 
animal problem can be solved.

When the farmer has agreed to take the necessary remedial steps, Mr Presland 
usually leaves him to it, only following up with a phone call or a visit if 
his sixth sense tells him the farmer is bluffing. "If that fails, if the 
owner doesn't do what he has to do, clearly there has to be a more robust 
approach, including the possibility of court action." Even better than 
fixing the problem is preventing it in the first place.

The other part of his role is educative – "spreading the gospel" about 
minimum standards of animal care to saleyard managers, stock agents and 
transport operators as well as farmers. But major cases of animal neglect 
don't happen overnight. They start with small signs and that's when Mr 
Presland believes the farmer's community can play a crucial role. "My 
experience is that other farmers in the area knew all along there was a 
problem and turned a blind eye." People saw their neighbour struggling but 
hesitated to become involved in case it was seen as being nosy. "A phone 
call, a bit of a helping hand back then could have saved the situation."

</content>

</doc>
