<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Aug  5 07:18:41 2003</date>
  <content>

The ?Animal Planet? network has been around and about South Florida for a while looking for dramatic rescues and above-and-beyond efforts to assist stricken critters.
At least twice, the film crew itself became part of the story. And on both occasions, the saved dogs ended up at the Tri-County Humane Society shelter in Boca Raton.
The latest incident was particularly heart wrenching, since it involved major emergency surgery that saved the life of a nearly dead canine, but left him with only three legs.
The rescued dog, Twiggy, is now recuperating in a Tri-County foster home and is doing very well, said Jeannette Christos, founder and CEO of the society. ?He has gained 17 pounds, is very active and gets around as if he still has all fours.? 
?He is sweet and loves kids,? she added. ?He will make someone a wonderful pet and is looking for a good home.?
In June, an ?Animal Planet? camera crew was riding with a Miami Dade animal control officer when they found a stray female dog that had just given birth to a litter of seven pups in a storage shed behind a restaurant.
Ed Hubbard ? who handles rescue calls for Tri-County ? was dispatched to bring the dogs to the shelter. 
Christos said Monday those pups have all been adopted, but the mom ? named Sweetie because of her disposition ? is still available.
As to the latest incident, Chloe Leland, producer and videographer for ?Animal Planet,? was again riding with a Miami animal control officer to film an animal abuse case in that city. On their way, they spotted an injured dog walking on the side of the road. The dog could barely walk and hadn?t eaten in a long time.
They picked up the dog and took it to Tri-County, where Dr. Bruce Tannenbaum of Regency Veterinary Clinic examined him. He weighed 37 pounds ? some 40 pounds under normal weight. 
He also took x-rays that showed Twiggy had at one time had a botched surgery on his hip. To walk properly and be free of pain and infection, he determined that Twiggy would have to be seen by a specialist.
?At that point, we called Dr. Kenneth Moore, who practices out of Coral Springs Animal Hospital and is one of the top veterinary surgeons in South Florida,? said Christos. ?We were hoping that there was something Dr. Moore could do to help Twiggy, who was obviously suffering terribly.?
He determined he?d have to amputate a leg, as the damage from the previous surgery was too extensive. Christos immediately wondered how Tri-County ? a non-profit organization ? could pay for it.
Moore solved the dilemma. Saying he did not want to see Twiggy suffer any more, he agreed to perform the surgery for free.
?We couldn?t believe what we were hearing,? said Christos. ?But the more we heard about Dr. Moore, the more we realized that he is not only one of South Florida?s top veterinary surgeons, he also sincerely loves his four-legged patients.?
Dr. Moore performed Twiggy?s three-hour operation, and ?Animal Planet? filmed the entire procedure. Twiggy?s story will air animal programming 

</content>

</doc>
