<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar 21 22:15:10 2004</date>
  <content>

Did David Graybeard, the chimpanzee who was first observed to use a tool by 
Jane Goodall, have any idea of who he was? Do elephants, dolphins, cats, 
magpies, mice, salmon, ants or bees know who they are? Was Jethro, my late 
companion dog, a self-conscious being? Do any of these animals have a sense 
of self? What do these animals make of themselves when they look in a 
mirror, see their reflection in water, hear their own or another's song or 
howl, or smell themselves and others? Is it possible that self-awareness - 
"Wow that's me!" - is a uniquely human trait?

Because there's much interest and much exciting work to be done concerning 
what animals know about themselves, it's worth reflecting on what we do and 
don't know about animal selves. There are academic and practical reasons to 
do so.

In his book, "The Descent of Man and Selection in Relation to Sex," Charles 
Darwin pondered what animals might know about themselves. He wrote: "It may 
be freely admitted that no animal is self-conscious, if by this term it is 
implied that he reflects on such points, as whence he comes or whither he 
will go, or what is life and death, and so forth." Darwin also championed 
the notion of evolutionary continuity and believed that animals had some 
sense of self. In the same book, he wrote, "Nevertheless, the difference in 
mind between man and the higher animals, great as it is, certainly is one 
of degree and not of kind." Thus, there are shades of gray and not 
black-and-white differences between humans and other animals in cognitive 
abilities. So, while animals might not ponder life and death the way humans 
do, they still may have some sense of self.

After decades of studying animals ranging from coyotes, gray wolves, 
domestic dogs, and Adlie penguins and other birds, I've come to the 
conclusion that not only are some animals self-aware, but also that there 
are degrees of self-awareness. Combined with studies by my colleagues, it's 
wholly plausible to suggest that many animals have a sense of "mine-ness" 
or "body-ness." So, for example, when an experimental treatment, an object, 
or another individual affects an individual, he or she experiences that 
"something is happening to this body." Many primates relax when being 
groomed and individuals of many species actively seek pleasure and avoid 
pain. There's no need to associate "this body" with "my body" or with "me" 
(or "I"). Many animals also know the placement in space of parts of their 
body as they run, jump, perform acrobatics, or move as a coordinated 
hunting unit or flock without running into one another. They know their 
body isn't someone else's body

</content>

</doc>
