<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 13 09:10:49 2003</date>
  <content>
Recently, the Tallahassee Democrat published a column from a member of a 
local animal welfare group taking the Tallahassee-Leon Community Animal Service 
Center (TLCASC) to task regarding its work with animal rescue groups.
I'd like to share some information regarding TLCASC, which is a 
city-operated, animal welfare and rescue organization that takes in more than 10,000 
animals a year. In addition to housing and caring for these animals, we oversee 
animal control, humane education, volunteer involvement and animal adoption and 
fostering programs.
Our organization reunites lost animals with their owners, helps mediate 
disputes between neighbors involving animals, treats ill and injured animals and 
testifies in court regarding citations and animal abuse cases.
We have a caring team of employees and volunteers committed to helping find 
homes for unwanted and abandoned animals. We receive an average of 30 such 
animals a day, peaking to over 60 on some summer days. Many come to us wretchedly 
ill and in poor condition, and, within our limits, we provide the best care 
possible with a full measure of compassion and dedication.
In both March and September of this year, no adoptable dogs were euthanized 
at our facility. That is a tremendous tribute to our staff and, most 
importantly, our community - from citizens to volunteers to benefactors.
We have effectively changed how TLCASC works with local animal welfare 
groups. In the past, purebred and very adoptable dogs coming to the shelter would 
often be immediately turned over to one of these groups. In a city-run facility, 
designed to serve the public, these adoptable pets must be made available to 
the general public first. Accordingly, our new policy reflects this mandate.
The policy states that we can transfer an animal to a local animal welfare 
group after two weekends in the adoption ward for the standard adoption fee and 
at no cost after two months. This allows the shelter to better serve the 
public, while working with the animal welfare groups to ensure the best chances for 
the animals finding a home.
</content>

</doc>
