<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar 14 00:40:47 2004</date>
  <content>

?They were first introduced to England near Cheshire,? explains Zoe Smolka, 
Scotland?s first red squirrel conservation officer, with the Dumfries-based 
Red Squirrels in South Scotland. ?At the time, a lot of plants were being 
introduced to decorate gardens, and stately home owners seemed to think squirrels 
would make a nice addition. No-one anticipated how successful they would be, or 
the serious consequences of their spread on the red squirrel population.? 
Numerically, the greys undoubtedly have it. Their population is estimated at 
more than two million against only around 160,000 reds. Why can?t they live 
together? The problem, apparently, is that while both eat similar diets, greys 
hold the evolutionary advantage, being capable of digesting large seeds from 
broadleaved trees. Reds, meanwhile, are heavily dependent on traditional Scots 
spruce trees ? which are currently in decline. What?s more the larger greys 
eat more and can digest unripe acorns and seeds. Reds ? which have to wait till 
fruits ripen ? are being pipped to their food supply, resulting in weight loss 
and inability to breed. The ?grey tide? is considered a major threat to reds?
 survival, which is why SNH?s strategy ? as well as targeting land 
management, including plantations that favour reds over grey ? also prioritises control 
of the invader, whose status is that of vermin. 
It gets thornier; ?control? translates as ?culling?. Live capture and 
shooting are the only legal methods of dispatching the creatures, and Smolka ? the 
red squirrels? champion in south Scotland ? demonstrates a typical wire cage 
trap. Baited with maize ? a favourite grey squirrel snack ? they are covered 
and placed on the ground, where greys generally feed. To minimise suffering, 
traps are checked twice daily, and any reds immediately released. As for the 
unfortunate greys, Smolka says: ?Some people shoot them in the trap, but we 
advise you get a sack, put it over the end and when the trap is open, the grey 
goes into the sack. You then take it in the sack to very solid ground, like 
concrete or stone, and give it a very hard blow to the back of the head.? </content>

</doc>
