<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Aug  4 10:46:14 2003</date>
  <content>
  "BGH-treated milk is safe because it is 
 indistinguishable from normal milk." 
 Executive Branch Report on rbGH, February 9, 1994 
 
 "Milk from cows given supplemental bovine somatotropin 
 is the same as any other milk...Unfortunately, a few 
 fringe groups are using misleading statements and blatant 
 falsehoods as part of a long-running campaign to 
 scare consumers about a perfectly safe food." 
 Statement of C. Everett Koop on Genetically engineered milk, 
 February 6, 1994 
 
 "Recombinant rbGH treatment produces an increase 
 in the concentration of insulin-like growth factor-I (IGF-I) 
 in cow's milk." 
 "Levels of IGF increase in milk after cows are treated with rbGH." 
 National Institutes of Health Assessment of Bovine 
 Somatotropin, December, 1990 
 
 "A strong positive association was observed between 
 IGF-I levels and prostate cancer risk." 
 Science, vol. 279. January 23, 1998 
 
 "Insulin-like growth factor is thought to 
 have a role in breast cancer." 
 The Lancet, vol. 351. May 9, 1998 
 
 "High plasma levels of IGF-I were associated with an 
 increased risk of lung cancer. Plasma levels of IGF-I 
 are higher...in patients with lung cancer than in 
 control subjects." 
 Journal of the National Cancer Institute, 
 vol. 91, no. 2. January 20, 1999. 
 
 "The insulin-like growth factor (IGF) system is widely 
 involved in human carcinogenesis. A significant association 
 between high circulating IGF-I concentrations and an 
 increased risk of lung, colon, prostate and pre- 
 menopausal breast cancer has recently been reported." 
 International Journal of Cancer, 2000 Aug, 87:4, 601-5 
 
 "...serum IGF-I levels increased significantly in the milk 
 drinking group, anincrease of about 10% above baseline-but 
 was unchanged in the control group." 
 Journal of the American Dietetic Association, 
 vol. 99, no. 10. October 1999 
</content>

</doc>
