<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Aug 13 14:59:24 2003</date>
  <content>
Suspicions raised over another death
'Blunt impact' killed veteran, 81, who had hired Michelle Knotek as 
caregiver
RAYMOND -- James McClintock, an 81-year-old Pearl Harbor veteran who often 
rode his motorized wheelchair to the grocery store, needed a caregiver. So 
he hired Michelle Knotek.

Six months later, McClintock died from an unexplained blow to the head, 
leaving Knotek $5,000, his home and his beloved dog, Sissy.

...

Yesterday, authorities said the couple's three daughters had also suffered 
abuse at the hands of their parents, and the Department of Health and Social 
Services began poring over its records to try to learn more about Michelle 
Knotek.

From April 2000 to June 2001, Knotek worked at the Olympic Area Agency on 
Aging in Aberdeen where she provided information and social services 
referrals before managers asked her to leave, said David Beatty, the 
agency's director.

The non-profit organization serves seniors and vulnerable adults in Clallam, 
Jefferson, Grays Harbor and Pacific counties.

McClintock was a client at the agency, where he received help with general 
issues, such as navigating Medicare, but he did not qualify for in-home 
care, Beatty said.

Sometime in September 2001, McClintock hired Michelle Knotek to care for 
him. During that same time, records show, McClintock wrote a will, leaving 
his home, his dog and some money to Knotek, whom he listed as a "friend."

Then, in February 2002, McClintock died from "blunt impact to the head," 
according to his death certificate. Michelle Knotek, who had called 911 that 
day, said McClintock fell, though a local doctor who examined McClintock's 
body ruled the manner of death "undetermined."

Michele Knotek received Sissy and at least $5,000 with which to take care of 
the dog. McClintock loved the black dog with skinny white legs so much that 
he wanted Sissy buried next to him.

Once the dog died, Michelle Knotek was deeded McClintock's $140,000 home, 
which is now up for sale.
....





Cruelty to animals is one of the most significant vices of a low and ignoble 
people.
Alexander von Humboldt


</content>

</doc>
