<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb 11 21:23:50 2004</date>
  <content>The first confirmed case of mad cow disease in
the United States has given consumers food for thought about what they put
on their dinner tables.

Food scares - Alar on apples, PCBs in farm-raised salmon, E. coli in
hamburgers - typically do. Although there are no documented cases of
anyone dying from the first two food-related issues, some have died from
E. coli.

But when it comes to mad cow, technically known as bovine spongiform
encephalopathy, once a person is infected, there is no question about the
outcome - he or she will die. To date, 143 persons in the United Kingdom
have died from the disease that literally eats away at the brain.
...
But some food industry experts wonder if the mad cow scare marks a
watershed event - a moment when a small but growing market for organic
food explodes in popularity. Although they don't expect a nationwide surge
in vegetarian eating habits - estimated at between 4 and 10 percent - they
do expect some shift in the food chain.

"This could be a shove in what I think is the right direction," said
Marion Nestle, author of the widely discussed - and debated - book "Food
Politics: How the Food Industry Influences Nutrition and Health," which
generally took big food to task for many of the country's health woes.
...
"Most stores are reporting they're getting about 30 calls a day from
people asking about organic goods, and that doesn't mean they're all the
sudden going to become vegetarians, but are looking for safer
alternatives," Tuitele said.

The beef industry is fighting back. The National Cattlemen's Beef
Association launched a $4 million television ad campaign promoting beef on
Jan. 26.
...
IS THIS FOOD REALLY NATURAL?

Here are the definitions of "organic" and "natural," according to the USDA:

Organic: A USDA-accredited certification agency must attest that the
animals have never received antibiotics or added-growth hormones. In
addition, all feeds must be certified organic.

Natural: Minimally processed, no artificial ingredients. The USDA permits
no preservatives in these products.</content>

</doc>
