<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb 25 17:02:42 2004</date>
  <content>A milestone was reached in Colorado this 
week with the first conviction under the state's felony animal cruelty 
legislation. 
Lyle Jackson Harrison of Aurora became the first person convicted in Colorado 
of felony animal cruelty for failing to provide adequate food and water to 56 
horses. As a result, he's being sentenced to 90 days in jail and 200 hours of 
community service. 
Aggravated cruelty to animals has been a felony in Colorado since 2002, but 
this was the first case that saw a conviction. Colorado's previous laws treated 
torture, maiming, or killing of animals as a misdemeanor only. 
"We applaud this conviction. It represents a victory in that laws against 
animal cruelty are not only being passed but are being enforced as the 
legislature intended them to be," says Joan Casey, American Humane's associate director 
of shelter services.
American Humane, a Denver-based organization dedicated to both child and 
animal protection, helped write this legislation and advocate for its passage. 
Spokespeople for the national nonprofit testified before the Colorado State 
Legislature on how animal abuse is linked to other types of violence, such as child 
abuse and domestic violence. The evidence is so overwhelming that 41 states 
and the District of Columbia currently have felony convictions for egregious 
acts of animal cruelty. 
The case has added significance in the wake of the recent tragic incidents in 
Colorado in which five dogs became the victims of savage cruelty after they 
were stolen from the Colorado Humane Society. Three of the dogs were set on 
fire. Only one, a puppy named Ashley, survived. Last week, American Humane 
awarded $1,000 through its Second Chance Fund to the Colorado Humane Society to 
offset the medical expenses for Ashley.
"With this conviction we have added assurance that whoever is responsible for 
these heinous crimes will be found and prosecuted to the fullest extent of 
the law," says Casey.
A primary goal of American Humane is to raise concern about intentional acts 
of cruelty toward animals and to encourage communities to enforce tougher 
penalties for these crimes. </content>

</doc>
