<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:36:48 2003</date>
  <content>
AN IMPENDING shortage of vets with farm animal experience could leave the 
United Kingdom vulnerable in dealing with a future major disease outbreak.
MPs have warned that unless action is taken the Government could find it 
difficult to put in place a prevention plan as part of its proposed animal welfare 
strategy.
A report by the all-party House of Commons environment, food and rural 
affairs committee said it was hard to estimate the number of vets able to deal with 
large animals. but it was apparent that there is likely to be a shortage.
Committee chairman Michael Jack said any shortage of large animal vets would 
leave Britain vulnerable to further outbreaks of major animal diseases like 
foot-and-mouth.
"The announcement of Government strategies to improve veterinary surveillance 
and animal health and welfare is welcome," said Mr Jack. "But the Government 
must ensure that there are adequate numbers of vets to deliver results."
The warning follows similar concerns expressed at the annual congress of the 
Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons earlier this month that more veterinary 
practices are focusing on domestic pets as the number of livestock farms shrink 
at the same time as pet insurance schemes guaranteeing full payment of vet 
bills increase.
A survey for the RCVS this year revealed that only 960 of Britain's 3,000 
veterinary practices now do farm work. 
The survey also showed that the proportion of time devoted to treating cattle 
has fallen from 14% in 1998 to 7.5% in 2002 and the time spent treating sheep 
during the same period has fallen from 4% to 1.3%.
The MPs say this trend threatens the Government's ability to encourage 
veterinary surveillance for animal disease outbreaks and improve ani-mal health and 
welfare standards.
They say the Government should encourage student vets to join large animal 
practices. And ministers should be prepared to intervene in the market if 
necessary to ensure adequate pay for vets who deal with farm animals.
They also warn that the Competition Commission's report into 
prescription-only veterinary medicines might further reduce the numbers of large animal vets 
and call for the report to be reconsidered in that light.
</content>

</doc>
