<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed May 28 23:41:00 2003</date>
  <content>
On Friday 23rd May, the 2 adolescent female gorillas "Brighter" and "Twigs" 
were repatriated to Cameroon from
Nigeria where they had lived for many years as pets in the northern 
metropolis of Kano. I'm sure you've all heard
the story by now, but the gorillas were purchased as infants by a Lebanese 
businessman who saw them in the market
and felt pity for them. He tried unsuccessfully several times to find 
permanent homes for them. The gorillas
(ages 6 &amp; 9 yrs) are products of the bush meat trade and are believed to be 
western lowland gorillas (G. g.
gorilla), and not Cross River gorillas (G. g. diehli). They were smuggled, 
in separate incidents, into Nigeria as
infants, to eventually wind up for sale in Kano. In December 2002, they 
were put under house arrest by the federal
Ministry of Environment as a violation of CITES protocols.

After months of trying to coordinate the effort, the NGO Pandrillus was 
able to successfully carry off the
repatriation on Friday. The gorillas were transferred from Mr. Paul Raad's 
compound to Kano International Airport
courtesy of Julius Berger Nigeria. They were flown on domestic carrier 
"IRS" to Lagos early Friday morning with
Pandrillus Director Peter Jenkins, Pandrillus Nigeria Manager Ubi Sam 
Ettah, Alhaji Bindawa of Ministry of
Environment (Kano), and Paul Raad of Kano. "Jam Packed Cargo" of Lagos 
coordinated their transfer to Murtala
Muhammed International Airport terminal, and loading into a Cameroon 
Airlines 757-400 jet for the 70 minute flight
to Douala.

A press conference was held by Environment Minister Dr. Imeh Okopido on the 
tarmac with Brighter and Twigs holding
forth in their travel crates. BBC, AFP and a tremendous turnout from the 
ever-vibrant Nigerian media were on hand.
Also in attendance were Prof. Emmanuel Obot, Acting Director of Nigerian 
Conservation Foundation; Ian Redmond of
GRASP; and Melanie Virtue of UNEP Nairobi. The aircraft departed Lagos at 
1:15 pm and was received in Douala by
Ministry of Environment &amp; Forests (MINEF) officials and staff of Limbe 
Wildlife Center. On the ground in Douala the
Provincial Delegate of Littoral Province handled all airport formalities 
for a swift and safe transfer to the Limbe
Wildlife Center.

The gorillas were promptly off-loaded to continue their journey in a MINEF 
truck to their new home in Southwest
Province, where they will join a group of 8 gorillas, ranging in age from 3 
to 13 years, once they complete
quarantine.

The Limbe Wildlife Center is a collaborative effort between MINEF and the 
NGO Pandrillus. LWC is also home to
orphan chimpanzees, drills, mandrills, baboons and 8 other monkey species. 
It was created in 1993. Pandrillus
also established and operates the Drill Rehab &amp; Breeding Center in Cross 
River State, Nigeria. The costs for
Brighter and Twigs repatriation were provided equally by UNEP-GRASP Nairobi 
and the Pan African Sanctuary Alliance
(PASA).

</content>

</doc>
