<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 11 17:10:29 2004</date>
  <content>
Every once in a while officers here at Animal Care and Control run into 
really sad situations. Last week, they were called to a residence to assist with 
about 35 cats that lived in a home with a lady who had to go to the hospital. 
The condition of the cats and the home were typical of an animal hoarder, a 
person who "collects" animals WAY past his or her ability to care for them. 
This home was filthy and full of cat feces and trash. The cats were thin, some 
had genetic deformities, many were deaf and had large areas of patchy or missing 
fur. 
So, thinking about this disorder, the boss went to the Tufts University Web 
site which has lots of enlightening and sobering information. They used the 
following criteria to define animal hoarding: "More than the typical number of 
companion animals. Inability to provide even minimal standards of nutrition, 
sanitation, shelter, and veterinary care, with this neglect often resulting in 
starvation, illness, and death. Denial of the inability to provide this minimum 
care and the impact of that failure on the animals, the household, and human 
occupants of the dwelling." 
These cases most often come to light when the "crazy lady with all the cats" 
down the street is brought to the attention of authorities by a neighbor, 
family member or health care professional. Sometimes utility workers who notice a 
foul smell from a residence or garage will contact the police and the truth of 
what is occurring at the residence comes out. 
The homes are often unlivable to anyone but the individual who resides there. 
Many of the homes of these people must be condemned once the enforcement case 
has come to an end because the interior of the home is so damaged by animal 
waste and filth it cannot be reclaimed. Animal control officers who have to 
enter the home often have to wear masks or self-contained breathing devices for 
their own protection.</content>

</doc>
