<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu May  6 22:17:20 2004</date>
  <content>

An iguana enjoys its new home at the Washington County Humane Society 
Thursday, after being rescued from a Germantown apartment where officials found 300 
animals, including 76 ducks, a pair of alligators, scorpions, tarantulas, 150 
mice and several snakes, including an anaconda and a python.


GERMANTOWN - 
State conservation warden William Mitchell said he has never seen - or 
smelled - anything like it in his 31 years as a state wildlife warden.
Tuesday night, local authorities followed their noses and found nearly 300 
animals and numerous carcasses in a village apartment at W162 N11651 Park Avenue 
leased by the girlfriend of a Milwaukee area man who has twice been cited for 
similar incidents involving illegal animals.
??Smelly. Very smelly. The smell was just unbelievable,?? Mitchell said.
In a freezer, he said he found frozen carcasses of "two raccoons, a gray 
squirrel, two cottontail rabbits and a raccoon pelt."
advertisement



Domestic ducks and wild mallards were also living in the apartment. Droppings 
covered the floor, Mitchell said.
??It was really stinking. ... It made my eyes water,?? Mitchell said.
More than 70 ducks in a basement pen were only part of the menagerie 
Germantown police found in the apartment when other residents complained of the stench.
Germantown police called Mitchell to the apartment at 10 p.m. after getting a 
9:30 p.m. complaint from the building?s landlord about the foul odor and odd 
noises, said Police Chief Peter Hoell. Eventually up to five police officers 
were involved in the investigation Tuesday night, he said.
Marnie Brown, executive director of the Washington County Humane Society, 
said with help from the Elmbrook Humane Society and a vet from Milwaukee Area 
Domestic Animal Control, 76 ducks, two game birds, two alligators, six snakes, 10 
turtles, an African frog and other frogs, a few geckos, an iguana, three 
tarantulas, three scorpions and well over 150 mice and rats were collected.
"All together, there were close to 300 critters in there," Brown said, 
including an anaconda and a python.
Decaying animal carcasses were found in an adjacent garage.



 

__________________________________________________________________________
</content>

</doc>
