<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr  5 01:57:10 2004</date>
  <content>
o outsiders, animal rights advocates look to be a strange lot. We don?t eat 
meat, avoid cosmetics tested on animals and boycott the Ringling Brothers 
Circus. Drape ourselves in fur? Forget it. Animal rights advocates don?t even wear 
leather or wool
Many people view advocates as certifiable, grade-A, top-of-the-class 
nutcases. Reduced to the essentials, however, what we believe is just common sense. 
We believe the animals killed for food, trapped for fur, used in laboratories 
or trained to jump through hoops are unique somebodies ? not generic 
somethings. What happens to them matters to them. What happens to them makes a 
difference to the quality and duration of their lives. 
In these respects, animal rights advocates believe humans and these animals 
are the same ? equal. And so it is that all advocates share a common moral 
outlook: We should not do to them what we would not have done to us. Not eat them. 
Not wear them. Not experiment on them. Not train them to jump through hoops. ?
Not larger cages,? we say, ?empty cages.? 
?Humane treatment? 
Comparatively speaking, few people are animal rights advocates. Why? Part of 
the answer concerns our disparate beliefs about how often animals are treated 
badly. Animal rights advocates believe this is a tragedy of incalculable 
proportions. Nonadvocates believe mistreatment occurs hardly at all. 
That nonadvocates think this way seems eminently reasonable. After all, we 
have laws governing how animals may be treated and a cadre of government 
inspectors who make sure these laws are obeyed. 
In the language of our most important federal legislation ? the Animal 
Welfare Act ? animals must receive ?humane care and treatment.? In other words, 
animals must be treated with sympathy, kindness, mercy and compassion ? the very 
meaning of the word ?humane.? It says so in any standard dictionary. 
For fiscal year 2001, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service 
conducted 12,000 inspections. Of that total, only 140 sites were reported for possible 
violations because of improper handling of animals. That works out to a 
compliance rate of almost 99 percent. 
Inspections and myth 
Tragically, the public?s trust in the adequacy of government inspections is 
misplaced. What inspection service inspectors count as ?humane? undermines the 
inspections before they are conducted.</content>

</doc>
