<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Oct 24 20:26:22 2003</date>
  <content>
Just recently, there has been a storm in cola bottles, with pesticides
being unearthed in soft drinks, adulterated spices, contaminants found in
bottled drinking water and now high levels of toxicity in some vegetables
 . Everyone is appalled and staring at their lunch and wondering if it is
edible, while the media are raising a general hue and cry about the whole
issue.

But what is really strange is that no one seems to be concerned about the
contaminants in meat, fish, chicken, eggs and dairy products. It is worth
thinking that if vegetables, water and spices have such high levels of
toxicity in them, the levels in the unhealthy, bacteria-laden meat that
people consume have to be off the scale.

In fact, meat-eaters have far more to worry about than vegetarians. Animal
products have more than 90 per cent of the toxic chemical residues as
compared to only 10 per cent in fruits and vegetables. It is a known fact
that non-vegetarians suffer more frequently from various types of food
poisoning than vegetarians. 
...
In fact, a study done by the US Department of Agriculture  found that 99
per cent of broiler carcasses have detectable levels of E. coli bacteria,
and their presence is an indicator of faecal contamination. If these are
the figures in the US, then imagine in India, where even the minimum
animal welfare regulations are being ignored?
...
People who follow a vegan diet,  whose meals are made from a variety of
grain foods (bread, cereal, rice, pastas), vegetables, legumes, fruits and
nuts, have dramatically less risk of contracting a bacterial infection
than those who eat meat and dairy products. Any health care ?expert? worth
his or her salt, including officials at the Physicians Committee for
Responsible Medicine and the leading dietary associations, will tell you
that plant-based foods are better for our health than animal products, and
it goes without saying that vegetarian foods are more humane.
...
During a photo shoot, model/actor Aditi Govitrikar told People for the
Ethical Treatment of Animals? representative, ?If you eat chicken or other
meat, you?re consuming toxins, fat and cholesterol. Veg food is powered
with all the vitamins and protein you need to be at your best?. Who can
argue with that?

--</content>

</doc>
