<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul  5 02:06:07 2004</date>
  <content>

For the last month, in DeKalb, Ill., hundreds of horses have been cruelly  
murdered in Cavel International, one of the three Belgian- and French-owned  
horse slaughterhouses in the country. 
They are hoisted by their rear legs, and their throats are slit while they  
are conscious, until their hearts pump the last drop of blood. This is all so  
that the well-to-do in Belgium and France can fill their bottomless bellies 
with  a fancy dinner in a high-profile restaurant. 
Every week, 1,400 sound, young American horses enter into the concrete hells  
of the three foreign-owned horse slaughterhouses (besides Cavel, there are 
two  others in Texas). They will not see the sun again. They tremble violently,  
fighting for their lives as the smell of the blood and the images of their  
fellow horses being carved up alive pierce their nostrils and their eyes. There 
 is no escape. 
Americans have stood up and said "No more," but one man from Virginia is  
denying them their right to be heard. Yes, Congressman Bob Goodlatte is one the  
main reasons why this holocaust continues. He is blocking, in the U.S. House  
Committee on Agriculture, a bill titled The American Horse Slaughter 
Prevention  Act (H.R. 857). This federal legislation would outlaw the slaughter of 
horses  throughout the country, in order to appease this foreign-owned 
horse-slaughter  industry and other special interests that seem to control his decisions. 
The representative from Virginia is not allowing democracy to run its course. 
 This legislation already counts 224 cosponsors - over half of Congress - and 
has  the overwhelming support of Americans who are outraged by this barbaric  
business. Yet it looks like his opinion is the the only one that counts. 
Despite  the fact that millions of letters have been received by Congress in 
support of  H.R. 857 and its Senate counterpart, S. 2352, Rep. Goodlatte is forcing 
us to  bow to his personal agenda and to the interests of overseas horse-meat 
 businessmen.
</content>

</doc>
