<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Feb 20 20:07:12 2004</date>
  <content>


The report, based on information provided by chief brand board investigator 
Jerry Derr of Rapid City, says brand inspectors falsified brand inspection 
documents.

That allegation centered mostly on a practice called "chuting" cattle, 
although the report refers to it as "shooting" cattle. The attorney general's office 
wasn't sure of the correct spelling on Thursday.

In any case, Reed said "chuting" is done not to hide anything but to speed 
shipment of cattle after a sale.

Here's how the process works.

When cattle are brought to a sale barn, a state brand inspector makes a 
record of each animal, its brand and its owner.

After the sale, a brand inspector fills out a market clearance form listing 
each animal, its buyer and its brand. That practice should be followed whenever 
cattle are sold to a feedlot, Reed said.

But state officials said inspectors often cut corners on the market clearance 
form when the cattle sold are going right to a slaughterhouse. Loads of 
cattle sold for slaughter are usually from many different herds and carry many 
different brands.

Writing down each slaughter cow's brand would add hours to the shipping 
process, Reed said.

"They want to get those cows out of those pens, get them on trucks and get 
them to slaughter."

So inspectors write down the exact number of cows in the shipment but record 
only a sampling of the brands.

"Nobody is ever going to look at those brand papers again," Reed said. 
"They're going east to a slaughter plant."

Reed said the "chuting" practice was in use when he became a brand inspector 
in South Dakota in 1960 and has been widespread and accepted since.

However, the attorney general's report insisted that "chuting" results in 
inaccurate or incomplete market clearances to cattle buyers. The practice makes 
it difficult and, in some cases, impossible to track title for individual 
cattle, the report said.

Reed said if there is any question of ownership, the brand record for each 
cow is still on file at the sale barn.

Reed said that before Derr's investigation, he thought chuting was legal. He 
still isn't convinced it is illegal but has ordered all inspectors to stop the 
practice.

Reed also disputed other allegations in the report and in statements by state 
officials:

n Long said the inspection system failed to discover at least half a dozen 
instances of cattle theft.

Reed said that charge originated from an incident at the Philip Livestock 
Auction in which seven or eight stolen cattle were sold and later discovered in 
Montana.

At the time, investigator Derr said he was troubled that stolen cattle with a 
registered brand and no proof of ownership could be sold within the West 
River Ownership Inspection Area.

But Reed said the sale barn and inspectors there followed proper procedure, 
requiring the seller to sign an affidavit showing where he had bought the 
cattle. That paper trail helped trace the cattle and prosecute the thief, Reed said.

Reed said he didn't know of other thefts the state report mentioned.

n The report said some brand inspectors illegally kept money from "local" 
inspections, those done at ranch sales. "That is bogus," Reed said. He said money 
from local inspections comes into his office. An inspector who embezzled 
inspection fees about 14 years ago was prosecuted and jailed.</content>

</doc>
