<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Sep  6 08:58:25 2003</date>
  <content>
With more than 60 percent of adults weighing in as overweight or obese,
public policymakers and government health officials are scrambling for
ways to improve the American diet.
...
Dr. Don Colbert, physician and nutritionist, thinks the obesity crisis
could be solved if Americans would pause before inhaling a super-sized
fast-food meal and ask themselves a simple question: "Would Jesus eat this?"

If it's loaded with saturated fats, sugar or artificial ingredients, the
answer is no, says Colbert, whose recent book, What Would Jesus Eat?
(Thomas Nelson, $22.99), combines biblical scholarship with conventional
dietary wisdom.
...
Colbert's not the only Christian diet guru urging people to ask what Jesus
would eat. Christian advocates of vegetarianism say if Jesus were alive
today, he would maintain a plant-based diet out of compassion for animals.
Others say Jesus would probably approve of genetically modified food,
given his own propensity for transforming and multiplying food in Scripture.
...
Although there may be disagreement over what Jesus would choose given the
option of a veggie burger, broiled lamb with garbanzo beans, or
genetically modified corn-on-the-cob, growing numbers of Christians are
looking to the Bible for dietary guidance, hoping that Scripture might
succeed where science has failed in inspiring healthy eating habits.

Dr. Stephen Kaufman, co-chair of the Christian Vegetarian Association,
said he hopes more Christians will start making faith-based choices about
what they eat.

"There are a lot of people out there for whom diet is a reflection of
their faith," he said. "We're taught to take care of our bodies, the
temple of God's spirit, as Paul said."
...
Calling the Christian vegetarian movement an "attempt to co-opt Jesus for
left-wing animal-rights propaganda," Moore cited Paul's letter to the
Romans, which calls vegetarians weak, as proof that the Bible sanctions
meat eating.

--</content>

</doc>
