<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jul 15 08:22:24 2003</date>
  <content>
PAMPLONA, Spain - Fugitivo panted hard. With blood streaming down his
legs, he stuck his tongue out and stared at the red cape as thousands
watched the final seconds of his four-year-old life.

Fugitivo, a gray 1,100-pound fighting bull, once lived on the Cebada Gago
ranch in southern Spain, but was noticed for his impressive horns. That
lured the scouts who picked the bulls for this year's San Fermin festival,
the annual fiesta that has attracted millions since Ernest Hemingway
chronicled it in the 1920s.

"We chose bulls from the most prestigious ranches, with the best horns,"
said Jesus Cia, one of the men responsible for picking the 60 bulls and
men who fight them.

With that, Fugitivo began an inexorable journey toward his ultimate fate:
becoming a bowl of wine-seasoned stew, served up at night in Pamplona's
restaurants.
...
"In the end, a bull is like a melon," he said. "You have to try it to know
if it's good or rotten."

Fight or no fight, from the moment a bull is dragged from the ring, the
business of selling the body begins.

Once a bull is bled and gutted, its head and hoofs are cut off and its
skin removed.

In the butcher shops and supermarkets of Pamplona, the meat sells for
between $2 and $4 a pound, depending on the cut. Some will end up in
Pamplona's beef stew.

Since mad cow disease rattled Europe's meat industry several years ago,
bulls undergo days of laboratory tests, delaying the sale by up to three days.

While the San Fermin bulls used to be butchered immediately outside the
bullring, the bulls are now merely bled here. They are then taken to a
slaughterhouse, where veterinarians extract brain tissue samples and check
for mad cow.

"It was more dignified when we used to cut the bulls up here," said Txema
Larragueta, an usher at the arena, watching as a forklift hoisted a
sagging animal and eased it into a refrigerated truck. "I preferred it
that way. The bulls kept their dignity."

</content>

</doc>
