<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec 22 09:31:19 2003</date>
  <content>
LONG Update, answers to some questions, and what we
 will need in terms of
 
 supplies.
 
 ChicagoLand German Shepherd Rescue is the rescue
 under whose license
 these 
 dogs are being pulled, cared for and placed.
 Maribeth is the 
 president/founder. But as you can imagine, she is
 swamped! See below for 
 contact info &amp; details.
 
 1. Media. Chicago Ridge Animal Welfare League is
 being very careful and 
 working with a specific reporter who has been
 supportive in the past. 
 Please do not publicize anything per se. Let the
 rescuer's handle it as 
 there are reasons for caution just now.
 
 2. Update. The last count was around 200 dogs. Seems
 there were probably 
 about 300 total. Just yesterday, they were able to
 get into the building.
 
 Before now, they were dealing only with the dogs on
 the outside.
 
 3. WE NEED:
 CRATES
 BOWLS
 COLLARS
 LEATHER LEASHES (nylon will be hard on the handler
 as these dogs are
 large 
 yet completely untrained).
 MONEY (see below for donation options) The bills
 will be high due to
 needed 
 veterinary care.
 FOOD: Adult or Lg Puppy formulas only! Please, NO
 regular puppy food!
 These 
 dogs are at starvation level and it will overwhelm
 their tummies. Right 
 now, they are being fed a tablespoon or two every
 hour until their
 stomachs 
 can start to function again. Also, no Eukanuba
 please as it is too rich. 
 Eukanuba Sr might work though.
 
 4. Kira is heading up fundraising. With support from
 Peter Johnson of 
 ChicagoLand GSD Rescue. See below for contact
 details.
 As we come up with fundraising ideas, I will send
 out updates.
 
 5. FINANCIAL DONATIONS can be made as follows:
 PayPal:  (there's a link on the home
 page - right side. Has 
 puppies in the picture)
 e-mail address for PayPal 
 Checks: Send checks to:
 
 FOSTER HOMES/ADOPTION:
 Contact ChicagoLand GSD Rescue!
 Foster/adoption forms are available on their website
 
 6. DONATIONS OF HARD GOODS: Crates, bowls, leashes,
 collars, food.
 (Crates 
 can be on loan also: in that case, if at all
 possible please find a way
 to 
 attach your name andphone number to the crate. A key
 ring/tag works
 well.)
 Contact Kira and Peter to arrange delivery/pick up
 of these items.

</content>

</doc>
