<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Feb 12 08:53:58 2004</date>
  <content>
 
A recent financial risk assessment "showed a significant shortfall in the 
project funding" 
Scientists and animal rights campaigners are at odds after the Government 
gave Cambridge University permission to build a research centre where tests will 
be carried out on monkeys.
Deputy Prime Minister John Prescott ruled in favour of the project after the 
local planning authority and an inspector found against it.
The university said the proposed centre at Girton, near Cambridge, was vital 
for the development of research into diseases such as Alzheimer's and 
Parkinson's.
However it admitted there were problems over funding the project.
South Cambridgeshire District Council refused permission after police raised 
fears about public safety at the site, which is on a main road.
The university appealed against the council's decision and a public inquiry 
was held last year.
An inspector recommended the appeal be dismissed but Mr Prescott disagreed 
and granted planning permission.
His decision report said: "The Secretary of State accepts the potential for 
disruption of the surrounding road network and associated safety concerns and 
he accords such concerns significant weight.
"Because of this he has considered whether there is a clearly more suitable 
alternative site ... but has concluded that none has been identified...
"In light of the national importance of the research work envisaged which is 
in line with stated Government policy, combined with the lack of a clearly 
more suitable alternative site, the Secretary of State concludes that ... very 
special circumstances exist that are sufficient to outweigh any harm to the 
Green Belt and other interests caused by the development."
Cambridge pro vice-chancellor Professor Tony Minson said the university was 
"pleased that this important research centre has been given the go-ahead".</content>

</doc>
