<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat May  1 11:55:49 2004</date>
  <content>
HELENA — The two men wandered into the Stevensville tavern and the 
conversation turned to hunting and fishing — not unusual in any Montana bar. 
They asked about one of the bar's regulars they'd heard about, a local named 
Ben Ruiz.

Before long, Ruiz approached the pair and offered his services, telling them 
he was a hunting and fishing outfitter. He said he could not only arrange a 
hunting or fishing trip but could get one of the men, from Iowa, an illegal 
Montana resident hunting license — for a price.

What Ruiz didn't know was the two men were undercover state game wardens 
investigating reports that Ruiz, who was not a licensed outfitter, was 
arranging illegal hunts.

Wildlife officials say Ruiz, who later was convicted or pleaded guilty to 
seven misdemeanor fish and game violations, is just one example of what they 
consider a troubling and growing trend in Montana — people taking cash to 
help others poach.

Increase in cases

Poaching is hardly a new phenomenon to Montana, and most cases still involve 
individuals illegally killing animals. The most common citations remain 
hunting or fishing without a license or hunting on private property without 
permission.

But wildlife officials say that over the past decade, they have seen an 
increasing number of cases of what they call "illegal commercialization" of 
wildlife, in which money — sometimes thousands of dollars — is exchanged to 
arrange illegal hunts.

"People are willing to pay large amounts of money to kill a trophy animal 
and don't care if it's illegal or not," said Jim Kropp, chief of law 
enforcement for the state Department of Fish, Wildlife and Parks. "They get 
comfortable hunting behind locked gates and shooting what they see.

"Things Montanans see every day and take for granted are worth huge amounts 
of money to some individuals," he said.

Kropp said it is difficult to provide accurate figures on how big an 
increase there has been in such illegal hunts. But he said it has been 
steady enough that catching those involved in illegal paid hunts has become 
a major focus for game wardens.



Our task must be to free ourselves by widening our circle of compassion to 
embrace all living creatures.            Albert Einstein</content>

</doc>
