<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec  1 07:16:20 2003</date>
  <content>Michael Spencer and his 16-year-old son, Sean, weren't looking
to make history when they drove down to the Eastern Shore from their
Montgomery County home yesterday. But if the first Sunday of deer hunting
in Maryland in 280 years was designed for anyone, it seemed perfect for them.

As Seventh-day Adventists, who celebrate the Sabbath on Saturdays, the
Spencers, who live in Silver Spring, went to church on the opening day of
deer season. This year though, like thousands of other hunters, they got
in weekend shooting by taking advantage of a one-day reprieve from a state
law that has banned Sunday hunting since the Colonial era. 
...
"The deer population has gotten so out of control, it's changed people's
minds about Sunday hunting," said Valerie Connelly, a spokeswoman for the
Maryland Farm Bureau. "It's not just soybeans and corn anymore. It's fruit
trees, and nursery and landscaping stock that's being destroyed."

With the Department of Natural Resources estimating Maryland's deer
population at nearly 300,000, wildlife management experts say allowing
about 75,000 licensed firearms hunters a crack at sika and white-tailed
deer yesterday might help cull 100,000 or more animals from the
overpopulated herd during the two-week firearms season. Bow hunters were
allowed a similar one-day Sunday hunt Nov. 2. 
...
Opponents of Sunday hunting, including animal-rights groups, some
religious groups, horseback riding clubs and others, say hikers and
outdoors enthusiasts should be allowed to roam the woods on Sundays
without fear of stray gunfire.

"From our perspective, Sunday was the only day during hunting season
without worrying you'll get your head blown off," said Cindy Wood, a
longtime member of the Wicomico Hunt, a fox-hunting group. "But with this
many counties excluded, including Wicomico, it lessens the impact. Maybe
it is a decent compromise." </content>

</doc>
