<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:52:14 2003</date>
  <content>
Not everyone subscribes to the "Pets, don't leave home without'em" school of 
thought. Still, about 14 percent of Americans have traveled with a pet, 
according to the Travel Industry Association of America.
Man's best friend - the dog, not the remote control! - is the most common of 
animal voyagers. An American Automobile Association survey reports that 78 
percent of the people who travel with pets have taken Spot along.
Fifteen percent have toured with Fluffy, and 2 percent have brought along 
their birds. Three percent have traveled with a ferret, rabbit or fish.


Most of these trips were taken by car, though about 6 percent of pet-lovers 
have boarded a plane with pet in tow.
According to the Humane Society of the United States, only a few cruise lines 
accept pets, and usually just on ocean crossings.
Except for Seeing Eye dogs, beastie riders aren't accepted on most other 
modes of public transportation in this country. But check before you go.
. . .
Just because Rover is happy and healthy doesn't mean he longs for the open 
road. Leaving a pet at home - unless it has a problem with separation anxiety - 
can be the best option.
If you have an adventuresome pet that travels well - or if you are the one 
with separation anxiety - go ahead and hit the highway. Just don't toss Princess 
in the back and hope for the best, though. Preparation is a good thing.
"Pets who travel frequently usually do well," says Dr. James S. Cloman. "But 
there are always exceptions." Cloman works at Hanover Green Veterinary Clinic 
in Mechanicsville.
One way to prepare for a longer trip, he says, is to take your pet on shorter 
trips to fun places - not just to the kennel, to get groomed or get shots.
At www.petswelcome.com, packing a kit for the trip and also in case of 
emergency is suggested. Include items such as a supply of your pet's regular food, a 
blanket, a favorite toy or two, paper towels or newspapers, plastic bags (for 
scooping) and a container of fresh water (to avoid a sudden change in 
drinking water).
If you're traveling with a cat or dog, make sure you have your pet's ID, 
rabies tags and medical history. Clipping Rex's nails also can help prevent 
scratches and upholstery damage.
Cloman suggests transporting cats and dogs in carriers, if possible. "It's 
really a safety issue. You don't want something jumping around you when you're 
driving."
Once in the car, an overwrought pet may pant or salivate heavily. Cloman 
doesn't recommend sedatives for trips that last an hour or less because the 
tranquilizing effect lasts too long.
Whether to use a sedative is a matter of common sense, he says. "If they get 
very restless, get very vocal, try to escape from the carrier . . . you might 
want to try it."
Always check with your vet before administering calming medications, Cloman 
warns. The dosage is extremely important, especially with very young or older 
animals.
"Another sign of nervousness," he says, "is coming out at either end." One 
way to avoid carsickness or diarrhea is to feed your pet the night before if 
you're leaving in the morning, or offer a light meal in the morning if you plan 
to depart later in the day.
It's generally a good idea not to feed your pet while you're in transit, 
though it should have access to water either in the car or at rest stops.
If your pet is on medication, call your vet before you go. Some drugs, 
particularly antibiotics, can upset pets' stomachs when they travel. Cloman says 
it's usually best not to administer drugs right before you leave.
When it comes to the restroom routine, he says, "Most people know their pets' 
habits. Sometimes the pet has to go more frequently on trips because he's 
nervous or excited. Let dogs get out where they can be comfortable and walk 
around."
And always make sure Rover's on a leash before you open the car door. "If 
they've really got to go, they will. Give them the opportunity. If they take it, 
great. If not, you've done all you can do."
Unless it's a 12-hour trip, Cloman says, most cats are really good about 
keeping their own counsel, as it were.
Some carriers are big enough to accommodate a small litter box, he says. But 
most cats usually wait to go till you get where you're going.
Some cats, Cloman adds with a laugh, won't do anything the whole trip except 
grumble.
Letting your dog hang out the window while driving isn't necessarily a good 
idea. "I have clients whose dogs never jumped out, but suddenly did, or had 
corneal injuries from rocks."
When it comes to carrying more than one cat, Cloman says, there's no set 
standard. Some do well two to a carrier; some need space. Sometimes, even if 
they're in separate carriers, it's better if they can see each other.
The best thing to do if you want to transport your pet via jet, he says, is 
to call the airline. Often, you'll need a health certificate, sometimes a 
number of days in advance. If you're leaving the country, check on quarantine and 
pet policies, as well as any necessary vaccinations.
"It's a big, loud trip," Cloman points out. Though most airlines now allow 
pets as carry-on baggage - if carriers will fit under your seat - some pets 
still must fly in separate compartments.
"They can be more stressed if their owners aren't with them. You can give 
them a sedative, but there's no one monitoring them, and that's not good," Cloman 
says. "It's a bit of a compromise . . . but nothing I would let stand in the 
way of doing it [if you must fly]."
However your pet travels, Cloman says, there's not much you can do if it is 
extremely vocal. Sometimes a good, calming touch will help.
But, he acknowledges, "I have a low tolerance for noise like that myself." 
Fortunately, his dogs mostly snore when they travel.
. . .
Small animals are a, er, horse of a different color, says Dr. Larry Winters. 
Winters, who built Hanover Green Veterinary Clinic in 1997, has worked with 
wildlife as well as "these other little creatures that have become popular [as 
pets]."
Winters usually recommends a travel carrier for smaller animals.
"We don't typically sedate them," he says. "They don't usually need it. 
Rabbits and ferrets aren't quite like a dog or cat that gets nervous or upset when 
you change their routine. They don't seem to be as stressed."
Of course, it can be hard to tell. "Most of these animals don't vomit," 
Winters says. "They just don't have the type of muscle in the esophagus that allows 
them to regurgitate."
Be sure not to use too large a carrier. If you're transporting a guinea pig, 
hamster or mouse, for instance, too big a carrier allows the animal to bounce 
around, which can cause injury.
Winters recommends lining the cage or carrier with a lot of bedding material. 
Unless it's a really long trip, don't leave food or water with your pet. 
"They tend to burrow or bury food, then just eliminate in that and [the bedding] 
absorbs the odor."
On long trips, a small water bottle will do the trick.
Winters also suggests smaller cages for birds on the go. Bigger birds do well 
in carriers made for cats or small dogs.
His primary advice for bird-lovers is to watch the car temperature. Too much 
air conditioning or wind from the windows, for example, tends to aggravate 
their respiratory systems.
Snakes, Winters says, usually do best in pillowcases (just don't forget to 
secure the open end!). They can breathe through the fabric. Plus, he says, they 
like the confinement, it keeps their body temperature normal, and they won't 
be bouncing off the walls.
The same goes for fish. Bag'em. "Plastic bags are the best containers," says 
Winters, "because they minimize trauma to the body of the fish."
Tie the bag so the water doesn't spill, then put it in a box or big can to 
keep it upright.
"Fish travel pretty well that way," he says. Just remember to open the bag 
every hour or two and let in some air.
Winters is a fan of containment in general. "Cats not confined can really 
freak out," he says, recalling one client who was traveling with her cat and dog 
when the cat jumped in the driver's face.
"She rolled her car; the cat disappeared; the dog broke his leg; the woman 
was injured. I give people carriers now"

Contact Cynthia McMullen at (804) 649-6361 or cmcmullen@timesdispatch.com



</content>

</doc>
