<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun May 16 00:37:34 2004</date>
  <content>
The setting: an operating room in Guelph, Ontario, where a team of doctors 
are hard at work trying to remove a faulty pacemaker wire from four-year-old 
Nikki?s heart. She?s had heart problems all her life and unless the wire is 
removed, she will die.
?It would be easier for us if we had the wire going this way,? says one 
doctor.
?Just put a finger underneath the heart so I can lift it up and just hold it 
so I can see where this should go,? says another.
?Is that good??
?Yeah, that?s fine.?
?Tell me when I can let it go.?
?OK, let?s put him back down. We?ll do this in stages.?
The conversation sounds like an exchange between doctors in any OR in Canada, 
but the Guelph facility where they are operating isn?t your ordinary hospital 
and Nikki isn?t your ordinary patient. In fact, this hospital is part of the 
Ontario Veterinary College, and Nikki, a boxer, is one of about 9,600 dogs 
that are treated there each year.
And it?s not just dogs that get treated at Guelph. The facility is a 
full-service teaching and referral hospital and features two clinics ? one for large 
animals such as horses and another for smaller animals where everything from 
dogs and cats to ferrets are welcome.
?I like to think of this as the ? Sick Kids Hospital of veterinary medicine,?
 says Dr. Karol Mathews, who runs the Intensive Care Unit at the small animal 
clinic. ?You could also maybe compare it to a Toronto hospital. It?s a 
teaching hospital. We have all types of specialists here. These are cases that we 
would see that would be referred by your family physician or your family 
veterinarian, simply because of the complexity of the illness or the injury, and 
just as you wouldn?t expect your family physician to be able to deal with 
everything, this is exactly what happens with the local veterinarian.?




 
______________________________________________________________________ 
</content>

</doc>
