<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Oct 10 06:54:28 2003</date>
  <content>

Federal agents are seeking a Sonoma man -- the son of a Bay Area city
official -- in connection with recent bombings at companies in Emeryville
and Pleasanton, the FBI announced Thursday.

A criminal complaint against Daniel Andreas San Diego, 25, was filed in
federal court Sunday but remains under seal by a judge's order. An FBI
news release issued Thursday says San Diego is char-ged with "maliciously
damaging and destroying, and attempting to destroy and damage, by means of
explosives, buildings and other property."

That's a fancy way of saying agents believe San Diego placed the two bombs
that exploded Aug. 28 outside Chiron Corp. at 5400 Hollis St., Emeryville,
and one that exploded Sept. 26 outside Shak-lee Corp. at 4747 Willow Road,
Pleasanton. He's now a fugitive, and if caught and convicted, could face
up to 10 years in federal prison for each bombing.
...
E-mail communiques passed through animal-rights groups after the bombings
said the companies were attacked because they've associated with
Huntingdon Life Sciences, a British laboratory firm that uses animals for
testing and has become the target of an international activist movement,
Stop Huntingdon Animal Cruelty (SHAC).

Biotech firm Chiron said it has used Huntingdon in the past but no longer
does. Shaklee -- a producer of vitamin, personal hygiene and household
cleaning products -- does no animal testing, but parent company Yamanouchi
Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. uses Huntingdon's services. 
...
Former FBI agent Rick Smith, who worked in the bureau's San Francisco
office during the Unabomber investigation, said he sees parallels between
this investigation and that which concluded with the arrest and conviction
of Ted Kaczynski. In both, he said, the wording and syntax in the claims
of responsibility for the bombings must have moved the case forward.

"This guy is way over the extreme edge," Smith said of the e-mails sent
following the Emeryville and Pleasanton bombings. "The more language
investigators have, the easier it is to identify people. It's usually one
person, not a group, so the writings help because now you can do a profile." 

--</content>

</doc>
