<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec  1 19:35:55 2003</date>
  <content>
Monday December 1, 03:00 AM 

Silent killers in our rivers 
THE role of otters in the rapid and devastating decline in Scottish wild salmon stocks may previously have been dramatically underestimated, new research indicates. 
A study by the Wester Ross Fisheries Trust (WRFT) shows that otters caught and ate 28 per cent of wild salmon captured and electronically tagged as part of a radio tracking project on the River Ewe. 
Now scientists have called for the experiment to be repeated on a larger scale to discover whether any action should be taken to prevent the mammals' further impact on salmon stocks in Scottish river systems. 
The main aim of the project was to help the Ewe District Salmon Fisheries Board target areas of the river system that were in greatest need of habitat and stock restoration, but also to discover the relationship between spawning salmon and other wildlife. 
Twenty-five wild Ewe salmon were caught, tagged and released back into the river from June to October 2001. 
The River Ewe catchment area, which includes Loch Maree and the Beinn Eighe National Nature Reserve in Wester Ross, is recognised as among the most spectacular and highly-valued natural wildlife habitats in Europe, and the freshwater fisheries are internationally famous. 
The WRFT report said: "Our observations, together with data from radio tracking, suggest that seven of the 25 radio tagged salmon (28 per cent) were taken by otters between mid November and early December. The fate of two other tagged fish is unknown." 
It adds that, with salmon stocks seriously depleted within the Kinlochewe area, "even a 10 per cent level of predation may impact adversely upon the subsequent recruitment of juvenile salmon". 
Dr John Webster, an independent scientific advisor to Scottish Quality Salmon, which represents the salmon farming industry, said: "If the level of predation of the tagged fish was as high as this report suggests, it could well be that the impact of otters [on the wild salmon population] has been dramatically underestimated. If you combine this report's findings about otters with the impact of mink, they may be taking a very significant proportion of salmon in the rivers." 
He added: "It is very difficult to know what the solution to this is as otters are highly protected. However, salmon are also protected. There are a number of options, and otters can legally be trapped and relocated to less sensitive rivers if it can be proved that they are having a significant impact." 
Destructive control by culling was out of the question, he said, and something that "no-one should condone or suggest". 
Numbers of the Eurasian otter, the only native UK species, declined sharply in the early 1960s due to organochlorine pollution, but have recently made something of a comeback. 
Populations are still healthy in northern and western Scotland and the UK numbers are starting to increase, but are still a long way off census information from the early 1950s. The last government figures compiled in 1996 estimated that there were 6,600 otters in Scotland, compared to just over 7,000 in the rest of the UK. They were afforded legal protection in Scotland in 1983, but remain threatened due to habitat destruction, pollution and high road mortality. 
Dr David Carss, an expert on vertebrate ecology at the Centre for Ecology and Hydrology in Banchory, who has himself conducted radio tracking research on otters, said: "I guess we are into new territory now because salmon stocks have declined so drastically in the last decade. As more people start looking they are finding evidence that otters do predate large adult salmon just on the point of spawning or just after." 
John McKenzie, a part-owner of fishing rights on the Ewe and a member of the Ewe District Salmon Fishery Board, said: "At face value it is a source of concern, that's for sure.
</content>

</doc>
