<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 29 01:58:44 2004</date>
  <content>
Time is running out for thousands of horses used to make one of the most 
widely prescribed drugs in the country. We're talking about the Premarin horses. 
Our investigation into the treatment... and slaughter of these horses back in 
November made national news. Now in a follow-up, Terri Parker meets with the 
people inspired to help, after seeing her story... and why their help is needed 
now more than ever. 
Chris Jung introduces us to Halo. "He's a 10 month-old Premarin foal. He's 
purebred quarterhorse and we rescued him from Foal Advocates Network up in 
Canada. 
Halo has the eyes of an angel, and the spirit of... well, he's certainly got 
the usual mischief of any youngster. He seems happy to be alive here at Gaston 
Farm in Port St. Lucie...as well he should be. 
"My daughter saved him", Jung adds. "She said an angel saved him. He was sent 
by an angel." 
Jung rescued Halo from a farm in Canada, where Halo was one of thousands of 
foals slated for the slaughterhouse. Halo's mother, was one of the "premarin 
mares". As we first revealed in undercover video in November, the constantly 
pregnant mares are kept tethered five months a year in small, cold stalls in 
Canada, so their estrogen rich urine can be collected to make the menopause drug 
Premarin. 
Premarin is short for "pregnant mares urine." 
Chris Jung, who founded the rescue group "Hope for Horses" did not know what 
those premarin barns were really like, until she saw our investigation. The 
foals born each year as a byproduct, aren't needed. So when they're just a few 
months old, they along with mares too old to breed anymore...are sent by the 
thousands to feed lots to fatten up and then taken to the slaughterhouse to be 
made into dog food, or shipped overseas as a delicacy. 
Since our report, others across the country have stepped forward to save the 
Premarin foals and the pregnant mares. Alice Crow saw our investigation on our 
sister station in Cincinnati. She was so moved, she rescued thirty premarin 
mares. 
"They work for us", Crow says, "And they make so much money. Then they're 
just tossed as a byproduct." 
The fates of others hang in the balance. Sales of Premarin dropped 
dramatically last year after a 2002 study showed hormone replacement therapy could be 
dangerous, causing heart problems and strokes. Premarin's maker, Wyeth Ayerst, 
had to decrease production by one third.</content>

</doc>
