<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Mar 31 15:10:03 2004</date>
  <content>
And the winners are ... 
- Overall Rescue Cat of the Year for 2004: Chrissie - Wolverhampton feline 
whose purr therapy and ability to make children feel loved make her a firm 
favourite on the children's ward of the local hospital. Chosen by a panel of cat 
lovers and feline experts and announced by Helen Ralston, Cats Protection's 
Chief Executive. 
- Best Friends winner: Chrissie. Details as above and in notes. Category 
judged and category winner announced by actor, Anthony Head, and his partner, 
Sarah Fisher. 
- Best Purr-sonality winner: Biscuit - a characterful cat from Huntingdon, 
Cambs, whose purr-sonality and love of life has won everyone's hearts - 
including the family dogs'! Category judged and category winner announced by eminent 
astronomer, Sir Patrick Moore CBE. 
- Best Turn-Around winner: Mittens - Skegness cat at death's door who, with 
her owner's TLC and the right cat-titude, turned herself right around to become 
a trusting caravan park host and daring rider of farm tractors and diggers! 
Category judged by Coronation Street actor, William Roache MBE. 
- Long-Distance Traveller winner: Houston - Brave and cheeky Aberdeenshire 
tortie named after her birthplace, who survived (just) a six-week transatlantic 
crossing trapped in a cargo container, with only drops of condensation to keep 
her alive. Category judged and category winner announced by renowned 
cat-loving journalist, Chrissie Iley. 
- Most Incredible Story winner: Susskin - Inspirational, blind feline from 
Stourbridge, West Midlands, who works miracles with autistic child. Category 
judged by author, Jilly Cooper. Category winner announced by Pauline McLynn. 
- Ultimate Survivor winner: Felix - A Birmingham feline who has survived all 
his nine lives and who lives with 35 pellets in his body as a result of a 
vicious attack by a poacher. Category judged and category winner announced by TV 
vet, Dr Scott Miller.
</content>

</doc>
