<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Aug 11 17:55:19 2003</date>
  <content>
Excerpts from Earth Policy News "CHINA LOSING WAR WITH ADVANCING DESERTS"
(Lester R. Brown)

 "....Power concedes nothing without a demand. It never did and it never
will......"
-  Frederick Douglass, Conference in Canandaigua, NY, 1857

 ...............China is now at war. It is not invading armies that are
claiming its
 territory, but expanding deserts. Old deserts are advancing and new ones
are
 forming, like guerrilla forces striking unexpectedly, forcing Beijing to
 fight on several fronts. And worse, the growing deserts are gaining
momentum,
occupying an ever-larger piece of China's territory each
year.....Overplowing
and overgrazing are converging to create a dust bowl of historic
 dimensions. With little vegetation remaining in parts of northern and
 western China, the strong winds of late winter and early spring can remove
 literally millions of tons of topsoil in a single day--soil that can take
 centuries to replace................A report by a U.S. embassy official in
May 2001
after a visit to Xilingol Prefecture in Inner Mongolia (Nei Mongol) notes
that
although 97 percent of the region is officially classified as grasslands, a
third of the terrain
 now appears to be desert. The report says the prefecture's livestock
 population climbed from 2 million as recently as 1977 to 18 million in
2000.
 A Chinese scientist doing grassland research in the prefecture says that
if
 recent desertification trends continue, Xilingol will be uninhabitable in
15
 years........... In the deteriorating relationship between the global
economy and the earth's
 ecosystem, China is on the leading edge. A human population of 1.3 billion
 and a livestock population of just over 400 million are weighing heavily
on
 the land. Huge flocks of sheep and goats in the northwest are stripping
the
 land of its protective vegetation, creating a dust bowl on a scale not
seen
 before. Northwestern China is on the verge of a massive ecological
meltdown.........While overplowing is now being partly remedied by paying
farmers to plant
 their grainland in trees, overgrazing continues largely unabated. China's
 cattle, sheep, and goat population tripled from 1950 to 2002. The United
 States, a country with comparable grazing capacity, has 97 million cattle.
 China has 106 million. But for sheep and goats, the figures are 8 million
 versus 298 million. Concentrated in the western and northern provinces,
 sheep and goats are destroying the land's protective vegetation. The wind
 then does the rest, removing the soil and converting productive rangeland
 into desert.


 This Update is adapted from Plan B: Rescuing a Planet under Stress and a
 Civilization in Trouble, being published September 10, 2003. Chapters 1
and
 11 are online now for free downloading.
 http://www.earth-policy.org/Books/index.htm



</content>

</doc>
