<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Apr  8 07:23:06 2004</date>
  <content>
Amidst the turmoil caused by Tuesday?s column ?Meat should not be pushed
out of diets? there has been a certain level of unchecked
anger regarding the perception entertained by some concerning meatless
diets. Truly, a reasonable mind must admit that vegetarianism is a life
choice that should be left to the individual, and barring extremism or
irresponsible management, is perfectly healthy. But there is a certain
faction within the vegetarian community, specifically those motivated by
animal rights, which would take a position of similar extremism to
Tuesday?s column.

Underlying the Tuesday column?s theme is a legitimate concern for
omnivorous individuals. The fact is, while most vegetarians would leave
the world to eat meat as they please, there is a certain number that would
strike it from menus world wide. 
...
In particular, this right is challenged by groups such as People for the
Ethical Treatment of Animals, and contemporaries who often militantly
lobby against the meat industry. PETA?s mission statement submits that
?animals are not ours to eat, wear, experiment on or use for
entertainment.? It is at this point that the very arguments present on
today?s page countering the April 6 column turn against PETA members and
supporters. Vegetarianism should not be forced upon meat eaters, and until
PETA and similar groups amend their campaign goals to allow for the meat
industry to continue operation, anyone who enjoys a burger is justified in
maintaining legitimate concerns about the vegetarian and vegan movement.
...
This does not imply that all vegans or vegetarians are blood crazed animal
rights activists, nor that they would impose their lifestyle on the
typical chicken loving consumer. But it is an aspect of the lifestyle that
should be considered by those who ascribe to it when they wonder about
their public image, and it is a feature of the lifestyle that anyone who
does not pursue vegetarianism must be aware of.</content>

</doc>
