<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Aug 18 11:48:00 2003</date>
  <content>
At the start of July, Stop Primate Experiments At Cambridge (SPEAC) was set up as the next stage in the campaign to halt to Cambridge Universityís proposed development of the primate research labs on the edge of the city. 

These labs are pointless, unneeded, and will cause untold suffering to the primates imprisoned in them. What is more, nobody in the area other than the University wants it. The public, police and local council have all spoken out against it. A local coalition successfully fought against it through democratic means, so now it has gone to the hands of the pro-animal abuse government. 

Nevertheless, SPEAC will continue the fight to ensure that these labs are never built. We hold the entire University guilty in this matter and are calling on everyone who opposes the primate prison to contact the university and put pressure on them until they do the right thing and cancel the project. 

Each week we will be releasing an action alert, targeting a different university college or department. It does not matter that they may not be directly involved in the building of the labs. What matters is that in Cambridgeís ancient and convoluted governing structure, they have a say and can influence the decision-making process. It is up to us all to make sure that they use their power to oppose the laboratories.

To this end, this week we are asking you to contact the top people at St Johnís College in Cambridge. Be polite, but be firm - these people are not the animal abusers. What is important is making sure your message gets though, that you want them to put pressure on the rest of the university and that we will not give up as long as Cambridge University insist on going ahead with itís plans. Ask them to contact the Vice Chancellor, the Senate and other relevant governing bodies on the primate prison issue and then let them know that there will be no peace for the entire university as long as they insist on going down this path. Ask them what they are doing to prevent the primate prison on the A307 being built.

</content>

</doc>
