<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Dec  5 16:43:58 2003</date>
  <content>As the mercury dips we all take shelter inside and 
seek warmth, meanwhile our four ? legged pals sit languishing in the chilly 
weather, for sometimes extended periods of time.
The Fort Record contacted the Edmonton Human Society (formerly the Edmonton 
Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals -- SPCA) and local dog sitter 
and canine expert Lisa Ecker, Owner ? operator of Fort Saskatchewan Canine 
Services.
?With dogs, people should keep in mind that not all dogs are built for 
lengthy periods of time outdoors. Generally short haired breeds, younger, and older 
animals, no matter how big they are, do not do well outdoors for long periods 
of time. If you do have an outdoor dog, and typically these animals are 
larger, long ? haired breeds, you need to still have an insulated or heated doghouse 
to give them shelter from the cold. In the doghouse we strongly recommend NOT 
having blankets, because they can freeze and then they actually make the 
animal colder. Instead we recommend using straw as bedding material. People can 
usually get straw by checking classified ads to see what farmers have for sale,? 
said Melissa Boisvert, Edmonton Humane Society Communications Officer. ?
Outdoor water dishes are a bad idea. If you?ve ever stuck your tongue to a metal 
pole when you were younger then you can imagine what it is like. Please use some 
other material than metal for your dogs water outside. Snow is not sufficient 
enough to be a water source. They really need to have fresh water ?.
Ecker echoed the concerns of the Humane Society and offered another option 
for bedding material, wood chips.
?First and foremost in winter are the icy conditions. A lot of people use 
salt to keep the ice and snow from cluttering their sidewalks, driveway or 
street. What that salt can do is really damage an animals feet and paws. It is 
really brutal on their feet just as it is on our vehicles. What you want to do if 
you are not using protective wear on your dogs feet is make sure that they are 
really well rinsed off after a walk. That salt can really irritate their skin,?
 said Ecker. ?Also keeping the hair cut fairly short if you have an indoor 
animal. That will help to prevent the ice and snow from balling up and causing 
irritation between their toes. A consideration for short coated dogs that are 
not outside a lot is protective winter wear like a sweater or jacket. Just 
because they have a fur coat on the outside does not mean that they are anymore 
capable of keeping warm than we are when the temperature starts to drop below 
minus 10?.</content>

</doc>
