<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Apr  3 10:27:49 2004</date>
  <content>
Hunting groups this week opened their campaign to discredit a ballot
measure facing Alaskans this fall that would ban bear baiting.

They accused sponsors of the ban of failing to register with the Alaska
Public Offices Commission. It's an attempt to conceal the identity of
individuals and groups bankrolling the effort, they say, and they suspect
Outside animal-welfare groups will be revealed.

Nonsense, say ban supporters, who believe baiting is unethical and unsafe
and that allegations of Outside influence are just a tactic to deflect
public attention from the real issue. And ironically, they note, the
hunters have hired an Oregon group to run their campaign.
...
The coalition, which includes the Alaska Outdoor Council, the Safari Club
of Alaska, National Rifle Association and other like-minded groups, hired
Pac/West Communications to run its campaign. Spokesman Jerod Broadfoot
said the Wilsonville, Ore., firm "handily defeated" an attempt to ban
trapping in Oregon in 2000. Alaska faces a similar challenge, he said.

"One of our main themes is, 'Don't let out-of-state extremists come in and
manage Alaska's game,' " Broadfoot said. "We completely expect the Humane
Society of the United States to dump three-quarters of a million" dollars
in the upcoming Alaska campaign, he added.

A spokesman for the Humane Society, senior vice president Wayne Pacelle,
said his group has not yet donated to the Alaska campaign but probably will.

"We are sensitive to the inside/Outside contribution issues. We also do
have a lot of other issues that we need to fund," he said. "But we
certainly don't want to see hunting groups based in Ohio and Washington,
D.C., pour money into a campaign to preserve the unsporting, inhumane and
unnecessary practice of bear baiting, and then claim they're somehow
Alaskans. It seems to me they've lost any credibility in this argument by
having a campaign based in Oregon. It's total hypocrisy." </content>

</doc>
