<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Jun 26 19:19:50 2004</date>
  <content>
If you feel a jab when you're walking the street alone, don't worry. It
will only be me infecting you with Aids. Look forward to meeting you
close up, you scumbag." This was the signoff in an anonymous letter sent
to a businessman linked with animal-testing company Huntingdon Life
Sciences.
...
...The firm, listed on the Alternative Investment Market, is building an
animal-testing laboratory at Oxford University. Extremists - none of the
well-known activist groups that The Independent on Sunday spoke to
claimed responsibility - wrote to shareholders warning that if they did
not sell their stakes, their details would be advertised on the
internet. "This will prompt activity by the animal rights movement to
persuade these shareholders to sell," the letter says. "If you are not
convinced of the effectiveness of these tactics then take a look at the
campaign against Huntingdon Life Sciences."
...
Activists say they will target any company connected with Montpellier.
Greg Avery, spokesman for Stop Huntingdon Animal Cruelty (Shac), argues
that anyone - and this includes market makers which allow the shares to
be bought and sold - providing a service to a targeted company is a
viable target. "If Montpellier had its market makers knocked out, then
it would have to be kicked off the London Stock Exchange." This includes
suppliers. "The Nazis could not have operated Auschwitz without
suppliers. Neither can companies."

The animal rights organisation Stop Primate Experiments at Cambridge
(Speac) has also turned its attentions to Montpellier, but insists its
activities are legal. It lists on its website the contact details for
Montpellier's London headquarters, as well as its six operating
subsidiaries. The site urges campaigners to make the companies "aware of
the depth of feeling within the animal rights movement towards this new
centre". But Robert Cogswell, a spokesman for the group, distances it
from violent tactics. "The purpose in posting the information is to
highlight a company's involvement in constructing the lab, but not to
encourage illegal acts."



</content>

</doc>
