<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri May 30 19:42:15 2003</date>
  <content>
Thanks a million for your support - please note that WWF, TRAFFIC and
Kadoorie Farm have withdrawn from the list and ammend.
The Resolution is now being sent to China's National People's Congress
in Beijing by Dr. David Chu Yu-lin.
Best wishes, Jill.

Snugglezzz@aol.com wrote:

 From: koreandogs@yahoogroups.com
 Sent: Friday, May 30, 2003 11:32 AM
 Dear friends,

 this is a very encouraging news. After this email, I
 will circulate a sample letter prepared by Animals
 Asia Foundation to urge the Chinese government to
 support this very encouraging development on behalf of
 wildlife, dogs and cats in China. Please circulate far
 and wide.

 I sincerely thank Animals Asia Foundation for their
 wonderful work for the animals. Please let's try our
 best to help their work by letting the Chinese
 government to know what positive effects it will have
 on the image and financial interests of Chins to pass
 this resolution. Action alert will follow soon.

 Thanks. Yoon

 --- In aapn@yahoogroups.com, "Dr John Wedderburn"
 &lt;jwed@h... wrote:
 PRESS RELEASE (for immediate release)      29 May 2003

 Hong Kong Legislator, Conservation and Welfare Groups
 agree on Resolution for China

 On Wednesday 28th May 2003, during a Discussion Panel
 on Protecting Wild Animals organised by Dr. Hon. Chu
 Yu-lin, J.P, Legislative Councilor and Deputy of
 China's National People's Congress, a unanimous
 resolution was passed concerning the trade and
 consumption of wild animals, together with domestic
 dogs and cats.

 Proposed by the Hong Kong based Animals Asia
 Foundation, the Resolution stated:  "We call for the
 Central Government of China to instruct all provinces
 to emulate the good example in Guangdong, where
 breeding, trading and consumption of wild animals has
 now been banned.  We urge the Central Government to go
 further by closing all wild animals markets
 countrywide, and banning the consumption of wild
 animals, dogs and cats, together with the breeding and
 trading of wild animals, dogs and cats for
 consumption."

 The Resolution, which was unanimously supported by the
 following groups, will now be submitted by Dr. Chu to
 the National People's Congress in Beijing:

 1.  Dr. Hon. Chu Yu-lin J.P., Legislative Councilor
 and Deputy of the National People's Congress
 2.  Animals Asia Foundation
 3.  The Conservancy Association
 4.  Friends of the Earth Hong Kong
 5.  Kadoorie Farm and Botanic Garden
 6.  Asian Animal Protection Network
 7.  Lamma Animal Protection
 8.  The Hong Kong Bird Watching Society
 9.  World Wide Fund for Nature Hong Kong
 10. Ocean Park Hong Kong
 11. TRAFFIC East Asia.

 During the meeting, Jill Robinson MBE, Founder and CEO
 of Animals Asia,  stressed the importance of finding
 solutions if the countrywide trade in wild animals,
 together with dogs and cats were to end and pledged
 Animals Asia's help in creating and producing public
 education programmes nationwide.

 Dr. David Chu Yu-lin said:  "Eating cats, dogs and
 wild
 animals is not only uncivilized, but can also
 negatively affect our health.  The Central Government
 should therefore ban such uncivilised behaviour
 through
 legislation."

 Ms Robinson paid tribute to Legislators and officials
 in Hong Kong and China who were spearheading a new era
 of humane education in China:  "The leadership of Dr.
 Chu and government members of the China Wildlife
 Conservation Association in Beijing is undoubtedly
 paving the way towards ending decades of misery and
 disease in the animals markets of China.  For the
 first
 time in nearly twenty years of calling for the closure
 of these cruel and unsanitary markets country wide,
 there is hope."

 Ends.

 For further information, please contact:

 Jill Robinson MBE - Founder &amp; CEO, Animals Asia
 Foundation, Hong Kong
 Tel: (852) 2719 3340 or Mobile: (852) 9095 8405 or
 jrobinson@a...
 or
 Dr. Hon David Chu Yu-lin - pager no.- Hong Kong -
 (852) 77703330

 For stills &amp; footage please contact Annie Mather -
 Media Director, Animals Asia Foundation, Hong Kong
 Tel: (852) 2521 0982 or Mobile: (852) 9425 7429 or
 amather@a...

   
</content>

</doc>
