<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 11:12:33 2003</date>
  <content>
Janine McCartney has a passion for cats -- a passion so strong that she has 
devoted a part of her life toward her fuzzy friends. 
McCartney has volunteered for the Cat Association of Topeka, 1719 S.W. Gage 
Blvd., since 1989. She also has served on its board for 10 years. 
McCartney has a magic touch with cats and is a licensed foster mom for C.A.T. 
When kittens need to be nursed to health or need to be bottle-fed, she 
dedicates the time to nurse them -- all with the ultimate goal of raising them and 
making them adoptable in the community. 

Janine McCartney has worked with the Cat Association of Topeka since 
1989.C.A.T. is a nonprofit, no-kill shelter that opened in 1989. The agency moved to 
its current location in July. 
"We renovated the building and did most of the work," McCartney said. 
The move took the help of many volunteers like McCartney. The cats and the 
staff are now settled in their new home -- a home dedicated to providing a safe 
place for the cats to reside until a match can be found for them. 
What prompted you to volunteer with C.A.T.? 
There was an ad in the paper when the association was getting organized. I 
attended the meeting, which was open to the public. I liked the idea of helping 
cats, so I started volunteering. I love all animals, but cats are easier to 
shelter. You could not have as many dogs here as you can cats. 
What is the best part of being with C.A.T.? 
Being with the cats. The reward is not in the paycheck. It's in perks, 
because they give back so much. There are a lot more people helping people than 
helping animals, especially cats. With a passion for cats, this is where I can 
help the cats. Coming here, I get to do what I like the most, be with the cats. 
The happiest time here is when someone comes in and fills out a pre-adoption 
form and walks out with the perfect cat. It's very rewarding. We have a lot of 
people who are dedicated. I've never worked so hard. You would not believe the 
things that people do to animals. That's why we're here. We know that the cats 
are safe. 
What do you consider your touch with cats? 
Fostering (kittens)... My goal is to bottle feed the kittens and get them to 
where they can be brought into the shelter and be adopted. The ultimate goal 
is always finding the perfect home. Sometimes that takes time. There is such an 
over-population of cats, so it takes quite a while before cats actually are 
adopted. Kittens are adopted faster. But some people do want adult cats. 
How do you keep yourself from getting attached (to the cats)? 
In the beginning I would adopt the cats myself. Then I got to the point that 
"No, that's not what a foster mom does." I can love them, take care of them 
and I have taught myself how to let go. Now it works for me being a foster mom. 
For a few years, I would just keep them. They do such a good job making the 
right match, that when a cat is adopted I feel very confident. I felt that I had 
kept so many of the fosters that I no longer had enough time to spend with 
each of them. Now I can do it. That's the goal of the foster home to be able to 
take care of them and love them and let go. 
What does your volunteer work at the shelter entail? 
I work retail and I do kennels once a month. That's a lot of work. It entails 
cleaning, feeding and medicating the cats, if necessary. 
What is the most challenging aspect of being at C.A.T.? 
We get a lot of calls from people who are needing help. We can't help 
everyone. Knowing how to help people, knowing how to answer their phone calls and how 
to help each individual. 
What was the remodeling process like with the new building? 
We did most of the work ourselves. Part of the building was new and the rest 
was a remodel. We had an interior decorator volunteer her services and picked 
out all the colors. It's a lot of paint and was really hard to paint all those 
colors. The cats now have colorful rooms and furniture. I'm just a small part 
of the C.A.T. Association. We had a lot of people who are dedicated and they 
just helped pull it together. It was a lot of hard work, I've never worked so 
hard. 
</content>

</doc>
