<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep  1 16:59:45 2003</date>
  <content>
Journalist Martin Coutts gives the details of a lengthy undercover
investigation conducted into a Premier Foods chicken farm, one of the
UK's largest chicken producers and known KFC supplier. The
investigators, working in conjunction with an undercover team from
Hillside Animal Sanctuary, shot extensive video footage of the
conditions on this factory farm. Here are some descriptions of the
cruelty they uncovered: 
. "There are more than 36,000 chickens here in huge windowless sheds.
The conditions they have to endure during their short, brutal lives are
so horrific it defies belief." 
. "Some birds are so lame and deformed they can only drag themselves to
the food and water troughs by their wings. Others stand motionless, too
dazed or dying to move." 
. "In one shed where chickens had been taken away for slaughter there
were dozens of carcasses littering the floor. In another - where scores
of birds had died - their remains were being picked over by other
chickens." 
. "One investigator who shot a secret film there said: 'I have
investigated animal welfare for many years, but this easily ranks
amongst some of the worst cruelty I have seen.'" 
KFC claims to have animal welfare standards in place which cover "all
chicken[s] intended to be sold at KFC," but such words are meaningless
when they allow hideous abuses to take place. And Premier Foods won the
"KFC Supplier of the Year Award" in January of 2001. If this level of
abuse represents the best of what KFC suppliers have to offer, imagine
what other farms allow! 

PETA is calling on KFC to immediately adopt PETA's recommended animal
welfare guidelines internationally. PETA's guidelines have been approved
by members of KFC's own animal welfare advisory panel and represent the
most up-to-date studies and research into animal welfare. Click here
&lt;http://www.kentuckyfriedcruelty.com/animals.html  to read more about
PETA's recommendations to KFC.


</content>

</doc>
