<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 17 14:42:27 2003</date>
  <content>
Association says raids targeting illegal trade in wildlife are harming 
animals, legitimate firms 
Zoo operators yesterday asked the authorities to halt raids of privately 
operated zoos, saying the stings had hurt business and adversely affected their 
animals. 
Forestry officials and police recently raided three private zoos in Chon 
Buri, Uthai Thani and Bangkok as part of a government initiative to stamp out the 
illegal trade in wild animals and endangered species. 
The raids followed a crackdown earlier this month on a wildlife-trade ring 
based in Nonthaburi, in which a large number of rare and endangered animals were 
discovered, most of them already killed and butchered. 
The Association for Thai Zoos, which includes over 100 private and state 
zoos, called a press conference yesterday at the offices of the Zoological Park 
Organisation (ZPO) to demand that further raids be postponed. 
The association said many private zoos were awaiting official permission to 
breed wild animals and also urged the authorities to better distinguish between 
legitimate zoo operators and illegal wildlife traders. 
Association chairman Sophon Damnui, who also serves as ZPO director, said the 
raids had demoralised zoo operators all over the country, fearing their 
premises could be next. 
Sophon, said most private zoo operators complied with wildlife laws. He also 
called on members of the public to report zoo operators involved in the 
maltreatment of animals. 
Also present at yesterday?s press conference were association advisers Pisit 
na Patalung, secretary-general of the Wildlife Fund of Thailand, and Senator 
Jaroon Yangprapakorn, whose family owns a private zoo in Samut Prakan. 
Pisit said that searches of zoos could have a negative impact on animals in 
captivity. Some of them could suffer shock, he said, while others might be 
unable to bear offspring for a long period. 
Meanwhile, a source said the ZPO ordered the transfer of Chiang Mai Zoo 
director Thanong Nateepitak. 
Thanong has been appointed deputy director of the ZPO, amid speculation that 
he was unable to cope with the additional workload in Chiang Mai following the 
arrival of two pandas on loan from China. 
Sophon insisted, however, that the new appointment was a promotion for 
Thanong. 

</content>

</doc>
