<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar 21 20:15:04 2004</date>
  <content>
Would you leave a profession with a reasonable expectation of a steady
income to start a business in which you have absolutely no experience?
Would you open a restaurant without a cook-stove? Would you open a
restaurant if you had to furnish it with tables and chairs from your own
house and donations from friends? Would you jump off a 300-foot cliff
without a parachute? Susan Mullen did.

Actually, she didn't literally jump off a 300-foot cliff without a
parachute. However, that is a reasonably accurate metaphor for what she
did in her professional and financial life when she opened Susie's
Vegetarian at 423 North LBJ, Suite E.
...
"Though I wasn't a vegetarian at the time, my vegan friends encouraged me
and convinced me that what this community really needs is a vegetarian
restaurant. I could have done a bakery, a pie factory or something of that
sort. But my friends convinced me that we need something for people who
wish to practice a healthier life-style.

On April 2, 2003, Susan opened Susie's Veggies on the Run. Much has
changed since then, including the name. It opened as a carryout - hence
the original name - but it has morphed into a sit down place with several
tables. More about the tables later.
...
Susan explained that her place is not your standard eating experience -
fast foods or otherwise. Every Wednesday night she and her customers have
a Sing-Out for Peace. Some folks just want to come in and talk. Politics
is a popular subject. Others find Susan's Vegetarian a good place to
exhibit art works. She has purposely kept her walls bare of murals or
other art so that painters, photographers and other graphic artists can
display their work. The artwork changes with the whims of the owner and
the artists.

"I realize my place fills a niche. I spend a little extra money to buy
baking powder with no aluminum. I buy organic products when possible. I
get people here from Weight-Watchers, the low-carb people and others who
are looking for special diets. I can deal with wheat allergies and people
who don't eat dairy products or eggs. And I can make it taste good. First
and foremost, I am a cook - was long before I became a vegetarian."
</content>

</doc>
