<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Apr 11 09:51:20 2004</date>
  <content>
Gardeners have had it with the deer. George Hughes, who lives outside
Annapolis, Md., has watched bucks use their antlers to lift the cages off
his tomatoes and sample the juicy Big Boys. They also mowed down 1,000
junipers he had planted at his tree farm in Easton, Md.

He had been told deer don't eat junipers. "Well, they don't like juniper,
but if they get a bad enough winter, they'll eat anything," he said.

So he rallied his fellow homeowners in Saefern, a community of 105 homes
on 250 acres, to bring the hunters in. He found a group of Vietnam
veterans who are ace bowhunters. They killed 15 deer in Saefern last
hunting season. "And they're going to do the same this year," Hughes said. 
...
Hunting seasons have been extended, and states like Pennsylvania, Maryland
and New Jersey have encouraged hunters to shoot does instead of bucks. But
even sharpshooters do not usually enter densely packed neighborhoods to
hunt deer. All those fertilized suburban lawns, luscious azaleas and
kitchen gardens packed with sweet corn have bolstered deer populations.
...
Animal rights activists, like Nancy Bowman, the president of the Mercer
County Deer Alliance, a coalition with 1,500 members, voiced their outrage
and filed lawsuits.

"It's morally and ethically bankrupt," Bowman said this week. "And it's
not necessary." Bowman says that deer are not destroying the habitat. 
...
Animal rights groups say there are other ways to protect the gardens. "We
suggested relocating the deer and doing a contraception program," said
Stephanie Boyles, a wildlife biologist for PETA, People for the Ethical
Treatment of Animals. "Killing the ones inside doesn't solve the problem,
because more will just move in to take their place."

By lengthening the hunting season and encouraging more doe hunting,
Maryland now kills about 100,000 deer a year, but that has only stabilized
the deer population. Managed hunts reduce deer in the immediate vicinity,
but the problem continues to grow as suburbs expand. </content>

</doc>
