<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 12:38:10 2003</date>
  <content>
A Stratford farm opened its doors Saturday to friends, neighbors and a state 
official to demonstrate the inner workings of a modern dairy farm, as well 
as to discuss the future of Wisconsin agriculture. At Maple Ridge Dairy 
Inc., Rod Nilsestuen, secretary of the state Department of Agriculture, 
Trade and Consumer Protection, spoke about bolstering Wisconsin's 
agricultural sector through a cooperation of governments, businesses and 
individual farmers. "As we look as a state in attracting and building new 
industries, we must remember what has already made a great impact," 
Nilsestuen said. "We need to make agriculture, both for the farmer and the 
state, profitable and sustainable in the long term."

The state of agriculture has changed dramatically. In 1978, 43,500 dairy 
farmers worked throughout Wisconsin, but now that number is down to 16,500 
due to retirement and stress of the industry, he said. To give the 
agriculture sector a boost, the state must unify its siting regulations, an 
issue that has pitted farmers against citizens at large, especially 
environmentalists, Nilsestuen said. "Minnesota had what was almost like a 
civil war between agriculture and environmentalists," he said. "We can't 
afford years of duking it out on the issue." The cost could be staggering, 
with a $40 billion agriculture and food industry depending on $30 billion 
from dairy and livestock, he said.

Nilsestuen said he had formed a committee of county and town officials and 
environmental groups to discuss scientifically based environmental 
standards, making siting a more predictable and transparent process that can 
still have local control. "I don't think state preemption will come out of 
this," he said. "We have to have balance."

Many of the problems in agriculture can be traced to a population shift, 
said Patrick Geoghegan, vice president of Wisconsin Milk Marketing Board. 
"We're seeing more urbanites who have lost a connection with agriculture," 
he said. "If we are to remain America's Dairyland, we must evolve as an 
industry." The process can begin by working with neighbors and showing them 
how the industry works, such as through events like the open house, he said.

</content>

</doc>
