<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed May 19 15:54:03 2004</date>
  <content>
"Joe was my first working cow horse and he was awesome. I sold him when he 
was 22 and every time I saddle up to work cattle I think about how much I miss 
him. One of my fondest memories was returning home to a message on the 
answering machine that my bull was out with a neighbor's cows. 
I rode the 640-acre pasture, sorted the bull from 150 cow/calf pairs and 
drove him a half-mile home within 45 minutes. Riding a horse that knows how, where 
and when to work cattle is a feeling that is hard to describe but wonderful 
to experience. 
I clearly recall my final months with Joe. I was reluctant to part company 
with him. In the final year, I didn't dare saddle him because of the stiffness 
in his legs. Age and dedication to his mission had taken their toll on him. 
I finally bit the bullet and sold him for a whopping $280. (Apparently and 
proudly to the slaughter plant)...Most importantly, no one is mandating how your 
horse leaves this life so why should you tell me how mine should be allowed 
to die?"
So, let me see if I understand you, Mr. Loos. Joe was an awesome horse. You 
loved him enough not to try to ride him the last year because he was too stiff 
and sore. In addition, you acknowledge that he had worn himself out dedicating 
himself to the mission of supporting you. Therefore, in gratitude, you sold 
that poor, pain-filled horse for a "whopping $280" to a killer buyer. 
Your horse got forced up a slippery metal ramp into the bowels of a 
double-decker truck and had to crouch on stiff, pain-racked legs, crammed in with other 
horses on a long, thirsty ride to a slaughter plant and off-loaded in agony. 
Looking for you, he saw only strangers that forced him down a chute into a 
box and left him swaying on those same, stiff legs until they shot a bolt into 
his head enough times for him to fall down and wait to be hoisted by a leg and 
have his throat slit. 
The only thing I can say is that I'm sure glad you don't love me! Your 
sentence about "Horses, like man, will die and death with a purpose gives full 
meaning to life", scares me half to death. I'd hate to be your worn out mother, 
grown old in dedication to my mission of raising you. 
</content>

</doc>
