<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan  5 14:40:26 2004</date>
  <content>

Just the name "mad cow" disease is enough to inspire alarm, and its 
scientific appellation isn't any more comforting: bovine spongiform 
encephalopathy. Humans who eat infected meat may suffer from a form of the 
illness called variant Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease, a brain-wasting affliction 
that, as David Plotz memorably put it several years ago, "murders by driving 
its young victims insane, then melting their brains." The illness is 
horrible, made even creepier by its long incubation (five years or more) and 
the lack of any cure. It was all but inevitable that the discovery just 
before Christmas of a single cow in my home state, Washington, that tested 
positive for BSE would send the nation into panic mode.

But as a few journalists have pointed out, the U.S. is hardly on the verge 
of an epidemic, and the odds are good that over the next 10 years hardly a 
soul will contract the cow-transmitted form of Creutzfeldt-Jakob. Even in 
Great Britain, where thousands of BSE-affected cattle entered the food 
supply eight years ago, only about 140 people have died from it. That's too 
many, of course, but it's a minuscule number compared to flu-related deaths 
(3,000 to 4,000 a year in England) or fatal auto accidents (about 3,500 
annually). Here in the United States, food-borne illnesses of all types 
cause 5,000 deaths a year—a number not likely to change a whit due to mad 
cow.

In fact, mad cow disease in the United States may be the best thing to 
happen to the U.S. food industry and consumers since the invention of 
refrigeration. It's entirely possible that as a result of the current panic, 
in 10 years we'll not only look back and find next to no cases of mad cow in 
humans, but also look around at a better, healthier food supply. Perhaps 
we'll even have whittled down that appalling deaths-from-bad-food figure. 
</content>

</doc>
