<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 12 06:28:20 2004</date>
  <content>
Below the drumbeat of reassurances from government and the cattle industry
that mad cow disease poses no threat to public health, a small universe of
scientists working on a family of related illnesses are finding disturbing
evidence to the contrary.

Several little-publicized studies, as well as ongoing research at a
government laboratory in Montana, continue to spark questions about human
susceptibility not only to mad cow, but to sister diseases such as chronic
wasting disease that mainly affects deer and elk, and to scrapie, which
infects sheep. 
...
For that matter, some say, it's possible that CWD, endemic in Colorado's
wild deer and elk, has also sickened and proven fatal to humans, but
doctor's haven't - or can't - yet recognize signs of the disease during an
autopsy.

Little of this research, nor the wary comments of researchers toiling in
relative obscurity, reaches a broad public audience, leaving most people
to hear the oft-repeated promises of well-funded interest groups or
high-profile public officials.

Just last week, for example, the National Cattlemen's Beef Association
described mad cow disease solely as an animal and economic problem - not a
human health problem. The U.S. Department of Agriculture and Colorado's
own commissioner of agriculture have made similar pronouncements. 
...
The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention wasn't initially
interested in the cluster, but since the discovery of the case of mad cow
in Washington state the agency is taking another look at the case,
according to The Inquirer.

CJD may be underreported

Even so, experts caution that clusters can also be coincidences. Rare
diseases don't always end up geographically spread out. 
...
Misdiagnosis of Alzheimer's

If one considers that Alzheimer's disease kills some 50,000 Americans a
year, then the true number of CJD cases is probably more than the
conventional estimate of 200 to 300 cases a year, but more like 500 to
5,000 cases if one considers the range of misdiagnosed Alzheimer's cases. 
...
"Could BSE have been transmitted to people in the U.S. but gone
unrecognized because it looked like (classical) CJD?" Bosque said. "I
suppose it is possible, but there would be no obvious explanation for the
fact that (new variant) CJD has not been seen in the U.S."
...
Bosque, the Denver neurologist, said the ability for TSEs to hide inside
some animals and increase their infectivity is worrisome.

"It raises an additional level of concern, that these prions can persist
in animals, and increase, even though (the animals) don't appear sick,"
Bosque said. "For one thing, it shows you that screening for just
obviously sick animals may not be sufficient."

But currently, the United States focuses its testing almost solely on sick
or "downer" animals. Industry officials have said testing every cow for
mad cow disease as Japan does would be a waste of time and money. </content>

</doc>
