<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Feb 14 15:08:43 2004</date>
  <content>
The gorillas need a stag film. 
The lesser flamingos prefer mirrors and showy neighbors. 
The lions, well, they don't require any help at all. 
At the Fort Worth Zoo, animals perform their mating rituals free of the 
romanticism and bad poetry of Valentine's Day. 
The often-mysterious whoopee-making activities of the 435 species at the zoo 
offer a fascinating study of behavior. But the subject is more than a 
curiosity for the keepers and curators, who use breeding to maintain the captive 
population, and in some cases, to act as a hedge against extinction. 
And while old-fashioned animal instinct is a powerful thing, it doesn't 
always lead to a lucky evening. 
Sometimes the keepers must intervene to help nature run its course. In some 
areas of the zoo, however, unchecked randiness has led to a different kind of 
intervention. 
Reproduction is "one of the most interesting parts of biology," said Robert 
Wiese, the zoo's director of animal collections. 
The zoo, along with most other major U.S. zoos, maintains a complex set of 
genealogical records on its animals, particularly on its 39 endangered or 
threatened species. 
It is Wiese's job to cull through the stud books to find mates for animals 
from jaguars and mountain bongos to rhinoceroses and elephants. He tries to keep 
the gene pool as broad as possible by matching animals that are the most 
unrelated genetically. 
"It's almost the opposite of domesticated animals," he said. "Where they're 
trying to breed faster thoroughbreds or more milk production from cows, we try 
not to select for anything." 
But nature is anything but uniform in its approach to reproduction, and so 
the curators and keepers at the zoo must think creatively to satisfy each 
animal. 
Some need space, some need privacy, some need to hibernate, some need a cold 
shower. Sometimes, the keepers just need to make sure they are putting the 
right pair together. </content>

</doc>
