<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul 14 16:45:16 2003</date>
  <content>
With the release in May of a 111-page document by the New Jersey
Department of Agriculture, "Humane Treatment of Domestic Livestock,
Proposed New Rules," the state has unleashed a small storm, pitting
animal-rights supporters and their notable spokespeople, including actress
Mary Tyler Moore, against large New Jersey farmers and livestock-industry
representatives from neighboring states.

The clatter is unusual for agricultural rules, which usually concern more
quiet matters, such as dairy licensing fees or proper apple storage. The
humane farming issue, in contrast, has turned New Jersey, the first state
to consider such rules, into something of an animal-rights battleground,
coming amid heightened concerns nationally about the treatment of farm
animals.

A number of cities across the country, from Newark to Cocoa Beach, Fla.,
to Berkeley, Calif., have adopted official proclamations on the humane
treatment of "sentient beings." And a handful of fast-food producers,
including McDonald's, Burger King, and Wendy's, have begun financing
research into what makes livestock happy.
...
Animal supporters say the "humane" rules are anything but. In fact, they
say, the rules would protect big farmers, not animals.

Lifted in part from industry guidelines, the rules would, for example,
permit calves raised for veal to be kept crated, chained, and without
bedding until slaughter.

Pregnant pigs could continue to live in "gestation crates,"
2-foot-by-7-foot metal cages that don't allow the sows to turn around, a
practice outlawed by voters in Florida last year and by several European
countries.

Laying hens could live in "battery cages" - small wire-mesh pens where
four or more chickens are confined.

And "forced molting," the practice of depriving hens of food for up to 14
days to induce a new cycle of egg-laying, could also continue under the rules.

"The word 'humane' is in there and these standards are not humane at all,"
said Barbara Dyer, program coordinator for the mid-Atlantic office of the
Humane Society of the United States, in Mount Olive. "It looked like this
was going to improve conditions for livestock, and it actually does the
reverse. I think this is misleading the people of New Jersey."

</content>

</doc>
