<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 25 07:13:30 2004</date>
  <content>
The nonprofit Center for a New American Dream, whose stated mission is to 
"help Americans consume responsibly to protect the environment, enhance quality 
of life and promote social justice," says that America's growing obsession with 
acquisition is taking a heavy toll on the environment. 
According to the group's president, Betsy Taylor, the U.S. consumes more 
energy, water, paper, steel and meat per capita than any other country -- so much 
so that at least four additional planets would be needed to provide the 
American lifestyle if every person on Earth were to demand it. Meanwhile, forests 
are being lost at an alarming rate, farmlands and wetlands are being engulfed by 
development, plant and animal species are disappearing and our air and water 
continue to be threatened by pollution. 
Participants of New Dream's Web-based Turn the Tide program follow "nine 
little actions" to try to reduce their personal impact on the environment, 
including skipping car trips, eating one less beef meal a week, reducing water use 
and installing energy-efficient light bulbs. The program enables participants to 
track the positive impact of their actions -- and see the cumulative impact 
of all he program's participants across North America. 
CONTACT: Center for a New American Dream, (301) 891-3683, www.newdream.org. 
Dear EarthTalk: I've heard that conventional lice treatments contain toxic 
chemicals. Are safer, more natural alternatives available? 
-- Dwayne Newton, Charleston, S.C. 
The National Pediculosis Association (NPA) advises consumers to be cautious 
with conventional lice treatments, including shampoos and lotions, since they 
contain toxic, and in some cases carcinogenic, pesticides. 
The NPA says that people with epilepsy, asthma, brain tumors, cancer or AIDS, 
as well as pregnant or nursing women, should completely avoid any chemical 
lice medications. Further, the NPA is calling on the medical community to 
address the current "resistance crisis" of lice becoming increasingly resistant to 
pesticide treatments. </content>

</doc>
