<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:42:48 2003</date>
  <content>
Our cat Buffett just returned from a trip to the veterinarian's. He had a 
good time in the car looking out the window, with his leg on the arm rest, on the 
trip to the clinic. Buffett enjoys his car rides, no matter where they end 
up. This isn't true for most cats. 
How often does your cat ride in the car? Most cat car rides end at the 
veterinarian's, groomer's or kennel - not destinations most cats look forward to. 
This can cause your cat to dislike car rides, or even being in a carrier, 
because these experiences are associated with unpleasant outcomes. Your cat may 
disappear when she sees the carrier, or become a demon cat if you try to put her 
in the car. 
To overcome these problems, give your cat small doses of carriers and cars, 
paired with good things. Put the carrier in the family room with a few pieces 
of tuna or other irresistible treats inside. 
Don't be surprised if it takes your cat a while to decide it's safe to 
approach this dreaded object. After she's going inside on her own to retrieve the 
tuna, put a few more tidbits in and close the door for maybe 30 seconds. 
Repeat this process many times, gradually increasing how long you keep the 
door closed. But don't close your cat in the crate every time she goes in - try 
every third time. 
Once your cat will tolerate her carrier for 15 minutes or so, follow a 
similar procedure for the car. With treats, a favorite toy or catnip in the carrier, 
put her in the car, drive around the block and come home. 
You can ultimately extend this approach to taking her to the veterinary 
clinic, groomer's or kennel for nothing more than positive greeting experiences. 
These kinds of desensitization procedures work best if your cat doesn't have any 
bad experiences with the carrier or car during the process. 
Even better is to prevent problems by starting these procedures as soon as 
you acquire a new cat or kitten. Many problems - including fights between cats, 
destructive scratching and not using the litter box - can be prevented with 
the right approach. 
</content>

</doc>
