<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Nov 26 13:26:24 2003</date>
  <content>
The turkey exploded when I stuck it with the serving fork. My Aunt Rita,
who has a bad valve in her heart, dove under the table, clutching her
blood-thinning pills, as boiling-hot soy-wasabi magma sauce sprayed across
the room.

"It's not so bad!" said my wife, Roni. Our Thanksgiving guests nodded
politely at her Pollyannaish reaction and held their noses as the
sulfurous smell of scorched seitan filled the kitchen. Burning, gassy
blobs of cranberry-tofu stuffing pockmarked the chairs, table, and linens.
(I took rounds in the chest, but was protected by my polyester-blend
shirt.) The label of the cheap South African zinfandel my Dad bought
peeled off and slid into the faux chicken pate, creating a
burning-oil-slick texture in the curiously untouched chafing dish. The
sweet-and-sour soy meatballs sat in small round heaps, also untouched,
like leftover ordnance.

The kids pretended to be wounded by soy shrapnel and draped themselves in
dying poses across the furniture. Last year was our first vegetarian
Thanksgiving, and both the Pilgrims and the Indians were unhappy.
...
"I saw something on CNN about fake boobs collapsing," said my Dad.
Although this non sequitur was inappropriate, given the presence of A. and
our five-year-old triplets, he did hit upon a strange cultural synthesis
between fake meat, the fixation on female breasts, and the bland, dry,
genetically mutated turkeys that dominate our holidays. What was it about
breasts, real or pretend, that crossed so many cultural boundaries?

The pseudo turkey was a noble experiment that veered out of control.
...
So the vegetarian Thanksgiving was Roni's attempt to demonstrate our pride
in A.'s quiet commitment to not eating murdered meals. Unfortunately, like
most heroic examples, his was impractical given the context of crazed
holiday expectations. Even I craved a slice of dry, throat-catching
turkey, covered in dark gravy cooked from animal bits best left to scavengers.

This year, Roni is cooking a 20-pound organic turkey, chicken-liver pate,
and sausage stuffing. A. and our vegetarian city friends will dine on a
brand-new product, Tofurkey. It actually looks tasty. That's the curious
thing about our culture ? the fake often replaces the real.

--</content>

</doc>
