<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Aug 11 13:16:44 2003</date>
  <content>


DNA fingers the dog, but did she murder the chickens? 

It wasn't the island's most gruesome crime: Similar massacres have occurred in 
the past. But for a few weeks on Martha's Vineyard this summer as rumors 
swirled and accusations flew, it seemed the whole island was obsessed by the 
question: Who killed Mal Jones' chickens? Partly it was the horrific nature of the 
crime body parts and feathers strewn all over the bloodied coop. Partly it was 
the accused. Sabrina, a beautiful 2?-year-old malamute-collie mix has a 
silvery tan coat and deep brown eyes that radiate friendliness, not murderous 
intent. But mainly the crime grabbed attention because for the first time, in these 
parts anyway, DNA was used by the prosecution to implicate a dog. Hair from 
the coop matched that of Sabrina. But was that enough to convict her of the 
alleged murder of seven chickens a crime punishable by death for dogs in these 
parts? 

Magid offered to settle the matter by paying for the chickens viewing it 
as a form of compensation for the trouble Sabrina's family had caused in the 
past. But she refused to pay the $400 DNA bill, saying circumstantial evidence 
did not make Sabrina a killer. Selectmen meetings are held in an old gray 
clapboard building and are generally relaxed and friendly: The secretary passes 
around raspberry and lemon tarts before they begin. But even the tarts couldn't 
mask the tension on July 16. Inside, Jones and his daughter sat grimly on the 
public bench. Outside Sabrina dozed in her owner's van, awaiting her fate. 
Aggressive animal complaints are among the most difficult issues to come before 
the board, whose members own dogs and chickens themselves. ''The dog cannot 
defend itself, and owners never want to believe their pets are vicious,'' said 
John Early, chairman of the Board of Selectmen. ''So it really boils down to us 
making a life-or-death decision.'' In Sabrina's case, they voted 2-1 for life 
at least for now. It seemed an audible sigh of relief swept the room. The board 
simply approved Jenkinson's recommendation that Magid pay a $200 bond to be 
returned after a year if Sabrina doesn't get into trouble again. Magid also 
wrote Jones a check for $375 covering half the DNA testing and $25 per chicken. 
And Sabrina was given a stern warning: Any more chicken attacks and she would 
meet the same fate as Betty Blue. She was also slapped with a lifetime 
restraining order. Meaning, of course, she must be leashed at all times. 
    

</content>

</doc>
