<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep  1 18:18:58 2003</date>
  <content>
The latest front in a global campaign being waged by radical animal
rights activists is a small Sonoma bistro where the spray-painted
word "torture" was being erased last week, replaced with the painted
image of an olive branch.

The peace symbol was a planned motif for Sonoma Saveurs even before
activists broke in and vandalized the restaurant two weeks ago,
stalling its opening. But the painting also could be seen as an act
of defiance.

Sides are being taken in the most unlikely of settings over foie
gras, a duck-liver delicacy that the restaurant's owners vow to serve
when they repair the damage and open, despite counter-promises from
activists to never let that happen.

Over the restaurant's front door where vandals spray-painted the word
"Stop," the owners hung a sign boldly declaring "Coming Soon!" and
the image of a duck.

"We don't want to create a big fight with these people," said
co-owner Didier Jaubert, whose home in Santa Rosa also was
vandalized. "We just tell them we respect what you want to eat, just
respect what we want to serve."
...
Victims' names on Internet

Activists who consider the process barbaric targeted Jaubert and
Manrique at home before focusing on their restaurant. In one
instance, vandals left behind a surreptitious videotape of Manrique's
family at his Mill Valley home.

The names, addresses and phone numbers of the victims also were
posted on the Internet.

Targeting people at home is a tactic more commonly used by animal
rights groups in Europe and on the East Coast but is now being used
here, Smiley said.

The cars and homes of some employees of Chiron Corp., a
pharmaceutical company, were targeted before two bombs went off
Thursday outside its Emeryville offices.

A radical animal rights group claimed responsibility for that attack,
and Smiley said it was the first time that he could recall where an
actual explosive device was used.

"It's a trend that is beginning to be frightening," Smiley said.


</content>

</doc>
