<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Aug 22 14:53:05 2003</date>
  <content>
WORLD ANIMAL DAY

We are planning a blessing of the animals celebration of World 
Animal Day, Saturday 4th October, in St Leonards Park, corner of 
Miller and Falcon Streets, North Sydney, from 11am to 3.30pm.

Rev Bill Crews of the Ashfield Uniting Church is most 
enthusiastic about joining Father Dan Donovan in officiating.

We'll make a day of it, with kindred groups holding information 
stalls and vegan food available.

Final details will be available in a week or so. Please ring the 
office (02) 9264 3222 or email sydneyhq@animal-lib.org.au for 
enquiries.

- - -

To also mark World Animal Day, we are holding stalls at 20 
railway stations on the City Rail Network on Friday 3 October, 
7am to 7pm. If you can help at whichever station is convenient for 
you, if only for an hour or so, it will be much appreciated. These 
venues are free and this opportunity for 'outreach' to hundreds, if 
not thousands of commuters comes only once a year.


- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -

STATEMENT FROM THE SAVE WILD ELEPHANTS COALITION

U.S. ZOOS WIN - BUT WILD ELEPHANTS LOSE

Appeals Court declines to stop shipment of young African 
elephants from Swaziland elephants taken from wild to be 
confined to small enclosures forever.

(Washington, DC) - Today the United States District Court of 
Appeals denied an emergency appeal for a temporary stay to 
prevent the San Diego Zoo and Lowry Park Zoo of Tampa, FL 
from immediately importing eleven wild African elephants from 
their homes in Swaziland. The members of the Save Wild 
Elephants Coalition, including Born Free USA, Born Free 
Foundation, The Elephant Alliance, the Elephant Sanctuary, In 
Defense of Animals, Animal Protection Institute, People for the 
Ethical Treatment of Animals and the Animal Welfare Institute, 
San Diego Animal Advocates, Animal Legal Defense Fund, and 
others are saddened by the fate that awaits the young elephants, 
two of whom are pregnant. The elephants will be taken from their 
home in Swaziland, where they have lived on more than 7,000 
acres and will now be confined to 2-2.5 acre lots in San Diego 
and Tampa.

This importation sets a dangerous precedent and opens the 
floodgates for the importation of threatened species that are 
protected by national and international laws and treaties. 
Leading wild African elephant researchers and habitat experts, 
including Cynthia Moss, Joyce Poole, Keith Lindsey and others, 
have condemned the import of these elephants - highlighting the 
devastating consequences this import will have on the individual 
elephants, on those left behind in Swaziland, and on African 
elephants in general</content>

</doc>
