<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Apr  4 12:03:06 2004</date>
  <content>
A dark-haired girl in a Harry Potter T-shirt sits at the dinner table
staring at those around her. The two adults at the table gobble down their
chicken and beef broth while the smallest child haphazardly attempts to
place bits of hot dog in his mouth.

The girl looks upon the spectacle in disgust, wondering how they consume
the bodies of the tortured souls in such relish. She looks down at her
plate of yams, green beans and pasta, and a smile creeps across her face.

The above excerpt explains a typical meal of mine. I've been a devoted
vegetarian for more than two years now, and I could never imagine going back.

My choice to become a vegetarian was first influenced by my affinity for
animals. I didn't understand why we had to eat them when there was such a
wide variety of other food choices. I've never had a real taste for meat;
the only meats I ever really liked were my grandma's fried chicken and the
quick and easy hot dog. My fate was sealed when I became aware of where
the meat was actually coming from and the many healthy benefits of
vegetarianism.
...
Protein and vitamin B12 must be implemented into a normal eating schedule.
I find the task of eating well to be relatively easy. Just as someone on a
normal diet should eat accordingly, a vegetarian should also. The only
difference is that food choices don't include meat, so other levels of the
food pyramid are substituted.

The tallest hurdle for me to overcome is protein, but it's still not
difficult. Vegetarians can still eat dairy products, so milk and cheese
supply protein. Or if you (like myself) are pursuing veganism (consumption
of no meat or animal byproducts), soy and tofu are valuable resources.
Soymilk is actually quite tasty and shelters me from the rank taste and
smell of cow milk. Soymilk can be easily substituted into recipes calling
for cow milk without a noticeable difference. Smart dogs or veggie burgers
(both composed of soy) are wonderful for a five-minute meal.
</content>

</doc>
