<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 20 12:37:41 2003</date>
  <content>
How long have you been working with PETA? What are its objectives? 
I've been with PETA for four years. PETA was founded over 20 years ago by 
Ingrid Newkirk, and our headquarters are in Norfolk, Va. We have 750,000-plus 
members -- we're the largest animal rights group in the world. PETA believes that 
animals are not ours to eat, to wear, to experiment on or to use for 
entertainment. The underlying goal of PETA is to encourage people to be vegetarian. We 
work to improve the conditions of animals that are used for food, but, 
ultimately, we believe that animals should not be food. 
How long have you been a vegetarian? 
I've been vegetarian for 13 years and vegan for five years. I quit eating 
meat when I was 16 -- that was the year that we did animal dissection in my high 
school biology class in New Jersey. The dead animals were getting bigger and 
bigger, from earthworms to frogs, and, finally, the teacher brought out a fetal 
pig. That night, my mom served ham for dinner, and I was completely repulsed. 
I started reading "Animal Liberation," by Peter Singer, and his arguments 
supported my gut feeling that eating animals was not right. 
What are your specific duties as national campaign coordinator for PETA? 
I work primarily on the antifur campaign. Our most recent action took place 
in New York City, on opening night at the Metropolitan Opera. People 
traditionally show their fur coats at this event, so we had 15 activists there who were 
holding the bloody carcasses of skinned foxes, and signs that said, "Here's 
the rest of your fur coat." I love these kinds of demonstrations -- actions that 
are shocking but appropriate. The point we're trying to make is that each fox 
coat generates 40 fox carcasses. 
Last winter, we also did a fur protest in Park City, Utah. We showed up at 
the Freestyle World Championship wearing just ski caps and skis, carrying signs 
that said, "We'd Rather Ski Naked Than Wear Fur." 
I imagine that you and other PETA activists get tons of attention when you 
don't have much on. 
Yes. That's why we do it: to get media attention for PETA's causes. I didn't 
like standing outside naked in 30-degree weather -- it's absolutely crazy! But 
we did it for the animals. 
Tell me about your Lettuce Lady costume. Did you design it? 
I didn't invent the costume. I am just one of many who have donned the 
Lettuce Lady costume for PETA. Our most recent Lettuce Lady is Pamela Anderson, who 
appears in the lettuce bikini in PETA's newest ad, to promote vegetarianism. I 
wore the lettuce costume in Singapore, in PETA's first-ever demonstration in 
that country, and I wore it on a tour through Croatia. I also wore lettuce in 
South Africa, in Johannesburg at the World Summit on Sustainable Development 
in 2002 and also in Cape Town. So, maybe, I have worn it 10 times. 
Lettuce Ladies hand out samples of delicious vegetarian food to show people 
that going vegetarian is not just good for the animals and good for your 
health, it's also good for your taste buds. Our mission is to encourage everyone to 
turn over a new leaf and go vegetarian. 
What about the Tiger Lady and Leopard Lady costumes? 
I didn't invent those costumes, either -- many others have preceded me! But I 
have stripped down to my leopard spots or tiger stripes to protest fur for 
PETA 50 times or so. 
Have you done Bay Area antifur actions? 
Yes. Last January, a friend and I painted ourselves like Leopard Ladies, and 
we skated around the Kristi Yamaguchi Ice Rink in Justin Herman Plaza in San 
Francisco. We carried a banner that said, "We'd Rather Bare Skin Than Wear 
Skin" until security kicked us out. 
We give our local activists printed materials that they can give to people 
who are wearing fur, like this. (She hands me three cards with various messages: 
"Fur Hurts!" "Whose Skin Are You In?" and "I Wear Fur; I'm an A**hole.") We 
want to create a situation where people are uncomfortable going outside in furs 
because they might be accosted, because they should be. 
San Francisco is not one of the furriest cities in the U.S.A. -- New York, 
Chicago, Philadelphia, Boston and Washington, D.C., are. But last year, it was 
noted in The Chronicle that opening night at the San Francisco Ballet, in early 
February, was a "furry" event. The symphony and the opera are also 
hoity-toity events where people who have furs might wear them, so I am thinking that 
this year, those places might be good places to show up with our little fox 
carcasses. I don't mind telling you this now, because we want people to know in 
advance that if they wear their fur there, they'll be confronted by people who 
are speaking up for the animals. 
Is there any connection between PETA activists and the Revolutionary Cells 
Animal Liberation Brigade, which recently bombed Chiron in Emeryville and 
Shaklee in Pleasanton? 
There's no connection between PETA and the Revolutionary Cells Animal 
Liberation Brigade, or with the Animal Liberation Front. We have no official stance 
on their activities, because they have nothing to do with us. We advocate going 
to any legal means to stop animal abuse, and we engage in civil disobedience, 
but PETA does not engage in violent activities. 
What about the recent foie gras incident, where the chef of Aqua Restaurant 
was threatened and his car, home and shop were vandalized because he's involved 
in foie gras production? Does PETA have a stance on that? 
That was also not a PETA activity, but PETA did do an undercover 
investigation at a New York foie gras farm. We saw an inflexible tube shoved down the 
throats of ducks and geese to force feed them a huge amount of grain. It was the 
equivalent of force feeding a human 20 pounds of spaghetti. They do this for 
several weeks. It causes a disease that makes the birds' liver enlarge. We got 
footage of punctured throats and esophagi, and the birds could no longer walk 
because they were so fat -- plus, they were injured because they had resisted 
the handling. Foie gras production is illegal in many countries -- it was just 
banned in Israel. 
Besides antifur demonstrations, what other activities is PETA involved in? 
We had a recent week of action against KFC, from Sept. 27 to Oct. 5. We 
showed footage of their slaughterhouse, and we handed out leaflets at two KFCs in 
San Francisco's Mission District. KFC is the largest purchaser of chicken 
carcasses in the world, and we want them to tell their slaughterhouses to eliminate 
the worst abuses that happen there. PETA has been protesting fast-food 
corporations for a while. We started against McDonald's, and they agreed to our 
terms after several months of aggressive campaigning. Then we had successful 
campaigns against Burger King and Wendy's. 
We also have an antidairy campaign. We do billboards a lot, with slogans like 
"Milk Is for Babies." 
Oh. 
(We both stare at the Thai iced tea I'm drinking. It has milk in it.) 
We also have billboards that say, "Got Pus? Milk Does," based on studies 
reporting on the percentage of pus and other contaminants in a glass of milk. 
Oh. Ick. Huh. 
Humans are the only species that drinks another animal's milk. It's surreal 
that we do that. 
Lisa, does PETA have a huge antihunting campaign? 
We have an antihunting campaign, but it's not one of our biggest priorities. 
The small number of animals that are killed by hunters each year is extremely 
insignificant compared to the 40 billion animals raised and slaughtered 
annually for human consumption. Plus, animals killed by hunters had lives that were 
far better than those of domesticated animals that suffered in confinement on 
factory farms, deprived of any natural behavior. It's also very hypocritical 
for people to say hunting is immoral and then go to the supermarket and stock 
up on meat. Those people just don't want the blood on their own hands. 
You have done a lot of protest actions. How many? 
Between 50 and 100. It's my full-time job. I have traveled around the world 
doing different fur actions. Last summer, I was in Moscow for a while, 
protesting a fur convention there. I sat in a cage wearing a full-length fur cape, 
with a sign saying "Summer Is No Vacation for Animals on Fur Farms." I also went 
to Athens, Budapest, Prague. Last March, I went to Hong Kong and Tokyo. In the 
United States, I have been to New York, Chicago, Miami, San Diego, Los 
Angeles, Huntsville [Ala.], Dayton [Ohio], Augusta [Ga.], Detroit, Dallas, Houston, 
Austin -- all over. 
Have you ever been arrested? 
Yes, three times. My first arrest was at Saks Fifth Avenue in San Francisco 
three years ago. The designer Michael Kors was having a trunk show, showing off 
his new collection, and he uses a lot of fur. So, I went with a big bag of 
play money that was painted red to look bloody. I poured it on his head and I 
said, "Here's your bloody money, you fur pimp." I was arrested and charged with 
disruption of business, but the charges were dropped. I think technically I'm 
never supposed to go back to Saks ever again. 
My second arrest was in Las Vegas at a fur protest. I was dressed as the 
Leopard Lady, wearing just panties and pasties, and they took me to jail. Of all 
places -- it's bizarre to get arrested in Las Vegas for indecent exposure! 
The third arrest was last winter in Boston at a fur protest at Macy's. We 
were wearing fur coats with actual leghold traps dangling off of them. We covered 
ourselves in red paint, we writhed on the sidewalk, then we crawled over and 
painted the front door red. I was arrested and given a sentence of 30 hours of 
community service that I am completing with the SF/SPCA. 
Your job sounds fun. Do you enjoy planning your protest acts? 
Yes, it's very creative. We have weekly brainstorming meetings to express our 
ideas for demonstrations. This country was founded on acts of civil 
disobedience, and there's a proud history of it in many movements: women's rights, 
civil rights. 
Do bystanders get angry at you at your demonstrations? 
Oh, yes. Once in while, people get defensive: I've been called a few obscene 
names that you can't reprint in the paper. I even found a Web page that was 
titled "Lisa Franzetta Is a F**ing Moron." Anyone who is a public face for PETA 
gets flak like this from our adversaries. When people are profiting from 
animal abuse, it is not surprising that they will sink pretty low to try to defend 
themselves. 
Do your parents worry? Do they like the PETA activities that you do? 
My parents are animal lovers, and I think they are proud of me, but I'd be 
lying if I said they didn't wish it was someone else's daughter who ended up 
sitting in a Boston jail covered in red paint on a cold December morning. But 
they agree with me that ending animal abuse is valuable work. 

</content>

</doc>
