<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Oct 10 07:13:10 2003</date>
  <content>

FAIRHAVEN -- Anita Hawkins' bloody reign on Main Street began about three
years ago, when the trim and tan sophisticate was 75 years old.

A neighbor left bread out for neighborhood squirrels, setting off an invasion.

Soon, there were great hordes of the gray-furred rodents, said Mrs.
Hawkins, marauding gangs of squirrels who scampered over her garage,
leaped into her yard, robbed her bird feeders and clawed along the very
walls of the Thomas Delano House -- circa 1790 -- which she has called
home for more than a decade when she and her husband are not at their
other residence on the island of St. Thomas.

And so she began to kill them.

She set traps for them -- Havahart brand traps -- and caught them by the
hundreds.

Then she drowned them in a green plastic trash barrel out back she had
filled with water for that very purpose.

"It snuffs them right out," she declared of the water treatment. "I called
an exterminator and that's what they say they do. They call it 'teaching
them to swim.'"

She bought a pair of Daisy air rifle pellet guns and soon she became an
enviable shot. She dispatched squirrels with shots through the bars of her
traps and she has potted them in her small back yard. 
...
Yesterday, the national animal rights organization People for the Ethical
Treatment of Animals (PETA) wrote a letter urging the Fairhaven police to
charge Mrs. Hawkins with animal cruelty.

"There's nothing in the law to prevent her from killing an animal that's a
threat to her property," conceded PETA wildlife biologist Stephanie
Boyles. "But that's clearly not why she's doing it. She's doing it for
fun. The body count is just way too high."

Her preferred method of killing -- drowning -- is inhumane, claims PETA,
and results in a slow, agonizing death for the animals. Also, BB guns
often only wound animals, leaving them to die over time.

Police Chief Gary Souza could not be reached for comment yesterday. But
police are aware of the situation and have been called on at least two
occasions to broker truces between Mrs. Hawkins and her next-door
neighbors over the squirrel issue. 

--</content>

</doc>
