<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr 19 12:00:39 2004</date>
  <content>
This is sort of an 'off-schedule'' posting, but I recieved a call over
the weekend to inquire more about this endeavor that has come from my
eager and innovative participants of the new coalition which was
originally formed in October of 2003.
Now, with a new platform but still actively promoting humane education
as a group,  our latest idea is garnering some substantial discussion
and interest among some heavy hitters.  Far out as it seems, it may
just be a workable plan.
 
Here's the idea in it's condensed version.  Please voice your opinions
and thoughts or offers to get involved.
 
$50 Million will change the face of education and civilization forever.

A one-time expenditure of $50 million would bring humane education to
our nations' schools

Due to the fact that I am not only proposing a philosophical conceptual
framework regarding the effectiveness of Humane Education, but I am
also a practitioner applying my theory within practical contexts, I
consider myself an action researcher. In other words, I don’t only
provide the rationale and philosophical underpinnings of my work, I
actually go out there and apply it hands on. Furthermore, I am
collaborating with professional researchers who are capable of taking
my findings (i.e. data) and analyzing and interpreting those findings
(i.e. scientifically based research).

Although Americans have been donating a billion dollars annually to
their favorite animal protection group (that's AFTER the nearly one
billion they also pay in taxes for local and area animal control
efforts) for over 25 years, we still see few tangible results. I am so
determined to prove that my idea is a likely solution to many if not
most of our problems, that I have outlined it to the best of my
ability. We may need to include in this budget the cost for
professional research to offer the educators, who don't care about
humane education but do care about science, math and reading test
scores, that our program can improve all of the above.

So, with $2 billion each year going mainly to salaries, condos, jet
planes, office buildings and printing costs to raise more funds for
next year, I'm asking for just $50 million on a one time basis to start
this idea rolling on a  nationwide scale that will undoubtedly prove
its cause worthy. However, thus far, I've not even been able to fill
the $50 million costs.

</content>

</doc>
