<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Apr 27 13:28:45 2004</date>
  <content>

Washington - The Humane Society of the United States (HSUS), the nation's 
largest animal protection organization, today named Wayne Pacelle as its 
new leader and Chief Executive Officer - Designate. Pacelle will fully 
assume the executive leadership of the Society after a brief transition 
period.

"I am pleased to announce that The Humane Society of the United States has 
named a dynamic, aggressive, and visionary leader to direct our domestic 
and global efforts to protect animals, to halt animal cruelty and abuse, 
and to protect their habitats," said David O. Wiebers, M.D., HSUS chair of 
the Board of Directors and a neurologist at Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minn. 
"Wayne Pacelle has long been one of the nation's leading advocates of 
social reforms to benefit animals, and our Board of Directors recognized 
that we need a leader of his determination and inspiration in facing the 
challenges of the 21st century."

A senior vice president for The HSUS for the last 10 years, Pacelle has 
been instrumental in helping pass more than a dozen new federal laws to 
protect animals, more than 15 statewide ballot initiatives, and countless 
laws at the state level.  From toughening up laws for animal cruelty and 
animal fighting to outlawing the use of steel-jawed leghold traps and bear 
baiting to banning cruel industrial farming practices, Pacelle has led an 
unprecedented effort to protect millions of animals.  He has helped to 
secure millions in federal dollars for enforcement of federal laws to 
protect animals in the United States and abroad.

"The HSUS will continue to focus on protecting companion animals and 
wildlife, but we will make aggressive and unprecedented efforts to halt 
institutional forms of animal abuse, including the mistreatment of animals 
on industrial factory farms," said Pacelle. "In order to succeed, we need 
the participation of millions of Americans in our cause to root out 
suffering and abuse.  I want to invite every American who cares about 
animals to join with us in pursuing our important mission."

Pacelle joined the organization 10 years ago as vice president for 
government affairs and media and was promoted to senior vice president for 
communications and government affairs in 1998. He is the organization's 
leading spokesperson and has led a wide variety of campaigns for The HSUS. 
Pacelle previously served as executive director of The Fund for Animals,
the national advocacy group founded by author Cleveland Amory.  He 
graduated from Yale University in 1987 and is a native of New Haven, Conn.

The HSUS board of directors voted late Friday to appoint Pacelle to the 
position being vacated by Paul G. Irwin, who was asked by the board of 
directors to stay on beyond his planned retirement in 2002. "Paul Irwin has 
helped to build The Humane Society of the United States into the most 
influential animal advocacy organization in the world," said Dr. Wiebers. 
"One of every 40 Americans is a direct supporter of The HSUS thanks to his 
leadership.  We could not be more grateful to Paul for his extraordinary 
and expansive leadership."  Irwin joined The HSUS in 1976, and took over as 
president in 1992.
"Protecting animals has not only been a personal passion, but a moral 
imperative," stated Irwin.  "I could not be more proud of the work of The 
Humane Society of the United States in halting cruelty and exploitation 
across the globe.  I am grateful to have had the opportunity to lead the 
organization for the past 14 years and to serve it in various other 
capacities for 28 years.  I will continue to stay engaged with the issues 
we address because they represent the core issues of humane and sustainable 
life on this planet."

Pacelle will announce other senior leadership changes in the organization 
in the coming weeks.

The Humane Society of the United States represents more than eight million 
members and constituents and has an annual budget in excess of $80 million. 
The organization has a staff of nearly 300 people working in the Washington 
area and in 10 regional offices across the country and in a number of 
offices throughout the world.  The HSUS maintains active programs in 
companion animals and equine protection, wildlife and habitat protection, 
animals in research, farm animals and sustainable agriculture, and national 
and international humane education and environmental protection.  The group 
is marking its 50th anniversary in 2004.


</content>

</doc>
