<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon May 24 09:51:33 2004</date>
  <content>
Quick, does Matthew Scully sound like a Republican? 
He wants increased government regulations of
corporations that mass-produce animals for slaughter.
He is against "free-market" techniques of
conservation, in which some animals are killed or
captured in order to raise money to protect others. He
wants the Internal Revenue Service to investigate the
Safari Club, a powerful hunting advocacy group. 
Scully may sound like a liberal, but he is a
conservative with impeccable credentials: He works in
the White House as a speechwriter for President Bush. 
He has also emerged as a potent voice for animal
welfare in what is widely regarded as a red-meat White
House. Groups fighting animal cruelty consider him a
powerful advocate, and Scully is helping to advance
their issues. 
"He has had a substantial positive impact," said Wayne
Pacelle, the chief executive-designate of the Humane
Society of the United States, who credited the White
House for being open to Scully's views. "I don't say
this lightly: He's a hero to animal advocates across
the country." 
Much of that reputation rests on Scully's 2002 book,
"Dominion: The Power of Man, the Suffering of Animals,
and the Call to Mercy." In it, Scully denounced
Norwegian and Japanese whale hunters, industrial
farming techniques and the hunting of trophy animals. 
Although animal welfare is usually thought of as a
liberal cause, Scully argues that it ought to be a
central issue for religious conservatives. 
"Religious people . . . hold a kind and merciful view
of life, the faith of the broken, the hounded, the
hopeless," he wrote. "Yet too often, they will not
extend that spirit to our fellow creatures. More than
anything else, I hope with this book to speak to those
people." 
In interviews, Scully, 45, said animal welfare is a
nonpartisan issue. Everyone, he said, can agree it is
wrong to inflict needless cruelty on animals for
profit and to use wildlife and farm animals as
"resources" no different from wood and steel. 
Such cruelties exist because ordinary people ignore
where the meat they eat comes from, Scully said.
People who love animals such as dolphins and elephants
are uninterested in the lives of chickens and hogs.
But people -- Scully calls them "moral actors" -- can
alter the workings of the free market by making
choices about what kind of meat they buy, or whether
they eat meat at all. 
"It's caprice to say my dog is deserving of my care
and that dog in the shelter can be disposed of,"
Scully said in an interview at his office in the
Eisenhower Executive Office Building, where his
computer's wallpaper is a picture of a dog bounding
down steps. The dog is Lucky, Scully's boyhood pet, to
whom his book is dedicated. 
Scully, a vegetarian for 30 years, talked about
individual responsibility when discussing a hog farm
he saw in North Carolina where pigs spend entire lives
in narrow crates. 
"Pigs and lambs and cows and chickens are not pieces
of machinery, no matter how cost-efficient it may be
to treat them as such," he wrote in his book.
"Machinery doesn't cry or feel frightened or lonely.
And when a man treats them this way, he might as well
be a machine himself." 
Smithfield Foods, whose farm Scully wrote about, said
in a statement that the company complies with all laws
and houses animals in "an environment consistent with
their physiological needs." 

</content>

</doc>
