<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Mar 17 21:35:22 2004</date>
  <content>
On June 1, 2001, fires were set at the Schoppert Logging Company in Eagle
Creek, Oregon. Schoppert was due to begin logging on US Forrest Service
land. One whole logging truck, valued $50,000 was destroyed and two others
damaged. This was terrorism, the FBI's Joint Terrorism Task Force said.
Indictments came down with charges of 1) damaging vehicles and other
property used in interstate commerce, 2) obstructing the movement of
commodities in interstate commerce, 3) using violence to interfere in
commerce and 4) using an incindiery device to commit an act of violence.
If convicted, defendents could recieve up to $1 million in fines or up to
80 years in prison, more than twelve times the average sentence for rape,
a class one felony.

Recently, environmental activist and tree-sitter Tre Arrow, wanted by the
FBI, was taken into custody by Canadian authorities in British Colombia
for shoplifting a pair of bolt-cutters. He is accused by authorities of
the Schoppert Logging fire and of being a member of the Earth Liberation
Front, America's #1 domestic terrorist organization.

With each new horrific assault on human life that occurs in this world, we
are inundated with streams of hollow rhetoric used to rationalize, not to
justify, whatever stance the government takes. Terrorism no longer has
anything to do with fear, freedom does not have any relation to rights,
and violence has nothing to do with harm to living things. Particularly
since 9/11, governments and corporations have demanded that we accept as
truth things that are either outright contradictions or examples of what
is known as false concreteness, the assumption that irrelevant association
leads to substantive conclusions with far reaching implications. Some of
the contradictions we are told to swallow are eternal, like the idea that
waging war brings peace or that security only comes at the expense of
liberty. Others, like the idea that invading Iraq would make us safer or
that conspicuous consumption is effective counter-terrorism, serve the
interests of the powerful.

Welcome then, to the propaganda of what the Zapatista rebels of Chiapas,
Mexico dubbed the Fourth World War, the struggle between the culture of
life and the culture of death, of neoliberalism against humanity, of power
against truth. </content>

</doc>
