<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon May 17 13:27:32 2004</date>
  <content>
The number one thing that we do wrong-and I am speaking from many years of
doing this myself-is that we place personal purity ahead of being as
effective as possible for animals. We lose sight of the fact that veganism
is not an end in and of itself but rather a means of ending cruelty to
animals. Being vegan is not about being perfect and causing no cruelty at
all-it's about decreasing suffering as effectively as possible. 

We all know this, but it bears repeating: At some level, everything we
consume harms some animals. Every non-organic thing we eat involves
pesticides that kill birds and other small animals. Organic foods use animal
fertilizer. Harvesting vegan foods kills and displaces animals. Bike tires
and even "vegan" shoes contain some small amount of animal product. We could
all go out into the woods and live on nuts and berries as "level 10 vegans,"
but ultimately, that would be far less effective than living where we could
influence others to adopt a vegan diet as well.

Animals don't need your purity, or else it would make sense to go live in a
cabin in the woods, causing as little harm as possible. What the animals
need is your advocacy-and they need for it to be as effective and
influential as possible. Ultimately, veganism can't just be about us, or it
will become just one more narcissistic cultural fad. Veganism must be about
helping animals.

So the issue of personal purity becomes one of basic math: Adopting a vegan
diet means you're not supporting the torment and slaughter of dozens of
animals every single year. Helping just one more person to go vegan will
save twice as many animals. But the reverse is also true: If you do
something that prevents another person from adopting a vegan diet, if your
example puts up a barrier where you might have built a bridge, that hurts
animals-so then it becomes anti-vegan, if vegan means helping animals.

</content>

</doc>
