<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 15 08:55:09 2004</date>
  <content>
Rep. Linda McKee, D-Wayne, is serving her fourth and final term in the
Legislature representing the citizens of House District 79 -- Fayette,
Wayne and Winthrop. She also is an English teacher at Winthrop High
School. Correspondent Tim Guiggey sat down with her recently to discuss
her time in the Legislature.
...
I noticed that many of the bills you've sponsored have to do with the
protection of animal rights. Where does that come from?

I think you may also be referring to the work I did on the snaring of
coyotes. Coyote snaring is inhumane and cruel, and once I saw the
pictures, I saw that snaring had come about really because of politics,
not because of good science. It was an issue that deeply divided the
Inland Fisheries and Wildlife Department. I talked to several biologists
and came to believe it was something that needed to be stopped. I tried,
but it didn't pass the committee. I decided to write a letter to the
attorney general to find out if our law was actually legal. In my view, it
violated the Endangered Species Act and federal law. They took a couple of
months to consider it and finally wrote me a letter with the finding that
we were indeed in violation of the federal law and were asking that the
snaring of coyotes be stopped. And so for now it has stopped. I'm also
opposed to bear baiting. It has to do with problems between the guides who
take up all the bear baiting sites and other hunters who have difficulty
finding a place to site bait. Bear baiting should end, and I hope it does.
I hope that the people of the state of Maine can see it for what it is.
You don't park a container of old doughnuts and cupcakes and dinky
Twinkies and bread and grease and put it out in the middle of the woods
and feed a bear for a week or so, or a month, and then come along and
shoot it. To me, it violates ... fair chase.

</content>

</doc>
