<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Mar 13 20:55:35 2004</date>
  <content>
Even groups which are not terrorists, but are opposed to the policies of
the U.S. government, are often branded "terrorist" in order to demonize
them and justify their persecution. FBI surveillance of demonstrators
against the Iraq war was justified through scare stories about "terrorist
infiltrators." The Earth Liberation Front has been labeled terrorist, even
though it hasn't killed, or attempted to kill, a single person. In Iraq,
many suicide bombs and attacks against military targets have been
described as "terrorism." Terrorism is the targeting and killing of
civilians, suicide bombings or other attacks against military targets are
not terrorism. If attacking military targets is also terrorism then
virtually all military action, virtually all violence, would be terrorism
- a definition so broad that the term becomes meaningless. The Earth
Liberation Front engages in property destruction designed to reduce
pollution and save the Earth. Regardless of the ethics of these actions,
it is not terrorism because they do not attempt to kill civilians. If
violating property rights were terrorism then the Underground Railroad
(which violated property rights) would be an example of terrorism. If the
American revolution had happened today George Washington would be branded
a domestic terrorist by the British.


This fake ?war on terrorism? is a highly-effective propaganda device used
by Bush and others to ram through their authoritarian agenda. Dissent has
been demonized as "unpatriotic" and ?anti-American.? Anything the
government doesn't like gets labeled "terrorist" or "supporting
terrorism." The "war" is used as an excuse to justify any kind of military
intervention, as in Iraq, simply by accusing the enemy of "supporting
terrorism." Opposing free trade has even been equated with supporting
terrorism. In the name of the "war on terrorism" civil liberties have been
drastically decreased through a number of measures. The PATRIOT Act,
passed by congress with virtually no debate, gives the FBI the power to
access your private medical, library, financial and student records
without a warrant and to forbid anyone from telling you that they have
accessed them. It allows non-citizens to be jailed on mere suspicion, not
actual evidence, and be denied re-admission to the United States if they
have opinions the U.S. government does not like. People convicted of no
crime may be held indefinitely without any meaningful judicial review. In
addition to the PATRIOT act, secret military tribunals have been set up to
try alleged "terrorists" without the right to a fair trial. Thousands of
immigrants were "disappeared." New attorney general guidelines allow
spying on dissident organizations without any evidence of illegal activity.</content>

</doc>
