<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Feb 12 11:05:24 2004</date>
  <content>
Is this once taboo trend making its way back to the fashion frontlines, or
are we faking it?

Notice anything different in the celeb rag mags lately? There?s a lot more
real fur being worn on the red carpet, in the swank clubs and on the
catwalk. Real fur. No disclaimers. No apologies.

Are we seeing a resurgence in the popularity of wearing fur in public even
in the face of protest, or is it all illusion? Is it real or is it faux -
really good, easy-to-fool-us faux fur? And are sales of real fur up or down? 
...
In an era when wearing furs may not be PC to many and groups such as
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals are putting up disturbing
protest billboards and promoting faux fur with a barely wrapped Melissa
Rivers, and celebrities have come out to say, "No, I?ll only wear faux!,"
how is it that so many are coming back to real fur, and so many designers
are bucking the protesters and designing with the real stuff?
...
Sperlazzi agrees. "The younger set likes ?luxe.? They follow fashion. If
it?s not the garment, it?s the trim or the accessory."

But talk to PETA and you?ll get a different story.

Michael McGraw, media spokesman for the group, admits that more designers
are using fur.

"Design houses are sending these young design students to Denmark and
spending tons of money to provide them with real fur to work with," he
says. "But fashion is fickle."

He also says that what we see in the popular media about fur is an
illusion. "These celebrities who look like they?re wearing fur probably
aren?t. Faux fur has gotten so realistic-looking even the media can?t
tell, and they don?t bother to find out. The technology has gotten so good
that if it looks like real fur, they?ll write ?fur.?" 
...
And about faux, Sperlazzi says, "Faux fur is positive for the fur industry
as a whole. It?s big in the junior market. These young women want the
look, but can?t afford it yet."

Does she or doesn?t she wear real fur? Apparently with advances in faux
fur and real fur design alike, only the furrier knows for sure. 
</content>

</doc>
