<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Feb 17 15:07:45 2004</date>
  <content>
Recent tuition hikes, the unhealthy quality of food, and inconvenient meal
times have forced a number of UMBC students to drop their meal plans
entirely. Director of Wood Company Dining Services, Oscar Berninger,
claimed that "decreases between the fall and spring semester happen at
every campus in the country."

Many students find it makes more financial sense to drop their meal plans
and convert scholarship money, or money intended for meal plans into Flex
dollars. Commuter student Jacqui Medford recently dropped her meal plan
and now only uses flex, but she is still having difficulties affording her
lunches. "Sometimes I won?t eat just because I can?t afford to, and that
is ridiculous. A super-sized meal anywhere else is around four dollars.
Why should we pay six to seven dollars just because we are on campus?
Where did the tuition raise go? Certainly not to [help] us." 
...
A number of students have dropped their meal plans not only because they
cannot afford them, or because they simply do not like the food, but
because they cannot eat it. Vegetarian Kristen Cevoli said, "I dropped my
meal plan this year and decided to cook for myself, mainly because the
options for me were so few, and not very healthy either." For Cevoli,
however, money was also an issue because "it would be cheaper to not pay
for a meal plan
 that way I wouldn?t lose money when I didn?t use all my
meals in a week, which always happened."
...
Although the Commons may not seem to provide extensive meal options for
vegans, vegetarians, and other special diets, Berninger claimed "We have
one of the most comprehensive vegan and vegetarian programs in the
country" in the student Dining Hall. This includes vegan soup of the day,
salads, and prepare-your-own fare at Fresh Choices. Also, Kosher frozen
fare is available at the Spot. But many students who don?t have time to
run to the Dining Hall between classes for lunch wish the Commons could
offer better choices.</content>

</doc>
