<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 16:25:30 2003</date>
  <content>

Animal models for human disease play an important role in understanding the 
causes and mechanisms of genetic disorders and are invaluable in developing 
new treatments and therapeutics. These animals are produced by several 
techniques, including transgene insertion and targeted gene knockout in 
embryos to generate new lines, but the subsequent crossbreeding and 
necessary genotyping make these time-consuming strategies. The generation of 
embryonic stem cell lines from genetically engineered embryos combined with 
somatic cell nuclear transfer (SCNT) is routinely used to produce animal 
clones with a known genotype from which further stocks can be bred and has 
been used with success in the production of sheep and mice. However, the 
production of cloned rats has been unsuccessful due to technical 
difficulties associated with spontaneous oocyte activation that occurs 
within an hour of egg collection.

In the September 25 Science, Qi Zhou and colleagues in a collaboration among 
Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique, the Chinese Academy of 
Sciences, and the biotech company genOway report the first successful 
production of cloned rats using a technique that reversibly blocks meiotic 
metaphase–anaphase transition in the oocyte and allows the successful uptake 
of transferred somatic cell nuclei (Science, DOI:10.1126/science.1088313, 
September 25, 2003).

"It is a real scientific collaboration between an academic group headed by 
J.P. Renard and a biotech company team," Alexandre Fraichard, chief 
executive officer of genOway, told The Scientist by E-mail. "Both partners 
provided expertise and technologies."

The team reported earlier attempts to develop a rapid, single-step, nuclear 
transfer technique, but found that within 30 minutes of collection, 70% of 
oocytes showed evidence of maturation. And while 201 out of 221 apparently 
successfully cloned embryos divided into two-cell embryos, no fetal 
development was observed in any of them.

</content>

</doc>
