<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 10:17:39 2003</date>
  <content>
When U.S. Marine Corps reservist Ravi Chand found out that he was going to go 
to war, his first reaction was confusion. 
A class of ?02 graduate of UC Santa Cruz, Chand, 23, had just moved to 
Virginia to pursue his career: campaigning for the animal rights group People for 
the Ethical Treatment of Animals, or PETA. That was put on hold with the 
American invasion of Iraq. 
"Here I am," Chand recalled thinking during a recent phone interview, "living 
the philosophy of nonviolence and then getting called to go to war?" 
But the vegan serviceman quickly found a way to reconcile his beliefs with 
his military action. 


A Sacramento native, Chand joined the corps at 18, right after high school. 
The challenge of going through boot camp that summer, he said, was just as 
exciting as the prospect of getting financial support in college. 
And while, he said, his young political views were unusual for a Marine, he 
enjoyed the chance to weigh his opinions against those of his peers. 
A defining moment in his thinking came during his junior year of college at 
UCSC. 
Sitting in the Cowell College dining hall one day, he was confronted by 
another student: "She started yelling at me because I was eating meat," he said. 
Chand was so disturbed that he felt he needed to know more. 
"I went and read ?Diet for a New America? to have argumentative comebacks," 
he said, referring to John Robbins? vegetarian anthem. 
Instead, the book turned him into a vegetarian. 
His senior year, a PETA documentary prompted him to go vegan and then to go 
out and spread the merits of his new diet. Watching the video made him think 
that "animals have the same range of emotions as humans." 
Soon, Chand was leading workshops sponsored by an animal rights student 
group. Kerry Holliday, then head of the group, said Chand?s disposition helped him 
carry his message to a mainstream audience. 
"He shattered that stereotype of the hippie vegan," Holliday said. 
After graduation, Chand moved to Norfolk, Va., to work full-time at PETA?s 
headquarters. 
Then came the war, and Chand served as a corporal on the crew of an Amtrack 
amphibious tank. His unit came under direct fire when it was ambushed in the 
southern Iraqi city of Nasiriyah, he said. 
His philosophy, he said, helped him put the horrors of war into perspective. 
After all, no act of mayhem could be worse than what goes on in 
slaughterhouses, or so he thought. He goes as far as claiming that killing animals is as 
immoral as killing people. 
Overthrowing the regime of ousted Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein, he said, was a 
good cause for going to war. At the same time, it gave him a chance to tell 
people about what is, in his view, the most important cause of all ? not eating 
animals. 
Chand said six Marines went vegetarian and one went vegan. 
</content>

</doc>
