<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec 22 14:10:13 2003</date>
  <content>
Before the ink even dried on Wyoming's wolf management plan, it was greeted 
by a chorus of howls. The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service voiced strong 
concerns that the plan would not provide adequate assurances to prevent 
wolves from becoming threatened again. Neighboring political leaders, such 
as Montana Gov. Judy Martz, admonished Wyoming to create a more balanced 
plan so as not to delay the transition of wolf management to all three 
Northern Rocky states.


Expert criticism
Conservationists also believed that the Wyoming plan was too aggressive by 
allowing the immediate shooting of wolves. And this past week, in a process 
called "peer review" (a step in the wolf delisting process), a group of 
federal, state, and academic wolf experts from all over the country added 
themselves to the chorus of concern about Wyoming's wolf management plan.


As part of the endangered species delisting process, Wyoming agreed that it 
would not rely on Yellowstone and Grand Teton National Parks to support all 
of its wolves, and be committed to maintaining a minimum of seven wolf packs 
outside of these protected areas. Yet under Wyoming's current plan, the Game 
and Fish Department has authority to regulate wolf killing only within the 
wilderness areas adjacent to the national parks-which covers just 10 percent 
of the wolves' range outside of the national parks. Across the rest of 
Wyoming, wolves would be classified as a "predatory" animal, meaning that 
wolves can be killed anytime, by anyone. Given these parameters, it is 
questionable whether Wyoming could maintain seven wolf packs outside the 
protected areas.


Not surprisingly, seven out of the 11 peer-review experts expressed concerns 
regarding Wyoming's management plan. Some specifically addressed the 
"predatory" classification across most of Wyoming: "This seems like an 
extreme form of wolf management," said the lead wolf biologist and manager 
for Wisconsin Department of Natural Resources.

</content>

</doc>
