<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Aug 17 22:38:59 2003</date>
  <content>
The Japanese call it bazashi, a toothsome treat served raw, with
chives, ginger, garlic and onion. Italians boast of pastissado de
caval, a succulent stew, while the Swiss savor fondue bourguignonne.

It is also popular with more than a few French, Belgian, German,
Romanian, Kazakh and Chinese gastronomes. Tongans, too -- including
those who brought the festive dish to Utah -- relish it roasted,
shredded and basted in coconut milk, or spiced with curry.

Horse.

In many lands, it's what's for dinner.

But don't go looking for filets of Flicka or the makings of
Seabiscuit Bisque or Seattle Slew Stew from local grocery stores or
meat retailers. While two foreign-owned slaughterhouses in Texas
annually ship an estimated 20,000 tons of horse flesh to diners
abroad -- among them more than a few animals from Utah -- most
Americans have no hankering for horse. 
...
So, where does one get horse meat in Utah? Afeaki and others in the
Tongan community say it is strictly a do-it-yourself proposition.
Purchases are made privately, usually from small auctions or a farm
or ranch trying to sell an old or broken-down animal; preparation,
too, is a quiet affair.

Usually, that is that, though occasionally an incident occurs that
makes authorities aware of the practice -- like the horse's head and
hooves found tossed over a West Valley City fence a year and a half
ago, says John Fox, an animal-cruelty investigator with the Utah
Humane Society. 
...
Proponents of the U.S. horse-slaughter ban debate just how "humane"
the final moments of the animals' lives can be, claiming some horses
-- despite being shot in the head -- are still living when hoisted by
their hooves to have their throats slit.

It is a claim the industry denies and points out no slaughterhouse is
ever a pleasant environment, whether the animals being killed and
processed are cattle, pork, chickens, turkeys -- or horses.

And, unless Congress passes a ban, horses in the United States will
continue to be slaughtered for overseas tables. 

s</content>

</doc>
