<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Apr 15 11:59:50 2004</date>
  <content>
Cougar hunting with dogs will be permitted this year in Okanogan County and 
four other counties under a three-year pilot project recently passed by the 
state legislature.

The new law calls for participating counties and state wildlife officials to 
work together to develop a program that allows the pursuit and hunting of 
cougars using dogs. Based on their recommendations, the state Fish and 
Wildlife Commission is expected to establish the rules for the hunting 
season in August.

The use of dogs to hunt cougars, bears and bobcats has been banned 
throughout Washington since 1996, when voters approved an initiative that 
eliminated the longstanding tradition of hound hunting. Since then, the use 
of dogs has been permitted only when a particular cougar is deemed to pose a 
threat to people or animals.

Senate Bill 6118, signed into law by the governor on March 31, establishes a 
pilot cougar hunting program in Okanogan, Ferry, Stevens, Pend Oreille and 
Chelan counties. The program’s primary goals, according to legislators and 
agency biologists, are to provide for public safety, to protect property and 
to assess cougar populations and help develop future cougar management 
plans.

Rich Beausoleil, a bear and cougar specialist for the Washington Fish and 
Wildlife Department, said the agency will begin meeting soon with county 
officials to come up with recommendations for the way the hunt will be 
structured, including the length of the hunting season and the number of 
cougars that can be killed.

"We’re going to have some boundaries because of the biology of the species," 
Beausoleil said. "We’re looking at the density of mountain lion 
populations."

Joel Kretz, a rancher who lives near Wauconda, was among the sportsmen and 
ranchers who have lobbied the legislature to reinstitute hound hunting. He 
served on a task force created in 2001, when Okanogan County commissioners 
determined that cougars were causing problems for livestock and residents in 
the county.</content>

</doc>
