<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jul  9 13:26:17 2003</date>
  <content>
Anti-tobacco lawyer John Banzhaf is presently building more solid test
cases against food corporations for knowingly selling products that are
injurious to consumers' health. Banzhaf will send a letter to McDonald's,
Wendy's, Burger King, Pizza Hut, Taco Bell and Kentucky Fried Chicken this
month, demanding that they label their food as containing substances that
may be as addictive as nicotine.

At the same time, there is talk of imposing a "fat tax" and/or forcing
manufacturers to put health warnings on certain foods, similar to the
warnings on tobacco products. McDonalds is apparently feeling the
pressure. They have recently issued a request to their meat suppliers to
reduce the quantity of antibiotics in their meat, perhaps a pre-emptive
measure, intended to demonstrate concern about the health impact of their
products in case of future lawsuits. 
...
Yet the balance of influences on our dietary choices has changed
dramatically over the last two centuries. Two hundred years ago, people
tended to stay in one small region for most of their lives and had little
or no access to the world outside. The influences on their diet were
predominantly regional and familial. They ate the foods that were home
grown, hand reared, or caught in their locale. Fresh meat, seafood,
vegetables and fruits could not be transported thousands of miles in a few
hours, so people tended only to eat locally grown, seasonal produce and
locally butchered meat. All the crops, vegetables and fruits were organic,
because chemical fertilizers and pesticides had not been invented. All the
eggs and chickens were "free range", and growth hormones, antibiotics and
steroids were not fed to livestock, so all meat and dairy produced was
chemical free. Supermarkets, mass media, and industrial food production
techniques did not exist. Even eating in restaurants was a rare experience
for most, since the majority population lived in rural areas and the few
restaurants that existed were in cities.
...
As John Banzhaf constructs his case, instead of pursuing the unproven
notion that fast foods contain addictive ingredients, he should consider
the more insidious and pervasive power of the media and commerce to create
unhealthy dietary preferences and to eliminate real consumer freedom of
choice.

--</content>

</doc>
