<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jul 30 17:56:11 2003</date>
  <content>
Here's a tip that vegetarians and savvy menu planners have been sitting on
for more than a decade. And it's a good one.

What if you could indulge in all your favourite foods such as nachos,
pizza, spaghetti sauce, burritos, deli sandwiches, bacon and chicken
fingers, but with a fraction of the saturated fats, calories and
cholesterol usually associated with those foods?

What would you say to a juicy, delicious burger with 12 grams of protein
but less than 100 calories and one gram of fat? Impossible? Not if you
replace animal-based meats with meat alternatives.

If the words "meat alternative" conjure images of bland, blobby tofu and
side trips to the health food store, here's welcome news: your local
supermarket has a full range of meat substitutes fashioned to replicate
the taste and texture of bacon, pepperoni, ground round and chicken strips
? but without the heart-unhealthy cholesterol and fat.
...
"One misconception (about veggie meats) regards taste," says Kurtis
Hooley, managing director of Hain Celestial Canada, the parent company of
Vancouver-based Yves Veggie Cuisine.

Yves ? which supplies McDonald's Canada with McVeggie burgers, and hotdog
stands with jumbo veggie dogs ? is North America's leading supplier of
packaged, soy-based mock meats.

"Meat alternatives have come a long way and many consumers remember
tasting tofu years ago and believe soy-based meat alternatives will taste
the same," Hooley adds. "All tofu is soy but not all soy is tofu."
...
Animal rights group People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA)
recommends faux meats and its Golden Bun awards recognize the best in
veggie burgers.

PETA pegs annual sales of veggie burgers in the U.S. at about $300
million, which may be a drop in the bucket compared to the billion-dollar
fast food industry. Yves pegs the meat alternative market in Canada at $33
million.

Nevertheless, many marquee chains, including Burger King, Harvey's and
McDonald's, now offer veggie burgers. Even mom-and-pop carnivore havens
like Toronto's Apache Burger and Dangerous Dan's have the veggie option.
</content>

</doc>
