<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Oct 31 06:24:20 2003</date>
  <content>


For many, it is a highly emotional issue -- accusations that helpless
animals suffer in sterile laboratories at the hands of soulless
scientists. Animal rights organizations routinely provide shocking video
to television newsrooms to dramatize their cause.

But the FBI says an increasing number of animals rights groups are now
turning violent, alleging hundreds of destructive acts have taken place in
recent years in what critics call a misguided effort to stop animal abuse.

"I think people in the animal liberation movement are moving from
persuasion to coercion," said Oakland author Wesley Smith, who is
researching a book about the growing violence in the animal rights
movement. "The animal liberation movement has become anti-human."
...
While the FBI describes the ALF as a terrorist group, Craig Rosebraugh
claims the only damage caused by animal rights violence is property
damage. "They have a strict code of protecting human and non-human life,"
he said.

Rosebraugh says he does not participate in the violence, but receives
"communiqu?s" from the ALF, which he passes on to the news media.
...
And indeed, the animal rights movement says if its current tactics don't
work, its violence could escalate.

"I can't list what it could include. Whether it's assassination, bombings,
property destruction, I can't say," said Rosebraugh.

The Animal Liberation Front is reportedly an offshoot of the Earth
Liberation Front, which has claimed responsibility for violent acts
against organizations such as logging companies.



Other News Headlines added in this hour to Animalconcerns
(http://www.animalconcerns.org/):

WHO KILLED JANE?
Anger at stores' sale of reindeer rugs
Lot pleads guilty to animal cruelty
WILDLIFE EXPERT CAUGHT SMUGGLING REPTILES
Man accused of animal cruelty
Safety on holiday stressed; black cat adoptions on hold
FDA: Cloned Meat Apparently OK to Eat
'Angel' Mahima is the new protector of animals
ANIMAL ADVOCATES: ABUSE MUST BE MADE A FELONY
Calf killer is canine, not feline
Sickly pets lead dog owners to sue Puppy Palace
Are you a vegetarian?
Tech plans trans fat labels

Click on "More News Headlines," too!--</content>

</doc>
