<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb  1 16:24:08 2004</date>
  <content>
Stray animals are a problem for most local communities. While most cities 
have ordinances and programs in place to deal with animals who are roaming at 
large, enforcing the programs are very costly. Depending on the city, the 
ordinances and policies dealing with stray animals vary.
Farmington
Shirla Boyd has been serving as the animal control officer in Farmington 
since 1998. Boyd has taken the homeless pets found in Farmington onto the 
information superhighway as the Farmington Police Department has joined Petfinder.com, 
a database of homeless pets.
"Once a pet's photo and description is added to our database, its chances of 
being adopted go up substantially," said Betsy Saul, president and co-founder 
of Petfinder.com.
Internet users can view pets that have impounded by the Farmington Police 
Department at http://www.petfinder.com/shelters/MO230.html.
Last year Boyd said the city collected 1,085 dogs and cats. Of those only 118 
were claimed by their owners. The majority of the dogs and cats impounded by 
Farmington go to Petsmart in St. Louis for adoption through the St. Francois 
Society.
Boyd said that owners will pay a $3 fee for the first day their pet is 
impounded, $1 for any additional days and if their pets are found running at large, 
owners are given a $75 ticket and have to pay court costs.
In addition to dogs and cats, Boyd also catches wild animals that are causing 
problems in the city.
"I've caught several snakes, skunks and possums," said Boyd. "I turn loose 
the raccoons, possums and the squirrels that I catch in their natural habitat. 
If I catch a skunk I have to take it to the range to be destroyed because they 
can carry rabies. The fire department, the police department and myself had to 
chase a button buck deer a while back. We chased it for two weeks. Its mother 
got hit on Route D and it kept coming into town. Finally it got with the rest 
of its family and took off."</content>

</doc>
