<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Mar 29 18:34:55 2004</date>
  <content>
Except for a few architectural differences in confinement buildings, Iowa 
Farm Bureau members found pork production in Italy to be surprisingly similar to 
U.S. practices.
The tour of the Pedercini International pig farm in Porzano di Leno was part 
of the annual By Tom Block 
Except for a few architectural differences in confinement buildings, Iowa 
Farm Bureau members found pork production in Italy to be surprisingly similar to 
U.S. practices.
The tour of the Pedercini International pig farm in Porzano di Leno was part 
of the annual county president?s incentive trip to learn about international 
agriculture. The farm is a research center for new products and technologies, 
including farrowing and gestation equipment, flooring system and slats, and 
weaning and finishing pens.
The farm?s four confinement buildings, housing about 2,000 sows, were 
constructed of concrete with both natural and forced-air ventilation. 
Inside, Pedercini has developed a patented Freesow gestation stall for sows 
and gilts to be held in groups according to new European Union regulations on 
animal welfare. After pregnancy detection, the crate can be raised to group 
four sows to a pen for 110 days. The animals are moved back to standard crates 
for farrowing.
county president?s incentive trip to learn about international agriculture. 
The farm is a research center for new products and technologies, including 
farrowing and gestation equipment, flooring system and slats, and weaning and 
finishing pens.
The farm?s four confinement buildings, housing about 2,000 sows, were 
constructed of concrete with both natural and forced-air ventilation. 
Inside, Pedercini has developed a patented Freesow gestation stall for sows 
and gilts to be held in groups according to new European Union regulations on 
animal welfare. After pregnancy detection, the crate can be raised to group 
four sows to a pen for 110 days. The animals are moved back to standard crates 
for farrowing.
</content>

</doc>
