<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:16:33 2003</date>
  <content>In reaction to the shooting death of a beloved family pet last 
month, the People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals has donated educational 
material to the town's elementary schools to help teach students to treat all 
life with respect. 
In an Oct. 10 letter to the Moosup and Shepard Hill elementary schools, 
Sangeeta Kumar, PETA humane educator, wrote that the organization donated the 
information after reading about the death of Mr. Bojangles, a basset hound owned by 
the Carpenter family on Ashley Street. 
?For more than 100 years, the humane-education community has sought to 
prevent violence and improve society by teaching compassion and empathy for all life,
? Kumar wrote. 
William Buchert, 44, of 1 Ashley St. was charged with cruelty to animals, 
unlawful discharge of a firearm and breach of peace for shooting and killing ?Bo?
 with a high-powered pellet gun, according to police. He will reappear in 
Superior Court in Danielson Nov. 26. 
Shepard Hill Principal Melanie Robeda and Moosup Principal Susan Chamie said 
they received the materials and, after carefully reviewing the information, 
distributed the packet that included a video and other educational materials. 
Teachers were instructed to use the information at their discretion. 
Robeda said since the beginning of school students have been discussing the 
different characteristics of a good citizen and that the ?Share the World? 
materials fit in with that curriculum. 
Chamie added that some of the second-grade teachers were able to incorporate 
the information into their classrooms and that so far the information has been 
well received. 
The kit also includes brochures to give parents tips on incorporating 
kindness into daily life and identifying potentially aggressive behavior at an early 
age. 
?The perpetrator of the vicious attack on the dog obviously was never taught 
these vital lessons as a child,? Kumar wrote. 
</content>

</doc>
