<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 19 14:18:22 2004</date>
  <content>



  On Saturday, December 13, one of the world's leading newspapers, The
  Guardian (UK), published a lengthy article seriously questioning the 
place
  of cows' milk in a healthful diet and government subsidies for the dairy
  industry. The article looked at both the UK and the US. It is available 
on
  the web in two parts at the following addresses:

  Part One:
  http://www.guardian.co.uk/weekend/story/0,3605,1104740,00.html
  Part Two:
  http://www.guardian.co.uk/weekend/story/0,3605,1104854,00.html

  I highly recommend reading it, but will summarize it below for those who
  don't have the time to read a 5467 word piece.

  The article is headed, "DAIRY MONSTERS: We used to take it for granted 
that
  milk was good for us. But now the industry faces a crisis, with the 
public
  questioning such assumptions. So just how healthy is milk? Anne Karpf
  investigates."

  Karpf notes that there is mounting scientific evidence that "regular
  consumption of large quantities of milk can be bad for your health, and
  campaigners are making a noise about the environmental and international
  costs of large-scale intensive European dairy farming." But she comments,
  "So thorough is our dairy indoctrination that it requires a total gestalt
  switch to contemplate the notion that milk may help to cause the very
  diseases it's meant to prevent....Today, there's a big bank of scientific
  evidence against milk consumption, alleging not only that it causes some
  diseases but, equally damning, that it fails to prevent others for which 
it
  has traditionally been seen as a panacea."

  She refers to the work of Frank Oski, former paediatrics director at 
Johns
  Hopkins school of medicine, "who estimated in his book Don't Drink Your
  Milk! that half of all iron deficiency in US infants results from cows'
  milk-induced intestinal bleeding." You can buy that book at:
  www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0945383347/dawnwatch

  She discusses lactose intolerance, which causes "bloating, cramps, 
diarrhoea
  and farts.": "In 1965, investigators at Johns Hopkins found that 15% of 
all
  the white people and almost three-quarters of all the black people they
  tested were unable to digest lactose. Milk, it seemed, was a racial 
issue,
  and far more people in the world are unable than able to digest lactose.
  That includes most Thais, Japanese, Arabs and Ashkenazi Jews, and 50% of
  Indians."

  Karpf notes that milk critics say that the idea that osteoporosis is 
caused
  by calcium deficiency is "one of the great myths of our time." She 
writes,
  "In fact, the bone loss and deteriorating bone tissue that take place in
  osteoporosis are due not to calcium deficiency but rather to its 
resorption:
  it's not that our bodies don't get enough calcium, rather that they 
excrete
  too much of what they already have. So we need to find out what it is 
that's
  breaking down calcium stores in the first place, to the extent that more
  than one in three British women now suffers from osteoporosis. The most
  important culprit is almost certainly the overconsumption of protein.
  High-protein foods such as meat, eggs and dairy make excessive demands on
  the kidneys, which in turn leach calcium from the body. One solution, 
then,
  isn't to increase our calcium intake, but to reduce our consumption of
  protein, so our bones don't have to surrender so much calcium.
  Astonishingly, according to this newer, more critical view, dairy 
products
  almost certainly help to cause, rather than prevent, osteoporosis."

  She notes, "American women are among the biggest consumers of calcium in 
the
  world, yet still have one of the highest levels of osteoporosis in the
  world" and that "Most Chinese people eat and drink no dairy products 
and...
  consume only half the calcium of Americans." Yet "osteoporosis is 
uncommon
  in China despite an average life expectancy of 70." Further, "In South
  Africa, Bantu women who eat mostly plant protein and only 200-350mg of
  calcium a day have virtually no osteoporosis, despite bearing on average 
six
  children and breastfeeding for prolonged periods. Their African-American
  brothers and sisters, who ingest on average more than 1,000mg of calcium 
a
  day, are nine times more likely to experience hip fractures."

  She quotes T Colin Campbell, the Jacob Gould Schurman Professor of
  Nutritional Biochemistry at Cornell University: "The association between 
the
  intake of animal protein and fracture rates appears to be as strong as 
that
  between cigarette smoking and lung cancer." Another quote from Campbell
  associates milk consumption with an increased risk of cancer: "Cows' milk
  protein may be the single most significant chemical carcinogen to which
  humans are exposed".

  Karpf discusses the conflicts of interest that have led to milk's status 
as
  the perfect food despite much scientific evidence to the contrary:


  "Another reason why official policy on milk is often at odds with medical
  evidence lies in the conflict of government role, both in Britain and the
  US. The US department of agriculture, for example, has the twin, and 
often
  mutually incompatible, tasks of promoting agricultural products and
  providing dietary advice. In 2000, it was still recommending two to three
  servings of dairy products a day, to the rage of critics such as the
  Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine. PCRM claimed that six of 
the
  11-member drafting panel had close ties with the meat, egg and dairy
  industries (five of them with dairy).

  "Britain isn't free from conflict of interest, either. The government is
  heavily involved in encouraging us to drink milk."

  Karpf criticizes the UK's National Dairy Council advertisements, 
commenting,
  "Of course, it's no crime for the industry to promote itself; what's
  disturbing is its masquerading as a disinterested source of 
incontrovertible
  information."

  Karpf feels that perhaps the "most insidious dimension of the dairy
  fightback is funding research."

  The article discusses animal welfare concerns in detail. She starts with
  "the vegetarian fallacy" which allows people to separate the dairy and 
veal
  industries:

  "Alongside the researchers raising questions about milk sits the more
  inflammatory animal rights movement, which has recently focused its
  attention on dairy farming and what it argues is its intrinsic cruelty. 
For
  a long time, those concerned about animal welfare seemed magically to 
exempt
  milk from their preoccupations. They suffered from what Richard Young of 
the
  Soil Association calls 'the vegetarian fallacy': non-meat-eaters who 
still
  drink milk and so perpetuate the cycle that ends in crated veal calves
  destined for European dinner tables. Now many of them have begun to 
contend
  that, organic or not, there's no such thing as humane milk. For in order 
to
  lactate, cows - like humans - first have to get pregnant. Calves are
  essentially the waste by-product of the industry. What happens to them 
once
  they've done what they were created to do - stimulate a cow's milk
  production by the very fact of their being conceived?

  "Male udderless cows are of no value to the dairy industry, so if prices 
for
  male calves are low and the veal route unprofitable, most are killed 
within
  a couple of weeks for baby food or pies, to make rennet, or sent to
  rendering plants to be turned into tallow or grease or, in other 
countries,
  animal feed. Female calves, on the other hand, are bred as replacement 
stock
  for their mothers. The provision of beef essentially originates in the 
dairy
  industry: if we didn't drink milk, we wouldn't have all that extra meat 
to
  get rid of.

  "Though a male calf's life is unenviable, its mother's is no better. To
  ensure almost continuous lactation, she endures annual pregnancies. Her 
calf
  is removed from her within 24 hours of its birth. Calves hardly ever 
drink
  their mother's milk.

  She goes on to discuss the exhaustive exploitation of the cows' bodies:

  "Like agribusinesses everywhere, milk producers have tried to increase
  output while cutting costs. The victims are the cows. Today, from the age 
of
  two, they're expected to produce up to 10,000 litres of milk during their
  10-month lactation stint (before they dry off, are re-inseminated and the
  whole process starts up again). Milked once or twice (or even three 
times)
  daily while pregnant, they produce around 20 litres a day, 10 times as 
much
  as they'd need to feed a calf. The amount of milk cows are required to 
make
  each day has almost doubled in the past 30 years, because having a 
smaller
  number of high-yielding cows reduces a farmer's feed, fertiliser, 
equipment,
  labour and capital costs. That's why the variety of cattle breeds in 
Europe
  has declined so much - everyone wants the high-yielding black-and-white
  Holstein-Friesens.

  "You don't need to be sentimental about animals to pity the poor bloated
  creatures, dragging around their vast, abnormally heavy udders. Many each
  year go lame, and they rarely live longer than four or five years, 
compared
  with a natural lifespan of around 25 years. Then they are slaughtered.

  And she notes the pain of mastitis and its impact on human health:

  "The official view is that not only do dairy farmers care about their 
cows,
  but that it's in their interests to keep them healthy. The reality is 
that
  overmilking, problems with cleanliness and the choice of high-yielding
  breeds together cause more than 30 incidents of mastitis per 100 British
  cows each year. Mastitis is a painful infection of the udder. Cows' 
mastitis
  has implications for human health, too, because to control infection 
farmers
  use more antibiotics."

  Finally, Karpf discusses government efforts to protect the dairy 
industry,
  such as the food disparagement acts introduced in 13 US states, and the 
UK's
  Common Agricultural Policy, which she writes is so absurd it "will have 
you
  thinking you've woken up in the middle of a Dali painting." She details 
the
  ways in which the government props up the dairy industry at the expense 
of
  small-scale farms in developing countries, human health, and animal 
welfare.

  She asks what the alternative might be, and notes that people don't want
  their eating habits policed.  "Yet," she writes, "what we eat and drink
  isn't just the result of individual choice and cultural tradition: the
  contents of our shopping trolleys are at least equally shaped by 
government
  policy and official decisions."

  She quotes Dr Tim Lobstein, co-director of the Food Commission, an
  independent watchdog on food issues, who "advocates the removal of all EU
  subsidies from dairy production, with the money going to support 
sustainable
  forms of food production, including some organic dairy farming." He
  comments, with regard to struggling dairy farmers: "I can't help to stay 
in
  business the producers of commodities that aren't helping human health -
  they'll have to find alternative employment. The EU should help farmers
  transfer to products more helpful to human health, such as horticulture."

  Karpf calls for a national debate on milk production and consumption. She
  writes, "Part of this debate will have to be a frank appraisal of whether
  milk can jeopardise human health.... it seems increasingly clear that 
dairy
  products alone probably don't protect bone health in the way we've long
  thought, and that calcium intake on its own has only a small effect on 
bone
  density."

  The article concludes: "At the same time (and Atkins notwithstanding), 
while
  some fats are essential, the human body does not thrive on excessive 
amounts
  of milk fat. Yet milk's connotations are so primordial, its associations 
so
  pastoral and the interests that promote it so enormous, that changing the
  way we think about it, and drink it, will be a process every bit as
  challenging and root-and-branch as the loss of unquestioning religious
  faith."



</content>

</doc>
