<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr 12 12:20:16 2004</date>
  <content>


We are writing to ask for your help on one or more of three important 
mercury-in-seafood/sea turtle-related matters.  The first is a request 
that you send a letter to the editor of your local paper (there is a 
sample below) about the FDA?s latest mercury-in-seafood advisory. The FDA 
has just issued an advisory that will threaten children and families from 
mercury.  Let the papers know what you think about the FDA playing 
politics with public health.

The second is that you print out a ?Got Mercury?? PDF document and post 
one or more of them on bulletin boards in your community (caf??s, grocery 
stores or other community bulletin boards).  The document can be 
downloaded from:
http://www.seaturtles.org/pdf/mercurytearoffsign3.pdf
or by visiting www.seaturtles.org and clicking the mercury, swordfish and 
sea turtle campaign link on the home page.  The website www.gotmercury.org 
allows seafood consumers to determine how much seafood is safe to eat, in 
complete contradiction to the FDA?s advisory.

And the third, in case you haven?t already done so, is to visit 
www.seaturtles.org home page and send a letter to Safeway asking them to 
warn customers in all of their stores about the dangers of mercury in 
seafood, not just California stores.  Safeway must not continue to ignore 
the public health threats posed by mercury in seafood!

Every time we take an action surrounding mercury, we are protecting public 
health and helping to reduce consumer demand of species caught in ways 
that are killing sea turtles.

If any of these items appeal to you, please read additional information 
below and thank you for supporting the Sea Turtle Restoration Project?s 
conservation efforts!

If you do take action on the Got Mercury or if you send a letter to the 
editor, please let us know!  It feeds our spirit, energy and motivation to 
know we are working together in solidarity!

Please call if you have any questions or comments.
</content>

</doc>
