<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri May 30 17:14:26 2003</date>
  <content>
Athens News - Letter to the Editor
 
There are many personal and professional websites that are appearing on the 
internet with figurative fingers pointing disapprovingly at Greece.  The 
testimonials and photos  giving graphic evidence of vicious animal cruelty in Greece 
are spreading steadily.  Cruelty news will, of course, eventually spread via 
the vast internet, which services millions of concerned people,  and to the 
international print and TV media.  
 
As the 2004 Athens Olympic Games loom ahead, the reports of pervasive animal 
abuse in Greece circulate and the ensuing global concern will gather momentum 
and as a consequence, wreak havoc on the  expectations and projected financial 
outcome of the Games.  This tragedy could so easily be avoided if the Greek 
government was truly willing to implement nationwide humane reform.  Greek 
officials disdainfully salute the world with their collective middle finger.
 
To date, government action in relation to  nationwide  vicious cruelty issues 
are in what appear to be a perpetual state of inertia and bureaucratic 
indecision.  Legal humane proposals sit idle before Parliament and the defenseless 
animals are taking the proverbial bullet for inhumanity.  In the interim, tens 
of thousands of innocent, unprotected, forgotten, abandoned animals are 
suffering and dying agonizing deaths via poisoning, hanging and shooting; as well as 
 by starvation and willful neglect.   At the same time billions of dollars 
are being spent on preparation for the Olympic Games infrastructure, airport, 
hotels, a new rail system, hotels, security and not a "drachma" has been spent 
to alleviate the suffering of sentient beings. 
 
This is a moral and social outrage.  When will this end?  The Greek 
government and her people appear to be  keeping this a "state secret". 
                                                                              
                             

 

</content>

</doc>
