<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct  6 06:46:38 2003</date>
  <content>
Las Vegas — Ildiko Pataki, a veteran acrobat of the Siegfried &amp; Roy show, 
heard a loud commotion and instantly knew something had gone badly wrong at 
The Mirage. Minutes later, Pataki watched as paramedics rolled out a 
bloodied Roy Horn on a stretcher. What many feared could happen had finally 
happened to the Las Vegas icon during a sold-out performance: A tiger had 
mauled him. "I was just petrified," said Pataki, 42, who had been with the 
show for 14 years. "I still cannot tell you how I feel about it. It was a 
nightmare."

Pataki was one of more than 200 people, many of them show employees, who 
turned out for a candlelight vigil Sunday night at University Medical 
Center, where co-headliner Horn is being treated. Horn, 59, suffered a 
severe wound to his neck when the 7-year-old male named Montecore attacked 
without warning Friday night in front of hundreds of people. Nobody was sure 
Horn would survive, but MGM officials finally delivered some good news at 
the vigil. MGM Mirage Resort CEO Bobby Baldwin said Horn's prognosis had 
improved. Doctors told Baldwin that Horn, who was in critical condition, 
could move his hands and feet and also gave a thumbs-up sign.

Those who attended chanted, "We love you Roy!" and held their candles in the 
direction of his hospital room. They described the people who worked in the 
show as a "tight-knit family" that had been rocked twice. First, they almost 
lost Horn. And now they had lost their jobs. With the co-headliner's future 
uncertain, MGM Mirage officials told the show's 267 employees Saturday night 
to look for new employment. MGM Mirage officials said the show was "closed 
indefinitely." They added that even if Horn recovers, it's unclear whether 
he would ever be able to perform again in the rigorous show. "We are not 
going to sugarcoat this," MGM Mirage spokesman Alan Feldman said.

</content>

</doc>
