<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Mar 19 07:37:18 2004</date>
  <content>
On March 10, Health and Human Services Secretary Tommy Thompson launched
public service announcements depicting dismembered body parts of fat
people -- double chins, stomachs, buttocks, and thighs -- caught in
grocery cart wheels, found by children along the beach and tripped over by
mall shoppers. They're part of Thompson's efforts to educate Americans
about obesity and persuade them to change their eating habits by showing
fat people what they should "lose."1
...
Meat

CSPI: CSPI's Perfect Diet states vegetarian diets are best and red meat is
"Heart Disease Enemy No. 1" and should be avoided because of its
"artery-clogging saturated fat." According to CSPI's A Dozen Diet Do's and
Don'ts, even lean meats are bad because they're not labeled so you don't
really know how much fat may be hidden in them. "Meat has also been linked
to cancer of the colon and prostate."

Facts: Scares over a link between red meat and cancer have been repeatedly
challenged by researchers.13 According to ACSH, scientists have found red
meat offers numerous healthful benefits. Meat protein helps build strong
muscles and appears to improve bone density in all ages, according to the
2002 Rancho Bernardo Study published in the American Journal of
Epidemiology. Meats, poultry and seafood are some of our best sources for
essential B vitamins and certain minerals, and play a significant role in
lowering our risk for heart disease.14 Beef is the biggest dietary source
of vitamin B12 and appears beneficial at lowering homocysteine, said
Klurfeld. Homocysteine is believed to be a major risk factor for heart
disease, as significant as cholesterol, yet nearly a third of vegetarians
have elevated levels as compared to 5% of meat-eaters. "Even though a
vegetarian diet can lower serum cholesterol, the opposite effect on
homocysteine could offset any potential benefit," he said.
</content>

</doc>
