<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 24 18:07:50 2003</date>
  <date>112303&amp;ID=s1444012&amp;cat=section.Animals</date>
  <content>
The tumultuous holiday season can be stressful enough for people who plan 
for it, but what about for our pets? The holidays can be satisfying and safe 
for your pet provided you take some steps to protect them from often hidden 
dangers.

Let's start with Thanksgiving. Roast turkey crowned with stuffing, mashed 
potatoes and giblet gravy, sweet potato casserole smothered with 
marshmallows, and pumpkin pie a la mode. That's just a partial list of what 
many will consume on Turkey Day, and the ambrosial description makes 
two-legged and four legged mouths water with anticipation.

Thanksgiving is all about giving thanks and sharing abundance. But before 
you think about sharing that mountain of meat, scrumptious leg bone, spicy 
stuffing, or amalgam of half-eaten desserts with your pet, think again. 
While overeating at Thanksgiving may be a "Tums time" for humans, it may 
result in an unexpected trip to the veterinary emergency room for pets, 
sometimes with tragic consequences.

Even if you don't end up at the emergency room with a pet, you may end up on 
your hands and knees cleaning up a smelly mess that spurted from either end 
of your pet. Unexpected dietary changes can lead to vomiting, diarrhea or 
worse. In fact, Thanksgiving keeps Dr. Steve Hansen, veterinary toxicologist 
and director of the ASPCA Animal Poison Control Center's staff, very busy. I 
recommend that you keep their Web site -- www.apcc.aspca.org -- handy, not 
just at Thanksgiving, but for any emergency that might arise.

Here are the top Turkey Day taboos:

• Bones: Bones are not as healthy and safe as you might think. Raw bones can 
contain bacteria, and cooked bones can splinter. As a veterinarian I've had 
to take ham bones off a dog's swollen tongue and round steak bones off a 
dog's lower jaw, remove rib bones wedged between the upper teeth along the 
roof of the mouth, and have had turkey-bone shards perforate the intestinal 
track, causing internal trauma.

• Fatty, rich foods: These typically include fatty trimmings off the ham or 
roast, turkey skin, butter-coated potato skins, and, of course, the gravy. 
Giving these to your pet is not a treat; it is dangerous for them.
</content>

</doc>
