<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 15 10:46:14 2003</date>
  <content>
For Immediate Release

FUND FOR ANIMALS ASKS JUNIOR COLLEGE TO CANCEL HUNTING COURSE

In a letter dated September 12 to 
Dr. Tom Delaino, president of Pensacola Junior College, The Fund for 
Animals, a national animal protection group with 200,000 members and 
active supporters, has asked the school to cancel a non-credit course in 
White-tailed Deer Stalk Hunting for Beginners. In the letter, program 
coordinator Norm Phelps said that the college Would never even consider 
offering a course in how to stalk and shoot dogs and cats because you 
would not want PJC to promote the cruel treatment of animals. The same 
reasoning should apply to a course in stalking and shooting deer. 
Phelps called hunting legalized cruelty to animals.

Noting that the catalog describes the course as geared to students 
8-80, Phelps said that, It is irresponsible to encourage children to 
go into the woods carrying high-powered, long-range firearms. They are 
too young to possess the mature judgement needed to use them safely, and 
many are not strong enough to consistently fire them accurately.
After pointing out that all of the virtues claimed for hunting, such as 
self-reliance, self-esteem, and an appreciation of nature, derive from 
the pursuit, not the kill, Phelps said, I am happy to see that you 
offer a course in Nature Photography (R00309). This course will teach 
all of the skills and provide all of the satisfactions of a hunting 
course  without teaching children and young people to kill innocent 
animals. I urge you cancel the course in deer hunting and send your 
students into the woods armed only with cameras.

Michael Markarian, president of The Fund for Animals said that, When 
you strip away the mythology, sport hunting is killing animals for 
pleasure. Community colleges should not be promoting this kind of animal 
abuse to anyone, least of all children.

</content>

</doc>
