<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar 28 10:39:59 2004</date>
  <content>
LOS ANGELES - Last season, they trashed chiropractors, psychics,
survivalists, environmentalists, creationists and space-alien molestees.
This year they're setting their sights higher, ruthlessly mocking love,
safety and the Bible. And, maybe, democracy.

''I would love to do a show just called, Your Vote Doesn't Count,''
confides investigative comedian-magician Penn Jillette. ``And just go up
against Rock The Vote. But I'm sure they'll squash me on that.''
...
But, though it may get lost among the purple language and the pranks, the
bedrock of P&amp;TB is old-fashioned journalism. That's never been more
apparent than in Thursday's season premiere, a hard look at animal-rights
zealotry.

After examining tax returns of the biggest animal-rights organization,
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals, Penn and Teller charge that
it has funneled tens of thousands of dollars to a confessed arsonist
linked by federal investigators to at least seven firebombings of
laboratories and farms. They also accuse PETA of killing more than 1,300
animals it ''rescued'' in raids on labs and animal shelters.

(PETA officials reacted with scorn last week to advance word of the
program. ''Penn and Teller's ratings for this show are as poor as their
longstanding lack of compassion for animals,'' said PETA spokeswoman
Jennifer McClure. ``PETA is fighting violence in society with peaceful if
sometimes gimmicky means; if Penn and Teller are going to try to cut and
paste in order to come up with some other interpretation, then shame on
their animal-hating agenda.'')

Although Penn and Teller narrate the episode while munching on spare ribs
and other former animals, the animal-rights show contains less of P&amp;TB's
trademark humor than usual. That's because, Penn and Teller admit, they
were scared by their own research.

''PETA is a scary organization,'' says Teller, the single-name part of the
team -- even his passport identifies him only as Teller -- who ordinarily
is silent. (He finally speaks in this season's premiere, but, predictably,
it's a word that makes newspaper copy editors throw up.)</content>

</doc>
