<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 13:11:08 2003</date>
  <content>
f you out there, to help me by making sure
 that justice will be done!
 Hopefully many of you remember the email I sent out on Sept. 12,
 2003, titled "TN State Law is not being enforced". It was about a
 case where there were 7 dogs, two adults and 5 pups, here in Houston
 County, TN, totally emaciated. First the Sheriff Dept. turned the
 case over to me, but when it came to enforce the Law, they refused,
 told me to leave the property, and, to top it all, the Deputy helped
 the owner in removing the animals from the same property, so there
 wouldn't be any evidences.
 I contacted the media, and asked for help to all I knew of, but no
 one helped! The thought of those poor creatures has been hunting me
 ever since.
 Last night, Nov. 1st, 2003, at 9:29 pm Central time, the 911 Houston
 Co. dispatcher, called me seeking my assistance in an animal cruelty
 case. I was put in contact with one of the two deputies at that
 location, and he told me that his supervisor, who is also the
 Sheriff's brother,  asked to get me out there to handle the case.
 A visiting friend of mine, and I left right away, and went to the
 location, which is only couple of blocks away from the location of
 the Sept. 12 case. Ironically I told my friend that it better not be
 the dogs! Once we arrived, I started to question the deputy to see if
 he knew, at that point, who the owner of the dogs was: SAME OWNER,
 SAME DOGS!!!!
 The deputy pointed at the small kennel where there were 5 pups, some
 dead, some still alive, and said that he couldn't go any closer to it
 because of the stinch. In the kennel we noticed moldy, and rotten dog
 food, a little pan with rain water in it, that was behind
 description, and maggots everywhere! Into a plastic container,
 resembling some kind of wast basket, there were two rotten pups, and
 three starving ones, that were feeding off the dead ones. There was
 no sight of the two adult dogs, although the smell pointed right at a
 parked vehicle.
 I demanded for the Sheriff, and/or the deputy brother of his, and/or
 the Assistant DA to talk to me and to come to the location. No one
 called. No one came.
 At this point the owner was threating us to get off his propery. The
 deputy tried to reason with him, and at last he consented to turn the
 pups over to us. Meantime, the deputy who was present during the
 Sept. 12 case, showed up, and we ended up just screaming at each
 other, because I made him look at those bodies, that he helped the
 owner with their removal on Sept. 12. Next thing, he was on the phone
 with the Assistant DA, and both ordered me to put the three pups
 back, or they would arrest me right there and then for theft, and
 trespass. 
 I have too many medical conditions to end up in jail on a Saturday
 night, especially when the Assistant DA himself  stated he would make
 sure I didn't get any help at least until the following Monday.
 We made it home at past 1:30 am, Nov. 2, 2003, with the above
 mentioned location only about 15 minutes away. We where there that
 whole time. I'm still expecting the Sheriff Dept. to come after me in
 one way or another.
 I'm begging each and everyone of you to help in seeking justice!!
 With all respect for other cruelty cases, we are not talking about a
 dirty food dish, nor dogs laying in their own feces, which is really
 bad, but nothing compare to this atrocity!!!!!

</content>

</doc>
