<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Feb 20 11:42:34 2004</date>
  <content>
Last week I talked about the problem with our Blacktail Deer populations. 
Oregon and other western states have been seeing a downturn in Mule Deer also for 
some time now also. There have been all kinds of theories as to why this is 
going on. Urban sprawl and lose of habitat are big ones and often given as the 
cause. Each state has an organization that is in charge of fish and wildlife. 
Here is the problem. 
Most organizations started out as departments of fish and game. The other 
animals were not regulated by these agencies. Then when the environmentalists 
found out how much money was going to these organizations because they were 
funded by people who were hunters and fisherman they found a way of tapping into 
this money. They caused a name change to wildlife and gave these organizations 
the responsibility for all critters. This started to strap these organizations 
for funding. Predators were listed as game animals and controlled. This was 
the beginning of the end.
Here in Oregon there was new and inventive ways of getting more money. The 
money for licenses and tags wasn't enough any longer, so more tags were offered 
for the female game animal, (doe deer and cow elk). This along with the fee to 
just apply for these tags brought in more money. The federal tax for firearms 
and other sporting supplies brought in more and more money from the federal 
government, however there was requirements that this money be applied to other 
than game animals and newly listed game animals. Now it is almost impossible 
to get enough money to study game animals and the problems of predation that 
surround them. When any agency attempts to do a study on predators and the 
effect they are having on game animals the enviro-nuts file suits in court to stop 
them. They know this is their Trojan horse to stop all hunting, and it is 
working like never before.</content>

</doc>
