<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Jun 23 22:55:55 2004</date>
  <content>
Here's a joke: Why did the vegan cross the road? Because the chicken was
about to beat him up.

Why did the butter-loving baker cross the road? Because the vegan cakes,
tarts and cookies were so good. No joke.

Thanks to cutting-edge pastry chefs with classical training, vegan
baking -- baking without animal products or refined sugars -- is now not
only good for you, but good tasting.

That's right -- adios, adobe cookies. Sayonara, straw cakes. Later on,
Uncle Manny's Whole-Wheat Hippie Brownies. Say hello to silken tofu pie,
bee-friendly baklava and custards without an egg in sight.

While you'll be hard-pressed to find all-vegan patisseries in your
neighborhood, there are a number of wholesale bakeries from Oakland to
Santa Cruz and Santa Rosa to Sacramento whose vegan baked goods are
available at Whole Foods, Berkeley Bowl, Wild Oats and Rainbow Grocery,
as well as at some coffee houses.
...
Why vegan?

People adopt vegan diets for health concerns and ethical consciousness.
Some people are allergic to dairy. Others can't stomach the thought of
eating animal-based products -- not just meat, butter, eggs or milk, but
white granulated sugar that may be processed using carbonized animal
bones; gelatin that's derived from cows, pigs or fish, and even honey
since it's produced by bees.

For bakers, producing tasty treats without the holy trinity of butter,
eggs or milk products is a challenge. Each of those ingredients plays
its own special role in structure, flavor and mouthfeel.
...
But Pearce, Costigan, Sibar and other vegan bakers certainly try -- and
succeed with appetizing results. Tofu and ground flax seeds substitute
for eggs' structural qualities. Some bakers use commercial stand-ins
such as Ener-G Egg Replacer, which includes a combination of tapioca and
potato flours. Fats such as canola oil and palm oil replace butter's
richness. While they lack the creaminess of cow's milk, soy, rice and
coconut milk are adequate substitutes. Natural products such as maple
sugar, evaporated cane juice, brown rice syrup and barley syrup provide
sweetness, tenderness and help extend shelf life. Unlike processed white
or brown sugars, which have no nutritive value, natural sweeteners
retain some fibers and nutrients.



</content>

</doc>
