<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul 28 15:04:58 2003</date>
  <content>

 Animal Voices runs every Tuesday from 11am-12pm EST; CIUT 89.5 FM
 in
 Toronto and the GTA (or catch us at www.ciut.fm).
 
 I am very pleased to announce tomorrow's guest on Animal Voices,
 Marc
 Bekoff. We'll be discussing Professor Bekoff's new book, Stolling
 with Our
 Kin: Speaking For and Respecting Voiceless Animals, as well as his
 perspective on science, animal rights, ecology, humane education,
 in
 addition to his work with Ethologists for the Ethical Treatment of
 Animals,
 and Jane Goodall's Roots &amp; Shoots program. Bekoff is truly an
 exceptional
 researcher and activist. The interview promises to be a very
 informative
 and interesting one. Hope you get a chance to tune in.
 
 
 For more information, check out http://www.literati.net/Bekoff/
 
 Here's an excerpt from Marc's bio:
 
 Marc Bekoff is Professor of Biology at the University of Colorado,
 Boulder, and is a Fellow of the Animal Behavior Society and a
 former
 Guggenheim Fellow. In 2000 he was awarded the Exemplar Award from
 the
 Animal Behavior Society for major long-term contributions to the
 field of
 animal behavior. Marc is also regional coordinator for Jane
 Goodall's
 Roots &amp; Shoots program, in which he works with students of all
 ages,
 senior citizens and prisoners, and also is a member of the Ethics
 Committee of the Jane Goodall Institute. He and Jane co-founded the
 organization Ethologists for the Ethical Treatment of Animals:
 Citizens
 for Responsible Animal Behavior Studies in 2000. Marc also is on
 the Board
 of Directors for The Fauna Sanctuary, on the Board of Directors of
 The
 Cougar Fund, on the advisory board for the Laboratory Primate
 Advocacy
 Group, and the Advisory Board for the conservation organization,
 SINAPU,
 and is part of the international program, Science and the Spiritual
 Quest
 II and the American Association for the Advancement of Science
 (AAAS)
 program on Science, Ethics, and Religion.
 Marc's main areas of research include animal behavior, cognitive
 ethology
 (the study of animal minds), and behavioral ecology, and he has
 also
 published extensively on animal issues.
 
 

</content>

</doc>
