<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jun 28 17:49:01 2004</date>
  <content>

GREEN RIVER -- Bird feeders and garbage are tempting targets for hungry
bears in residential areas of Jackson, Wyoming Game and Fish Department
officials say.

After more than two weeks and several phone calls regarding a nuisance 
black
bear, agency biologists killed a sub-adult female black bear just west of
Wilson on Monday, Game and Fish Bear Management Officer Eric Shorma said.

Shorma said the department received several reports of the bear getting 
into
bird feeders and garbage over the past few weeks. He said the bear was
easily identifiable because it was missing hair on its back.

"Unfortunately, this bear was very habituated and not afraid of people,"
Shorma said.

"The fact that it was in poor health was also a factor in the decision to
put the animal down," he said. "It was obvious this bear was going to
continue to seek out food in residential areas."

Shorma said the department is receiving an increasing number of calls about
bears.

He said biologists have already dealt with five nuisance bears in the
Jackson area this summer. Two of the bears were captured and relocated.

The department has instituted a wildlife feeding ban in Teton County, 
making
it illegal to have bear attractants -- such as bird feeders and garbage --
available to bears.

Shorma said it's legal to feed birds, but residents must make sure the
feeders are unavailable to bears and other wildlife.

"Whether there's an ordinance or not, we should be vigilant about keeping
our property free of potential bear attractants," he said. "We're fortunate
to live in a place with abundant wildlife ... but we need to remember with
that comes a responsibility to live compatibly with the wildlife."

Common bear attractants include garbage, compost piles, bird feeders,
barbecue grills and pet food, among others.

Shorma stressed the importance of contacting the local Game and Fish office
as soon as a bear causes problems. That ensures the best chance the bear 
can
be relocated, he said.



</content>

</doc>
