<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Aug  6 17:26:34 2003</date>
  <content>
These [genetically engineered] products are absolutely safe. For the most
part you wouldn't know [if you were eating them] but the point being that
you wouldn't need to know.

- Bryan Hurley,

Monsanto spokesperson

There is a great deal of controversy about the safety of genetically
engineered foods. Advocates of biotechnology often say that the risks are
overblown. "There have been 25,000 trials of genetically modified crops in
the world, now, and not a single incident, or anything dangerous in these
releases," said a spokesman for Adventa Holdings, a UK biotech firm.
During the 2000 presidential campaign, then-candidate George W. Bush said
that "study after study has shown no evidence of danger." And Clinton
Administration Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said that "test after
rigorous scientific test" had proven the safety of genetically engineered
products.

Is this the case? Unfortunately not, according to a senior researcher from
the Union of Concerned Scientists, Dr. Jane Rissler. With a Ph.D. in plant
pathology, four years of shaping biotechnology regulations at the EPA, she
is one of the nation's leading authorities on the environmental risks of
genetically engineered foods. Dr. Rissler has been closely monitoring the
trials and studies. 
...
GE Crops Can't Be Contained

A test conducted by the Wall Street Journal found that 16 of 20 vegetarian
foods labeled as being "free" of genetically engineered products actually
contained GE soybeans. As Arran Stephens, president of Nature's Path
Foods, noted: "You cannot build a wall high enough" to prevent genetic
pollution of wild and organic crops.

In August, a team of Belgian researchers were surprised to discover that
Monsanto's GE soybeans contained "a DNA segment... for which no sequence
homology could be detected." "No one knows what this extra gene sequence
is [or]... what its effects will be," said Greenpeace-UK's Doug Parr. "If
Monsanto did not even get this most basic information right, what should
we think about the validity of all their safety tests?"

John Robbins is the author of Diet for a New America and founder of
EarthSave International. Excerpted with permission from Food Revolution:
How Your Diet Can Save your Life and the World [Conari Press, 2550 Ninth
St., Suite 101, Berkeley, CA 94710, (510) 649-7175].

--</content>

</doc>
