<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jan 13 06:40:34 2004</date>
  <content>
Below the drumbeat of reassurances from government and the cattle industry
that the meat supply remains safe despite this one case of mad cow
disease, a small universe of scientists working on a family of related
illnesses is finding disturbing evidence to the contrary.

Several studies, including research at a government laboratory in Montana,
continue to spark questions about human susceptibility not only to mad
cow, but also to sister diseases such as chronic wasting disease, which
mainly affects deer and elk, and scrapie, which infects sheep. 
...
Most scientists believe the relatively small number of known human cases,
called Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease, strongly indicates this disease --
whatever its cause or origin -- is rare and difficult to transmit. There
is also no evidence yet that scrapie in sheep or chronic wasting disease
in deer has ever been passed to humans.

But some scientists say it's possible that chronic wasting, endemic in
Colorado's wild deer and elk, has sickened and proved fatal to humans.
These experts challenging the standard view note that doctors haven't --
or can't -- recognize signs of these other forms of the disease during an
autopsy. 
...
It's long been believed, for example, that only one of the two versions of
human CJD can be linked to eating meat contaminated with mad cow disease.
The other version, known as sporadic or classical CJD, has long been
thought to occur randomly in about one in every million people, a
distinctive illness with no link to meat from an infected animal.

But a few studies in the past three years have challenged that view,
suggesting that classical CJD, might, in some cases, also result from
eating contaminated meat.

Scientists in Great Britain injected tissue from a cow with mad cow
disease, also known as bovine spongiform encephalapothy, into mice whose
brains were genetically engineered with human genes. One set of mice fell
sick with the human form of mad cow, or new variant CJD. 
...
"Given the new research showing that infected beef may be responsible for
some (classical) CJD, thousands of Americans may already be dying because
of mad cow disease every year," wrote Dr. Michael Greger, a physician and
vegan advocate.</content>

</doc>
