<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Feb 23 13:18:02 2004</date>
  <content>U.S. foodmakers are scrambling to satisfy
consumer clamorings for low-carbohydrate products but also see a move
toward more balanced eating that could spell doom for the strictest
low-carb diets, like Atkins.

At an industry conference last week in Scottsdale, Arizona, companies
including Kellogg Co. and Hershey Foods Corp. touted products such as
low-carb cereals and chocolate bars catering to the millions of Americans
following diets that eschew carbohydrates like bread, sugar and pasta in
favor of high-protein foods and those made with sugar alternatives.

But even as they push these new products, companies which have been hurt
by the backlash against carbohydrates expect consumers will soon back off
the more extreme low-carb diets due to growing concerns about their intake
of artery-clogging fat and cholesterol.

Recent studies have put the number of Americans following low-carb diets
at anywhere from 10 million to 24 million. 
...
The negative reports about Atkins, which prompted a flurry of headlines
across the globe labeling him "Dr. Fatkins," come on top of numerous
public attacks by low-fat diet gurus such as Dr. Dean Ornish and nutrition
advocacy groups.

Late last year, the vegetarian group Physician's Committee for Responsible
Medicine created buzz by saying the Atkins diet could lead to heart
disease and may have contributed to the death of one teen-age dieter.

"You're beginning to see some publications and some articles about taking
these diets to an extreme," Kellogg Chairman and CEO Carlos Gutierrez told
reporters at the conference. "All these small events, whether it's
somebody on the news or whether it's a magazine article, they chip away at
the diet."

Kellogg is addressing concerns about the strictest low-carb diets in a new
television commercial for its Morningstar Farms vegetarian burgers and
patties, which the company says are naturally low in carbs. In the
commercial, a voice questions whether low-carb diets are being taken too
far, while a woman is overheard ordering veal chops, ribs, buffalo wings
and a burger without the bun. </content>

</doc>
