<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed May 19 01:26:53 2004</date>
  <content>

With high-spirits and strong guts, many people from all corners of the 
country take table-exoticas like frogs, ant eggs, locusts, crickets (kamaru,) dogs 
(as Azucena,) and duck eggs (balut) for their unique taste, and?believed to be?
potent effects. 
 Azucena (out of dogmeat) is an exotic food, widely eaten by Filipinos both 
in cities and rural areas because it is affordable and sometimes free. And as 
part of the exotic fiasco, stealing a neighbor?s dog is part of the whole 
process. 
Early during morning, the men from   dog pounds  are already roving the 
streets, looking or hunting for stray dogs?creatures that are candidates for being 
an azucena. Even in the earlier days, people from Northern Luzon, practice dog 
hunting, and cooking to feed prisoners from other tribes. For so, the custom 
of eating of man?s best friend has been going on for a long time?mostly 
prevalent to our brothers in the Mountain Province.  According to the writings of 
the Commissioner of Health in 1905, Mr. Victor Heiser, On the Benguet Road I 
often see Filipinos bound for the Saturday dog market at Baguio, each dragging 
along on a leash. This custom is however ruled out, at present, by ordinances 
and laws of pro-life organizations. 
However, in reality, people still eat dogs in the outskirts of Sagada, and 
illegal restaurants in Pangasinan; more or less, dog dishes like mechado and 
adobo are served in demand. Not to mention, even in progressive cities, despite 
laws and tight availability.
Usually Drunkards who can?t wait for regular dogmeat peddlers, dognap their 
neighbors? pets, or dogs wandering the streets. Dog thieves snatch the poor 
animal, and load it into a sack and kill it by striking a hard material on its 
head; then roast it over an open fire?a procedure to easily brush off the fur. 
Then, they wash the meat and cook it in their own preference. Caldereta, and 
adobo are some the most favorite Azucena dishes, and go best with beer or gin.
Another way of preparing it is starving the poor animal, then feeding it with 
rice until its belly bulge, full, before a swift kill, followed by the 
roasting method. After roasting, the undigested rice inside the dog?s stomach will 
be steamed naturally. Soon after, the coal-blistered animal?s belly is cut, 
open, and the rice will be eaten as a festive meal. It is said to be the greatest 
delicacy in the old days. Some lop its head, letting the blood flow, then cut 
its body open, the innards are removed and  usually cooked into tinumis. 
While its raw skin and liver are soaked in vinegar, garlic and onions, and made 
into kinilaw. 
Also, Dog blood is believed to be nutritious and beneficial to TB patients. 
Sufferers insert a straw into the animals jugular vein, to immediately suck the 
blood fresh. Also, as a myth, azucena is noted to be a great aphrodisiac, 
making the body extremely hot. But, like Ginseng roots, and other Aphrodisiacs, 
there is no concrete proof available to support this claim.


</content>

</doc>
