<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Sep 21 09:36:44 2003</date>
  <content>

When I moved to Oregon from England in 1976, "hunting" was just one of
many American words I failed to understand. Where I came from, hunting was
something you did on horseback with hounds. It was usually about killing
foxes, though sometimes in Scotland it involved deer. If you wanted to
carry a gun, you used your own two feet and went after pheasants and
partridges (the upper classes) or rabbits, hares and lowlier birds
(everybody else). This was called "shooting," never "hunting."
...
Objections to banning hunts tend to center on the expendable, too numerous
or even dangerous (to humans) nature of the animals concerned. Sometimes
tradition is invoked and always human superiority is assumed. But
underneath these objections, I believe, lies a more profound fear of what
might happen to us if we gave up our ritual engagements with death.

Whether we recognize it or not, exercising our power to kill other living
creatures keeps at bay the certain knowledge of our own frailty: our
vulnerability to cancer, old age, terrorism. I wonder who we might become
if we had to face this knowledge and live our lives in its shadow. I tend
to think we might be wiser and, perhaps, happier.

One day our descendents will look back on these ritual "sports" with the
same degree of disgust as we look back at the slave-gladiators killing
each other for the amusement of the Romans or the man who placed his own
daughter's head on the block. As for the foxes and deer, elk and bulls,
the random crows hanging from trees and the rabbits caught in traps -- all
those who entertain us by getting stalked and chased, wounded, shot or
torn apart -- they will surely be better off when we find something better
to do. Judith Barrington is a poet, memoirist and creative writing teacher
who lives in Portland. Her third collection of poems, "Horses and the
Human Soul," will appear next spring. 

--</content>

</doc>
