<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Feb 23 11:38:24 2004</date>
  <content>
AN ISLAND GP says it is only a matter of time before someone is killed in his area in a road accident caused by deer. 
Dr Julian Toms, based in Portree on Skye, has been prompted into collecting details of collisions after many of his patients and colleagues were involved in deer-related accidents. 
He is to pass his findings to his MSP and an Executive-backed research programme investigating deer collisions, which are seen as a significant and growing problem. 
It is estimated between 15,000 and 20,000 deer-related accidents occur in Scotland every year - about a quarter of the UK total - while at least nine people have died and ten been seriously injured in Scotland between 1996 and 2000. It is thought the accidents cost about £5 million a year, with another £1 million estimated in damage to vehicles. 
However, the current figures are only the tip of the iceberg, as accurate information on the scale of the problem, its geographical distribution, and accident black-spots is still lacking. 
Dr Toms said that since starting his study of the accident toll two weeks ago, he has been sent details of 11 road accidents involving deer which occurred in the last year, and is aware of another six collisions. Although none resulted in serious injury, the cost of damage to cars has ranged from £200 to £2,500. 
The most common accident hot spots are the A87 road, near the Cluanie Inn between Invermoriston and Kyle, and around Glenshiel in Wester Ross as well as between Broadford and Kyleakin in Skye. 
"I had an accident myself three weeks ago at Glenshiel when I hit a red deer hind. 
"My car is still being repaired at a cost of several thousand pounds. This was a Land Rover and had it been a smaller vehicle the hind may have come through the windscreen. 
"I work in a partnership of six doctors and now three of us have hit deer in the last 18 months. 
"I have a letter from a woman who was involved in an accident and who is now very afraid of driving on this road, so it's affecting people quite badly and making them hesitant about driving, particularly at night and in the winter." 
Dr Toms said many similar accidents go unreported each year and is to suggest that a system is introduced making reporting to police compulsory.He added: "A member of staff at the local hospital was in an accident when the deer came through the windscreen and right into the vehicle. An animal that weight and size could cause major injuries. 
"The other problem is that people try to avoid deer on the road and there is a risk of hitting another vehicle." 
Dr Toms's action has been welcomed by Professor Rory Putman, who is collecting information on deer accidents in Scotland as part of a two-year UK-wide project to develop a national register and highlight the scale of the problem and the worst affected areas. 
Prof Putman said researchers are now getting more complete details of accidents involving human injuries from all police forces, as well as information from insurance companies for claims to vehicles, from councils who have to remove deer carcasses, trunk road agencies and the Forestry Commission, stalkers, the Scottish Society for the Protection of Animals and members of the public. 
He said: "The information from people like Dr Toms will help us get more objective estimates of the number of incidents arising in Scotland and identify the hot spots." 
Ongoing research may help efforts towards preventative measures. These include removing roadside vegetation, erecting fencing to direct deer to a safer crossing point; reflectors which give a flash warning when they reflect headlights; and high-frequency whistles fitted on cars.
</content>

</doc>
