<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Feb 11 13:40:16 2004</date>
  <content>
Robert Atkins spent his life telling people they could eat fat and stay
slim. But according to his medical records, the man behind the Atkins diet
was obese at the time of his death.

The medical records, leaked to the media yesterday, also showed that Dr
Atkins had heart disease and hypertension, conditions that have been
linked to high-fat diets.

At first blush, the news has the potential to devastate the estimated 30
million followers of the counter-intuitive Atkins diet, which encourages
people to eat a diet high in protein (such as red meat) but low in
carbohydrates (cereals, pasta and rice).

But Dr Atkins's medical report was released by an organisation that has
long campaigned against his diet. It opposes consumption of meat and
promotes a vegan diet as a way of preventing cancer.

The medical report, leaked to The Wall Street Journal, shows that Dr
Atkins, at 1.83 metres, weighed 116 kilograms last year. This would have
given him a score of 35 under the body mass index calculation, used across
the world to define whether a person is of healthy weight or not. Under
the BMI, a score of 25 defines one as overweight. Over 30 and you are obese. 
...
Dr Atkins, a cardiologist, said in a TV interview three months before he
died that he had a heart attack in 2002 and that he believed his heart
disease was caused by a virus.

The medical examiner's office said this week that Dr Atkins's medical
report was "sent in error" to Richard Fleming, a member of the Physicians
Committee for Responsible Medicine, which runs an anti-Atkins website.

Dr Fleming last year released the diet book Stop Inflammation Now!, which
promotes a diet that is all fruit, vegetables and whole grains.

The Atkins company deplored the leaking of Dr Atkins's medical records to
"a known group of vegan and animal rights extremists".

Neither Dr Fleming nor the group he represents answered calls. </content>

</doc>
