<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 10 13:24:04 2003</date>
  <content> Beth Herr was ecstatic. 
For months, the curator of the Ward Pound Ridge Reservation had been 
following the movements of the park's 50-year-old wood turtles, an endangered species, 
and trying to improve possible nesting areas to encourage their breeding. A 
radio signal from the tiny transmitter on one turtle's back indicated she had 
stopped at a sandy pit built earlier in the summer by Eagle Scouts. 
"She poked her head up and I realized she was laying eggs," said Herr, who 
intended to come back later to protect the nest from predators. "I was so 
excited." 
She was also too slow. The turtle had deposited 62 eggs in three holes, but 
by the time Herr returned she found the nesting holes enlarged by claws, 
probably from a marauding raccoon, and all the eggs devoured. 
"It was so sad," Herr said. 
Such is the cycle of life and death in Westchester County's largest park, 
where curators have waged a concerted effort to improve breeding and feeding 
conditions for a variety of wildlife. For the past 15 years, curators have 
carefully chronicled and monitored the health of the inhabitants of the six 
ecosystems within the 4,700-acre park. Monitoring the breeding habits of the elderly 
turtles is just one of the latest efforts to improve the park's biological 
diversity and stem the loss of varying species of plants and animals. 
Volunteers and park curators spend thousands of hours each year on habitat 
improvement and scientific projects ranging from the low-tech sandboxes, used by 
turtles for egg laying, to the high-tech, water- and mud-proof radio 
transmitters fitted onto their shells. The curators have developed species management 
projects for each ecological system in the reservation. So far, those efforts 
have attracted more than 1,000 distinct species of plants, bugs, birds and 
animals, a level of biological diversity unmatched at any other county park. 

Park employees have encountered groups wading in the streams during picnics 
to catch and grill crayfish or gathering bags full of fiddlehead ferns for 
their salads. So the park has begun posting signs alerting visitors that what's in 
the park is for viewing, not hunting. In boggy areas, there are also signs 
alerting motorists to frog and salamander crossings. 
"During breeding season," Herr said, "we close the road because if the wea
ther is right, there can be 200 to 300 of them on the road, and people would just 
drive right over them. We want them undisturbed." 

</content>

</doc>
