<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Mar 21 21:56:15 2004</date>
  <content>
"Here's where the animals are brought in," Jim Tucker says. Tucker is 
talking about horses and pointing to what looks like a garage door. This is 
the door the horses will walk through to be killed -- horses that somebody 
sold for a few hundred bucks or less: the old ones, the slow ones, the mean 
ones, the lame ones, the ugly ones. Chances are, each horse will have a 
name. Chances are, each one will have pulled a load or carried a rider or 
eaten sugar from a child's hand. But the moment it goes through this door, 
its status will plummet to mere livestock, just a cow with spirit. Then, in 
the next day or two, it will be killed and skinned and gutted, carved into 
steaks and chops, and shipped to countries across the seas where people eat 
horse meat. The slaughterhouse is in DeKalb, 60 miles west of Chicago, and 
Tucker runs the place.

Which puts him in a tough spot. "No doubt about it," he says Friday 
morning, walking through the place, giving a tour. "It's an issue with some 
people." How much of an issue? What happens when you tell people what you 
do for a living? "For every 10 people, I'd say that maybe one or two are 
amazed," Tucker replies. "They won't talk about it. Most of the rest will 
say, 'I don't think there's anything wrong with that.' And a couple will 
say, 'Good for you.'"

Cavel International, a Belgian firm, operated a slaughterhouse for horses 
in DeKalb from 1987 to 2002. Some people in town protested, but Tucker 
likes to pull out old business stories from the local papers about how 
great it was for DeKalb. When the slaughterhouse burned down in 2002, Cavel 
decided to rebuild. The new plant -- a big block of gray concrete in the 
boonies of DeKalb -- is scheduled to open in a couple of weeks. It would 
employ 30 to 40 workers and could handle the slaughter of 100 horses a day.

A bill pending in Springfield, however, would close down the slaughterhouse 
before the first horses even showed up. The bill, which would ban the 
slaughter of horses in Illinois for human consumption, was approved by the 
Senate last year. An amended bill, backed by the state's five biggest 
racetracks, could be voted on in the House as early as Thursday.
</content>

</doc>
