<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Aug 23 00:01:45 2003</date>
  <content>
CANNIBAL COWS AND DYING DEER

Mad cow disease has killed more than a hundred people in Great Britain and 
may kill many more. The circumstances that created that epidemic exist right 
here. An infected cow was recently discovered in Canada--but not until after 
it entered the food supply


We all know (or should know) that factory meat farming is violent and 
environmentally destructive. You don't have to be a vegan activist to be 
disturbed by the conditions in which most meat animals live and die. And you 
probably already know that a large percentage of pesticide use, water 
pollution, and groundwater depletion is caused by the intensive cultivation 
of grain used to feed livestock, especially cattle. The environmental damage 
caused by the cattle themselves--the enormous expanses of land required, the 
destruction of native vegetation, the problem of what to do with all that 
poop--has fundamentally altered entire ecosystems. So that every supermarket 
can be packed with cheap beef and milk, every town can have scores of 
fast-food chain restaurants, and most Americans can comfortably participate 
in the fallacy that a meal is not a meal unless it contains meat, we feed, 
pump full of drugs, and confine about 96 million cattle every year. We kill 
about 30 million.

We would all be better off without so much meat. Still, the cattle industry 
has proved as resilient as most Americans are oblivious to the process by 
which that burger came to their table. Despite a decade's worth of bad news 
about beef, the average American still eats 66 pounds [in 1999], and beef 
consumption typically goes way, way up in the summer months. How many 
hamburgers have you had since Memorial Day?

A new player, however, has emerged in this game and could force the issue 
and destroy the multibillion-dollar beef industry: the infective prion, the 
agent that causes mad cow and similar diseases. Unfortunately, prions also 
have the potential to cause human suffering on an enormous scale. The recent 
discovery of mad cow disease in Canada and a good look at the ineffectual 
efforts to avoid it here show that the disease is not far away from us at 
all.


Meat Market Prions

Until the 20th century, most people who ate meat either grew or hunted it 
themselves; the animals you ate lived where you did and ate what they had 
evolved to eat. Now, though, we have the factory meat industry, to which it 
is difÞcult to offer any compliments. From the near-extermination of 
American buffalo to the return of the low-paying, dangerous slaughterhouse 
job to the present treatment of living creatures as commercial products 
packed in tight boxes and fed everything from cardboard to chicken shit, its 
unsavory history goes back more than 100 years.
</content>

</doc>
