<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Aug  3 07:56:53 2003</date>
  <content>
Although civil libertarians praise Attorney General Bill Lockyer for
denouncing spying on political protest groups, activists now say his
reforms don't go far enough.

Lockyer pledged to remind California's80,000 law enforcement officers that
civil disobedience is not terrorism and only a "reasonable suspicion" of
criminal activity justifies gathering information about political or
religious groups. 
...
Before the Sept. 11, 2001, attacks, state criminal intelligence analysts
rarely warned local police and sheriffs about protests.

But the state's anti-terror center, created two weeks after the attacks,
began sending out protest warnings within 45 days, tapping the Web, the
FBI and colleagues in other states for information about protesters. They
sometimes suggested that police spy on activists and report back. 
...
In early April, CATIC quoted threatening statements purportedly by a
former spokesman for the Earth Liberation Front, an underground
eco-sabotage group that the FBI classifies as a domestic terrorist
organization. The former ELF spokesman called for attacks on government,
military and corporate interests by "any means necessary."

CATIC analysts concluded that "protesters at past demonstrations with
causes similar to those expressed by ELF, ALF (the Animal Liberation
Front) and anti-war adherents have committed violent crimes to further
their beliefs," and warned law enforcement to expect activists and
"anarchists willing to commit acts of violence."

Three days later, CATIC again blended the former ELF spokesman's talk of
military targets into a warning about a Direct Action to Stop the War
protest at the Concord Naval Weapons Station. CATIC warned the U.S. Coast
Guard and the Contra Costa County Sheriff's Department of "potential
violence" at the Concord weapons station.

Direct Action organizer David Solnit called the bulletin "a hit piece" and
"a waste of taxpayer dollars."

ELF experts such as Skidmore College sociology professor Rik Scarce said
the analysis shows a fundamental misunderstanding of such groups.

"To lump together public protesters who don't violate the law at all with
folks whose entire tactical approach is stealth, to get in underneath any
sort of surveillance, do damage and get out, is just beyond belief," said
Scarce, author of "Eco Warriors: Understanding the Radical Environmental
Movement." 

--</content>

</doc>
