<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 10 04:13:24 2003</date>
  <content>
  Dog trainer Kasha Winston approached the 75-pound pit bull and 
mastiff mix, leaning toward its chain-link kennel in the city?s animal shelter. 
?Are you a nice boy?? she asked in a sugary voice. 

 The lean, muscular dog stood up on his hind legs, his front paws on the 
fence, his face inches from Winston?s. He growled. 
Winston stepped back quickly, shaking her head. ?I didn?t think so,?? she 
said. 
She jotted a note on her pad. 
A few kennels down, a pit bull-mix puppy greeted her by rolling on its back 
playfully when Winston opened its cage door and petted it. 
Winston was assessing which newly arrived animals were suitable for adoption. 
A few months ago, neither dog would have been a candidate because of the 
Norfolk Animal Management Center?s long-standing practice of euthanizing pit 
bulls. 
The city reversed the policy in September, and is now making some members of 
the controversial and often-abused breed available to those seeking pets. 
For years, concerns about pit bulls? potential for aggression, coupled with 
fears that new owners would train them for the fighting pit, kept the dogs off 
the adoption list. 
The only pit bulls that left the shelter were lost animals reclaimed by their 
owners. 
Shelters across the country attempt to match pets and owners, and more of 
them are initiating temperament testing programs, said Betsy McFarland, program 
manager for animal shelter issues with the Humane Society of the United States. 
Effective laws and policies target dangerous animals, not specific breeds, 
she said. Still, the Humane Society does ?recognize and support that many 
shelters choose not to adopt out pit bulls because of the high prevalence of 
dogfighting in their communities,?? McFarland wrote in an e-mail. 
Norfolk?s policy change reflects a belief that pit bulls can be suitable 
pets, and should be judged by ?deed, not breed.?? 
The deeds have been, at times, vicious 
. Pit bulls have ravaged each other in organized fights in Norfolk. 
Authorities have confiscated wounded dogs, dog-fighting videos and other accoutrements 
of the bloody contests.
</content>

</doc>
