<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Apr  9 20:43:52 2004</date>
  <content>Wilbur was savaged by a dog. Petey didn't eat much because of 
his overbite. Noah had kidney stones. Chief was going to be stuffed.
As Debra White strolls through the wooded 10 acres of her Winslow Farm, she 
tells the stories of each of the animals that waddle, lumber and trot up to 
greet her, sniff her hands, and nibble at the drawstrings of her jacket.
"They're my children," she says, as she stands in a pen inhabited by horses, 
llamas, emus and other creatures she's rescued from neglect, or worse.
Winslow Farm is nestled among colonial and split-level ranch homes, on a side 
street where trucks roar past the parking lot. But stepping through the 
handmade gate, visitors enter a seemingly enchanted world among the oaks and pines.


On the other side of the fence, soothing music is piped through hidden 
speakers, and the smell of burning sage fills the air from a fire pit. Stone statues 
peek out from under bushes, and birdhouses await springtime visitors.
But the most startling element of Winslow Farm is its inhabitants.
Cats mill underfoot, scamper up fence posts and skulk across the rooftops of 
buildings. Emus pick through leaves. Sheep and pigs loll side-by-side. 
Peacocks rattle their tailfeathers. Goats and ponies wander up to sniff visitors. The 
sound of crowing, clucking and honking animals fills the air.
"I've been blessed enough to be given this opportunity. I suppose I could 
have sold the land and had a good amount of money come in, and maybe traveled or 
something, but my mission is to do a good thing," White said.
White, 51, grew up on the property next to the farm. Her father was a 
mechanical engineer, but was so debilitated by Parkinson's disease that White says 
she served as his hands, learning how to build the things that he couldn't.
She inherited the 10 acres where she now lives from her grandparents, and 
planned since she was young to start a refuge for animals on the property. She 
worked three different jobs for 17 years to save enough to start the farm.
</content>

</doc>
