<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jul  6 20:00:48 2004</date>
  <content>
June 24, 2004 - SCI Sends Comments to Officials On Wolf Down Listing
Safari Club International has again spoken up for hunters. This time, SCI 
has submitted official comments to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service on the 
issue of de-listing the gray wolf. In western states, the deer and moose 
populations can be adversely affected by wolf overpopulation.

SCI has submitted official comments regards to the Service’s proposed 
regulations for the management of experimental populations of gray wolves in 
Idaho and Montana. SCI submitted their comments in support of the March 9, 
2004 proposed rule concerning the ‘Nonessential Experimental Populations of 
the Western Distinct Population Segment of the Gray Wolf.’

The Service published these draft rules “so that States with wolf management 
plans approved by the Service can apply for additional authorities to manage 
wolves consistent with those approved plans.”

The proposed rules are intended to give Idaho and Montana enhanced 
management authority over the experimental populations of wolves living in 
those states. Those two states have submitted gray wolf management plans 
that have been approved by the Service. Total delisting of gray wolves in 
these three states cannot take place until the Service has approved the game 
management plan of neighboring state, Wyoming. Once the Service has approved 
Wyoming’s gray wolf management plan, the Service will delist the species in 
all three states and will transfer management over the wolves to the 
individual states’ authorities.

SCI’s comments stressed continued management of carnivore and ungulate 
populations. These comments, submitted on May 10, 2004, stated that: “SCI 
and SCIF believe that impacts on ungulate populations must be regulated 
through effective management of wolves. The key to socially acceptable 
population levels of wolves will be productive huntable populations of 
ungulate species.”

</content>

</doc>
