<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 10 04:12:49 2003</date>
  <content>
During a nostalgic moment not long ago, I opened a can of beef ravioli, stuff 
I devoured as a kid. 
I couldn't wait to taste it, to revert, for a moment, to my childhood days. I 
took a bite and - yuck! - spat it out.
It was just plain nasty.
I checked out the label, trying to understand why, and saw a list of 
ingredients that seemed like something out of Dr. Evil's laboratory.
What were monosodium glutamate, caramel coloring, modified corn starch and 
enzyme modified cheese doing in there?
Something sinister happened to our food during the workplace revolution.
Food manufacturers started selling convenience foods that resembled real 
meals.
Heat and eat was their mantra. Working moms everywhere started snatching up 
frozen TV dinners, canned dinners and "add water and stir" meals.
But it's food that's so overprocessed, much of its original nutrients are 
gone. In its place are salt and fat - stuff that tastes good but later leaves you 
feeling lethargic and hungry.
Supermarkets are filled with that stuff. The consumer backlash only went so 
far.
The federal government doesn't force food manufacturers to make their foods 
healthier. They just require labels that tell consumers there is zero 
nutritional value.
So those of us looking for healthy food that doesn't contain synthetic 
additives, unnecessary preservatives and other chemicals shop at health food 
supermarkets, such as Whole Foods.
We buy organic apples because pesticides scare us. We prefer free-range 
chicken and hormone-free beef - the kind of food our parents used to eat when they 
were little.
We read labels. And we depend on the federal government to figure out what's 
unhealthy and either ban it from the marketplace or require full disclosure on 
the labels.
It's a given that we should know what we're ingesting. Right?
Well that may not be the case with beef, pork and chicken coming from cloned 
animals.
That's right. Cloned animal meat may be coming to a supermarket near you.
The federal Food and Drug Administration is planning to determine by next 
spring whether meat from cloned animals should be allowed to be sold for 
consumption.
Last week, an FDA advisory committee released a report saying that after 
reviewing numerous studies - mostly of cloned cattle - it found no significant 
differences between cloned animals and naturally bred ones.
I'm fine with cloning animals in the name of science. But in the wealthiest 
nation in the world, there's no need to breed animals for us to eat when they 
can be reproduced naturally.
Even if the FDA decides, after exhaustive studies, that it's OK to sell 
chicken breast, ham and pork chops that came from cloned animals, they should 
require a huge label on the package so those of us who want to bypass it - and I 
have to believe that includes most of us - can move on to the real thing.
Otherwise, a whole lot of us are going to become vegetarians.
</content>

</doc>
