<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon May 24 14:30:55 2004</date>
  <content>
Diane at Pet Protection down on highway 93 north of Kingman AZ. 
Licensed for 50 dogs. The largest rescue in entire county which spans
the entire grand canyon on both sides.  Usually has 250 or more tied up
to fence posts, 6 large dogs in a 10X10 cage for weeks on end.  Never
try to stop any fights. Never lets them out for exercise. Diane doesn't
live there, but 30 miles away.  Every caretaker I've ever met there was
so drunk or drugged up I couldn't even carry on a conversation with
them. They loose 2-3 dogs a week on the freeway out front.  In 20
months have had two fires destroying the caretakers home the second
time.  First fire killed 16 dogs. Second fire killed caretaker and two
small children and more dogs.  Both fires caused by meth labs.  Many
dogs die of disease or thirst with no shelter or can't reach food and
water bowls.  In my three visits, I've never seen the various
caretakers remotely sober or able to converse.  Doubt that alcohol is a
major problem, but am not sure what all is involved.
 
When entering the front gate, you see dead kittens laying by the gate -
nobody bothers to clean them up.  Now, they have some pigs running
around the yard and along the highway with no containment at all.  When
I went to offer some suggestions, the three workers there were sitting
out front drinking beer and playing cards and yelled at me to get out
of there.  'IF YOU WANT TO HELP US, GIVE US $5,000 OR GET THE HELL OFF
THE PROPERTY!!"
Kingman County offices or animal control is not online or even
computerized.  
I found a computer for them and got a corp. to donated their ISP but
nobody has ever called the donors to confirm or approve.  Over a year
now.  supervisor Lane Plunkett is nice man with head up butt and does
little to see improvements.   Real blame here goes to the city managers
and city council who do as most other cities by reducing the AC budget
each year as they also witness but ignore the problems increasing
drastically.  The city council thought I was being too outspoken by
asking them to pay $350 for the  upgrade to the computer world. I
reminded them I had found it as a DONATION then they complained it
wasn't in their budget or ''approved '' county equipment.  I reminded
them before being escorted out of the court room that the 35% pay
increase they voted for themselves was also not in their budget - what
a surprise.
 

</content>

</doc>
