<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jul  5 14:55:18 2004</date>
  <content>
On Sunday evening, June 27, 2004 my little 20 pound beagle, Maggie who was 2 
years old was shot and killed by a neighbor of mine who lives just beyond the 
woods.  He came to our home on Monday and admitted that he shot Maggie for no 
reason other than he suspected I took his Jack Russell who went missing 
several months before.  I do  K9 rescue work from my home and certainly did not 
steal his dog.   He said Maggie was not bothering him in anyway and was with our 
other beagle, Daisy who is traumatized terribly.  He said they were standing in 
the lane and he just snapped and shot Maggie.  He tried to shoot Daisy  as 
well but missed her.  He told us he thought he only injured our Maggie and he 
shot her with bird shot from some far distance.  He assured us she would come 
home and he would pay the vet bills.  Sadly, Maggie did not come home and I 
found her while searching frantically for her on Tuesday at the edge of this man's 
driveway on our family farm.  He had to ride by her everyday and look at this 
baby decaying.  I know my Maggie suffered horribly.  My vet examined her 
remains and verified she was shot with a slug.  

   Our local sheriff is telling us it is not a felony.  It is a Class 1 
felony in this state to shoot a dog for vengeance or premeditation.  Nothing has 
been done to arrest this man as of yet.  Please help by calling the sheriff's 
office at  and asking what is being done about this senseless 
killing.  The man who shot my dog is Wayne Forehand.  Please let us all ban together 
on this and get justice for Maggie.  Too many dogs are being killed like this 
and nothing is being done.  Please send this to as many folks as you can.  We 
need all the calls at that  sheriff's department as we can get.  We have to 
push him to make that felony charge.  I really need your help on this one.  I 
am begging you to please call.  
</content>

</doc>
