<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Dec  7 23:25:53 2003</date>
  <content>n his dim trailer in the pines, Virgil Butler writes of 
killing.

He once shot a man to death in the parking lot of a bar. In the American 
invasion of Panama, he killed at least two enemy soldiers at close range. But that 
is not the violence that drives him to his keyboard.

He is haunted, instead, by the nine years he made his way in the world by 
slaughtering chickens.

In the chilled dark of a Tyson processing plant, Butler killed 80,000 birds a 
shift. He snapped their legs into shackles so they hung upside down. He slit 
their throats. Every two seconds, another chicken came at him down the line, 
squawking and flapping. It was not possible, then, to think much.

But Tyson fired Butler last fall, for reasons the company won't specify. He 
has time now to think. The man he shot at the bar ? that was self-defense. The 
soldiers he killed ? that was war. It's the birds that shadow his sleep. He 
sits cross-legged on his sagging bed and pulls the keyboard to his lap. "There 
is blood everywhere.... It's just you and the dying chickens.... You are 
ashamed to tell others what you do at night while they are asleep in their beds."

Butler writes for hours each day. His words have electrified animal-rights 
activists around the globe.

Posted at http://www.cyberactivist.blogspot.com, Butler's account of a career 
on the kill floor is being translated into French and Dutch. Britain's 
Guardian newspaper has recommended his Web log as "powerful stuff," a "must-read." 
Supporters in Singapore and Russia e-mail questions. Strangers from across 
America send cards.

Veterans of the animal rights movement say Butler has done more for their 
cause than celebrity endorsements from actress Pamela Anderson and former Beatle 
Paul McCartney. Lucy Kelley, a 60-year-old cook in Mt. Juliet, Tenn., said she 
could find only one response to the blog: "I don't eat chicken any more."

"Virgil's description of the horrible abuse of chickens in our nation's 
slaughterhouses ... has turned more people vegetarian than anything else we did 
last year," said Bruce Friedrich, director of vegan outreach for People for the 
Ethical Treatment of Animals. With 750,000 members, PETA is the largest 
animal-rights group in the world. "We get letters and e-mails about it constantly," 
Friedrich said.
</content>

</doc>
