<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar  4 22:46:03 2004</date>
  <content>
After members of Takoma Park's food co-op voted nearly 3 to 1 last March
to keep the word "vegetarian" out of the organization's mission statement,
the member-owned grocery store took a dramatic step in February to better
compete with other retailers.

Starting last month, meat products started appearing on the shelves and in
the refrigerated and frozen food cases of the Takoma Park Silver Spring
Co-op's store in Takoma Junction.

It wasn't an easy decision for the store's management, especially since
the store was completely vegetarian -- albeit unofficially -- for the
previous 22 years.

"It was a tremendously difficult decision," said Bob Atwood, the co-op's
general manager, but a decision reached after consulting with members and
explaining the economics of the situation.
...
Convenience aside, the move to meat has received mixed reactions from
members of the area's vegetarian community. Former co-op member Paul
Shapiro of Takoma Park said he has heard complaints from members of
Compassion Over Killing, the animal rights and vegetarian advocacy group
he founded.

Shapiro said he is concerned the co-op never formally polled its members
on the specific question of selling meat at the Takoma Park store,
although Atwood said the membership vote last year was, in essence, a
referendum on selling meat.

Shapiro, who withdrew his co-op membership over the question of selling
animal products, also questioned some of the meat products sold in the
store, saying that he called several of the companies whose products were
labeled free-range, and that some of the companies didn't actually offer
free-range products.

"There are some people for whom 'factory farming' [where animals are
confined versus roaming freely] is the issue, while others say it's
unethical to unnecessarily kill animals," Shapiro said.

"We now have what was an all-vegetarian co-op selling some, but not all,
'factory farm' products," he added.</content>

</doc>
