<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 11:12:10 2003</date>
  <content>
    Undercover operations to expose the illegal trade in protected species 
are rescuing thousands of animals and decreasing demand for their pelts and body 
parts, but the operations also are provoking violence from criminal gangs. 
    A recent report by the international environmental organization Wild Aid 
revealed a series of gang-style killings related to the shark-fin trade in 
East Asia, a market dominated by Chinese triads. 
    In August, five person were killed in Fiji, apparently fighting for space 
in the black market. In February, a man sentenced to house arrest was slain 
in his home in Cape Town, South Africa, as part of the "Chinese mafia shark-fin 
war," the report said. 
    The Russian mafia and Latin American drug cartels also participate in 
illegal wildlife trade, while some poaching groups specializing in smuggling 
plants and animals or their parts using drug- and gun-smuggling routes. 
    In Europe, enforcement agents have been shot in gunfights with gangs, and 
in Latin America, several drug shipments have been discovered mixed with 
animals or plants. Snakes with bags of drugs inside are just a sample, according 
to a previous report by Traffic, of the World Wildlife Fund. 
    It showed, too, that the past two Chinese anti-poaching leaders in Tibet 
have been slain and that anti-poaching teams in many countries are often 
targets of assassination. 
    This type of trade is attracting organized criminals because of the high 
profits (up to 800 percent in some cases) and the lack of serious punishment, 
which leads to an estimated trade worth at least $6 billion annually in the 
world black markets. 
    "It's the most profitable illegal trade after drugs and guns," said Peter 
Knights, executive director of Wild Aid. 
    An example is rhinoceros horns, with prices of up to $40,000 per kilo, 
more than five times the price of gold, according to the organization Asian 
Conservation Awareness Program (ACAP). Not surprisingly, 97 percent of the world's 
rhinos were lost in the past 30 years. 
    Animals are wanted for food; for their skins, organs and bones; as exotic 
pets; or for traditional medicine in Asia. Several species are being pushed 
to the edge of extinction. The main markets are probably the United States and 
China. 
    In Cambodia, from 2001 to 2002, Wild Aid rescued 8,250 animals from 
illegal traders, helped apprehend 239 criminals and confiscate 1.3 tons of fresh 
meat and two tons of dried animal parts. 
    About 100 million sharks and shark-like fish are caught every year, and 
about 50 percent of them have their fins sliced off while still alive. Then, 
they are thrown back into the sea, where they sink and slowly die, so the rest 
of their bodies is wasted. 
    The fins are used for soup, an expensive delicacy in some parts of Asia, 
but finning has increased so much in recent years that fins are used even for 
canned cat food, said the Wild Aid report. ...
    Wild Aid regularly intercepts poachers, prevents them from killing 
animals and destroys their camps. It also goes undercover with hidden cameras to 
expose the traders' inner workings. 
    The gangs involved in illegal trade often take advantage of small 
communities. People in these communities do the killing or collecting and sell their 
catch cheap to the gangs, which profit. A parrot, for example, can be caught 
for $5 and sold commercially in the United States for $500. 
    International organizations send speakers to Third World communities to 
publicize alternative products and inform villagers and police about how to 
conserve wildlife. In Thailand, the poaching of some species has decreased 70 
percent with these efforts. 
    Campaigns in the media also have shown results. In Phnom Penh, Cambodia, 
where from 2001 to the end of last year more than 8,000 animals were rescued, 
75 percent of restaurants stopped serving wildlife dishes. 
    Wild Aid also operates an animal facility to care for creatures that are 
injured or have been in captivity too long to be released into the wild. 
    Not all wildlife trade is illicit. The Convention on International Trade 
in Endangered Species (CITES), signed by 164 countries, allows the commercial 
use of some species according to their extinction risks. 
    Noncompliance with the rules can lead to sanctions against trade coming 
from violator countries, said Simon Habel, director of Traffic North America. 
"But [illegal traders] know what they're doing ? clearly, corruption is an 
issue too," he said. 
    Some methods of smuggling involve falsifying certificates or sending 
animals to a country where it is not illegal to hunt them, then re-exporting them 
from there. Smugglers also hide wildlife in shipments of other goods and 
airport luggage. 
    



</content>

</doc>
