<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 29 01:58:09 2004</date>
  <content> bronze sculpture of Marjan, the Kabul Zoo's ailing lion who 
became a symbol of war-ravaged Afghanistan, will be on display later this year at 
the N.C. Zoo for a few months before it is shipped overseas.
A Texas sculptor is preparing the bronze of Marjan who received worldwide 
attention more than two years ago through the Kabul Zoo and Afghanistan animal 
fund-raising effort coordinated by the N.C. Zoo and the N.C. Zoological Society.
N.C. Zoo Director Dr. David Jones, who has been actively involved with 
efforts to help the Kabul Zoo, updated members of the N.C. Zoo Council Feb. 25 about 
the global outreach project.
"Marjan the lion stimulated interest in the wildlife in Afghanistan," Jones 
said.
Bob Coffee, an Austin, Texas, sculptor, submitted a proposal nearly two years 
ago to create a memorial sculpture of Marjan and Kabul officials agreed to 
the donation.
"This old, busted-up lion, with one eye, his jaw hanging down - he was the 
symbol of this country. Old, ailing, but proud, like Afghanistan," said John 
Walsh after Marjan died in January 2002.
Walsh has been international projects director of the World Society for the 
Protection of Animals, a partner in the international effort to help the zoo.
In a 2002 visit to the local zoo, Walsh expressed the hope that a sculpture 
of the lion would be installed at the Kabul Zoo with only three words to 
describe Marjan, who was 24 years old, and the country's people - Old. Ailing. 
Proud."
Hundreds made donations to the fund after learning about the plight of Marjan 
who was found to be blind in both eyes and had been at the zoo during 23 
years of war and cruelty in Afghanistan. He had lost one eye to a grenade in the 
1990s and lost weight during the war years. The apparent cause of death was 
kidney and liver damage.
More than $600,000 has been raised, through the N.C. Zoo and its nonprofit 
support organization, the N.C. Zoological Society, to aid both the beleaguered 
Baghdad and Kabul zoos and animals in Iraq and Afghanistan.</content>

</doc>
