<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Feb 24 22:02:11 2004</date>
  <content>
Do not know if t
We have very busy and very important days ahead of us from now through
March 2nd.
 
On Saturday, February 28th  there will be a 15th Congressional District
March of Delegates and Kucinich Volunteers starting at 96th Street and
Broadway (southwest corner in front of Rite-Aid) where we will meet at
11:00 am.  
 
NYC Friends of Kucinich is providing posters on cardboard tubes and some
literature.  If you have any literature left on Saturday which we can
distribute along the route of march, please bring it.  Delegates, if you
would like to make some sort of sign to wear or carry identifying
yourself as a candidate for delegate, please do so.
 
We will march on the sidewalk up Broadway to 125th Street where we will
make a turn.  We will then walk across 125th Street to Lexington Avenue. 
At that point, those who wish to continue will take the A train up to
181st Street, from where we will march down to 165th Street.   
 
If we have not already told me you are definitely participating (or not)
in the March, please call me  or send me an email reply
ASAP.  If you are a Washington Heights/Inwood person and want to meet us
up there, please let me know now so we can arrange the logistics of
timing with you.
 
There are a few other items as well.
 
First, in these remaining days, please try to get out and leaflet as much
as possible ? in any moments you can spare.  It is also helpful to call
and email any undecided friends and family to try to convince them to
vote for Dennis.
 
Second, please let me know if you would like lists of prime voters whom
you can call.  Scripts and instructions are included.  By the way, if you
have phone numbers of people you registered to vote, be sure to call them
on Monday, March 1st and remind them to vote for Dennis.
 
Finally, please let me know if you will be able to pass out our beautiful
new palm cards at the specified distance from your polling place on
Primary Day.  Even if you have an hour before or after work, that would
be wonderful!  We will have the cards for you at the March ? or you can
pick them up from me, I can get them to you or you can download them and
print them yourself from www.nycfordennis.com.
 
I look forward to hearing from you in the next day or two by reply email
</content>

</doc>
