<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb 29 01:58:20 2004</date>
  <content>
With La Fiesta de los Vaqueros in town, opposing views on the treatment of 
rodeo animals are back on the front burner. 
The Animal Defense League of Arizona (ADLAZ) and two other animal-activist 
groups are planning to hold a protest Sunday outside of the Tucson Rodeo 
Grounds. 
Group leaders believe rodeo invokes naturally docile farm animals into 
violent behavior through acts of animal cruelty. 
Those working for and on the Tucson Rodeo Committee said rodeo livestock is 
too valuable to be treated poorly. 
Gary Williams, who has been general manager of La Fiesta since 1995, said 
that animal activist groups do not base their opinions on fact. 
"Animals are these people's livelihood," Williams said of those involved in 
rodeo. "These animals aren't pets. They can withstand things other animals 
cannot." 
"We are going out to protest the inherit animal abuse at the rodeo," said 
Gary Vella chairman of the ADLAZ. "People pay attention when you hurt kittens or 
puppies, but when it comes to farm animals they turn their head." 
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) has long been against 
rodeo. 
PETA, the largest animal-rights organization in the world, contends rodeo 
animals are treated cruelly and sent to slaughter once the event ends. 
One intolerable action is using flank straps, which go around an animal's 
abdomen and groin, a PETA official said. 
"The straps can cause them to suffer internal bleeding," Amy Rhodes, senior 
animals in entertainment representative, said from the PETA national 
headquarters in Norfolk, Va. "They also cause sores or other injuries." 
The Professional Rodeo Cowboys Association states in its animal welfare 
pamphlet that the flank strap does not induce animals to buck, but instead 
"augments the bucking action, encouraging a bucking bronc or bull to kick high with 
its back feet." </content>

</doc>
