<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat May 31 17:58:51 2003</date>
  <content>
LAS VEGAS MAKES CONSCIOUS DECISION TO KILL MORE ANIMALS THAN OTHER CITIES IT'S SIZE.  Lives, nor
even the safety of innocent animals fall short of the almighty dollar.

"Oh, Praise Mary Greenspun Almighty"  or so she demands anyway.

TO: The Las Vegas Media Community and Residents
                             (seeking a knowledgeable hard hitting attorney for this case)
 
It's not likely that many of you who live in the Vegas area will ever see this or have a single
idea that this huge scandal exists and is continuing in your community.  WHY?
Because, the person in the very center of stealing your money is the woman who owns both
newspapers and some of the TV stations in Las Vegas. 
 
As in all crime stories, there is a 'boss' and the 'triggerman' or in this case 'trigger woman'.
Janie Greenspun will play the part of the ‘boss’ here and her ‘trigger woman’ will be known as
Mary Hero who made her millions from the Animal foundation.
 
These two women are about to launch yet another campaign to raise millions off 
the backs of dying innocent animals through deceitful and highly questionable fundraising
practices they’ve made so much money from over the years right under your noses.  It seems as
though using the poor animals to raise funds for their luxurious homes and lifestyles isn’t
enough.  Since the mainstream public in Las Vegas has no time to find out the facts, the two women
are now the likely candidate to receive the County’s animal control contract in 2005 issued by the
Clarke County Supervisors - yes, the same ones who are under investigation by the FBI on several
illegal dealings and operations they have been involved with, USING YOUR TAX MONEY!!  One would
quickly assume that the entire group is somehow involved in undermining the reputation as well as
the operations of the city. The Clark County board of supervisors is likely to award the contract
for animal control to her in 2005. There are other qualified entities in Clark County who would be
much more suitable for this contract, but until the public realizes that the problems that the
animal facilities face is actually the fault of the community at large, the awarding of this
contract seems to be a given. The county refuses to budget appropriately and nobody receiving this
contract will be able to make the appropriate changes that make the difference until the community
is made aware of who is actually running the majority of the animal orgs and learn to make
necessary changes in their lives as well.  
 
The simple fact that they have spent so much time in pointing fingers and accusing others of so
many  things, proves three things:  1.these two women do NOT hold the safety and welfare of the
animals in the highest esteem and would rather divert the public’s attention away from what
isreally going on , 2. they forget what they are ‘supposedly’ accepting the money to accomplish –
as if there just arent’ enough animals to help, so they use extra time and  money to make this a
competition, and 3. the community is quite unaware that they are being ‘taken’ in this game they
play.  NOBODY WINS, but the animals really loose. Now, it’s not the millions of dollars they’ve
made from running the Animal Foundation for so many years. Anyone who can solve these problems in
a community or our nation should be made a billionaire on the spot.  But the animal problems
continue in Clarke County. This type of ‘female’ bickering  leaves the good people who actually
try to help the animals, to fend for themselves and eat off the bottom of the barrel.  They are
the ones who will really make a difference, but are pushed aside and forced to close.
 
Janie, the ‘boss’ is known to sue anyone who just might stand up and look as if they may be
pointing a finger at her.  Many even suggest fear of personal injury or harm to themselves, should
they speak out.  One who is actually being the complete opposite of a caring individual is most
appropriate to describe Ms. Greenspun. Finally, one who needs to be exposed and stopped.

The attempted ouster of  Hero came last summer just a few weeks after the entire management team
of the Lied Animal Shelter from 2001-2002 called for Mary Herro's removal as president.  This team
included two veterinarians, and three managers, and the former director of operations there.. 
They all stood together to blow the whistle on the fraud and mass killing at the Lied Animal
Shelter, particularly after Mary reinstated her horrible daughter Stacy as the manager of the
shelter.  The result?  More than 800 killings in just one month -- June of 2002!!  (The board did
demand and receive Stacy's dismissal.)

Meanwhile, they raise money and hold themselves out as a no-kill sanctuary.  This while animals
are slaughtered just for having ringworm or kennel cough, or are killed in mass numbers out of
Lost &amp; Found - never even making it to adoptions - if considered old, ugly, or otherwise chosen
for death.  In addition, many know that the Animal Foundation failed its two audits by the city
(one in 1998, the other in 2001).

</content>

</doc>
