<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 22 10:24:06 2003</date>
  <content>

Guam to benefit from coral reef summit

The ancient and beautiful rock-like animals that live under the transparent
sapphire waters surrounding Guam will be getting a lot of attention in a few
weeks. 
Those animals are the ones that protect the island during typhoons, that
house the fish we later turn into kelaguen and sashimi, and that many
believe are the island's No. 1 ticket out of its economic blues. 
Attention, as well as money and other kinds of support, is what Guam's coral
experts and managers are hoping the island's reefs get out of next month's
Coral Reef Task Force meeting, which will be held in the Mariana islands for
the first time, according to the Task Force's Web site. 
In a rare moment for Guam, dozens of officials from as many federal agencies
will all be on island at the same time. Representatives from entities
including the Department of the Interior, Department of Transportation,
Department of Commerce, Department of Justice, Department of Defense and
even NASA will arrive on island to make sure they are on the same page in
halting what they call the global "coral reef crisis." 
According to Gerry Davis, the Department of Agriculture's Division of
Aquatic and Wildlife Resources chief and one of the main organizers of the
meeting, the meeting's purpose is to bring all entities that have a stake in
the future of the planet's reefs to one place. Officials from each entity
will present a report on their progress and an action plan for the future,
as well as ask for the financial and logistical support they need to protect
the nation's reefs. 
The coral isn't the only thing to benefit from the Task Force meeting,
according to Davis. With dozens of dignitaries on island, he said, it will
afford the governor and others the opportunity to ask for other help, such
as funding to help clean up the sewage outfalls in Hag?t?a Bay, money to
close the Ordot dump or cooperation in resolving Guam's conflict with the
U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service over the Critical Habitat designation. 
</content>

</doc>
