<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct 27 07:16:18 2003</date>
  <content>
Ernest Hemingway will be turning in his grave: Barcelona is planning to 
deliver the coup de grace to bullfighting. 
The author had a lifelong love affair with bullfighting and wrote evocatively 
of its "spiritual intensity." 
But public opinion in Spain's second city has swung against the ancient 
sport, and talk of a ban is rife in the corridors of the city council and the 
parliament of Catalonia, the region that includes Barcelona. 
One senior member of Barcelona's ruling Catalan Nationalist Party said it was 
"only a matter of time" before an official ban was proposed and that 
bullfighting could disappear from the city "within a few years." 
Opponents of bullfighting argue that the slaughter of more than 100 bulls a 
year for public entertainment is anachronistic and incompatible with 
Barcelona's ambition to become one of the world's leading cities for arts and culture. 
Animal welfare campaigners want bullfighting banned by the end of this year 
because they say it will taint the 2004 Universal Forum of Culture, a festival 
that Barcelona is hosting. 
Bullfighting has already been halted in several Catalonian towns, and in June 
the regional parliament became the first in Spain to ban children under 14 
from attending corridas de toro. 
Opponents of bullfighting are protesting not only because of the "cruelty" of 
the sport but also as part of their campaign for independence from Madrid, 
the Spanish capital, where the corrida remains highly popular. 
One anti-bullfighting Bar-celona politician said, "We are forging our own, 
distinctly Catalan identity based not on the outdated public slaughter of 
animals but on the arts, music and architecture." 
Talk of a ban is a red flag to bullfighting supporters. The Catalan 
Bullfighting Federation attacked the campaigners as "ill-informed." 
"Bullfighting is an art form and a vital part of our history and culture and 
gives jobs to thousands of people," said German Jimenez, the federation's 
spokesman. A ban would mean caving in to "ignorant" and excessively delicate 
modern sensibilities about animal welfare, he said. 
Jimenez warned that the prospect of a ban could bring thousands of 
bullfighting supporters on to the streets in protest. 
Aficionados endorse the views of Hemingway, who saw bullfighting as a ballet 
led by a proud, elegant matador. In Death in the Afternoon, he writes of "the 
emotional and spiritual intensity and pure classic beauty that can be produced 
by a man, an animal and a piece of scarlet serge draped on a stick." 
Barcelona has only one of its three original bullrings left -- La Monumental 
-- and there are only four in all of Catalonia. 
</content>

</doc>
