<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 19 21:31:55 2004</date>
  <content>A funny thing happened even before the polar ice cap
dropped on our doorstep this month:

After more than a decade of giving fur the cold shoulder, young
fashionistas cozied up to it.
...
Fallen from favor are the big-haired, broad-shouldered beaver coats of the
1980s. Faded from the public consciousness are the guerrilla paint attacks
and PETA's "I'd rather go naked than wear fur" ads, which commanded
attention in the early '90s.

Replacing them are everything from discreet shearlings to chubby jackets
in "Monsters Inc." colors. A host of former spokesmodels for People for
the Ethical Treatment of Animals (Cindy Crawford, Naomi Campbell, Claudia
Schiffer) have turned on their heels and strutted in more than one skin since.
...
"No one is (saying), `What about animal rights?' I've never really thought
about it. That whole thing happened when we were younger, when my mom had
a fur and she stopped wearing it," said O'Brien, regional producer for the
Gen Art organization, which promotes young artists, designers and musicians.
...
Regan, a retired North Carolina State University philosophy professor,
says that the formerly potent Coalition to Abolish the Fur Trade has
disbanded. Trans-Species Unlimited, which sponsored day-after-Thanksgiving
"Fur-Free Friday" protests starting in 1985 in New York, "ran with that
for 10 or 15 years," he said. "They just kind of got worn out."

Other groups, such as PETA, maintain anti-fur campaigns, but "those
particular organizations whose primary focus was fur have just
disappeared," Regan said. "And no one has stepped in to take up the slack."
...
Regan, a vegan who doesn't wear leather or wool, dislikes some animal
rights tactics. But he believes some progress has been made. The number of
mink ranches has declined from 1,000 in the '80s to about 300, he said.

"You'll find a significant decrease in the body count," he said.</content>

</doc>
