<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Apr  9 16:44:09 2004</date>
  <content>
The widely held notion that Canada is taking excellent care of its wild, 
pristine lands ? far better than the gluttonous citizens in the United States ? 
is nothing more than a misperception approaching myth. Americans, or Yanks as 
they are often called up north, are frequently verbally assailed by Canadians 
with the misplaced and perhaps na?ve notion that all U.S. citizens are swine 
when it comes to caring for and preserving quality country.

Canadians, in contrast, are valiant, conscientious souls who have no blood on 
their hands. This stance is at best spurious and possibly created to hide the 
fact that the western provinces of Alberta, British Columbia, the Northwest 
Territories, and the Yukon are being plundered at an astonishing rate.

While I was having a couple of drinks in a bar called The Pit in Dawson City, 
Yukon, last summer, a Canadian came up to me and asked where I was from. When 
I told him he said, "You damn Yanks don't give a damn about your own land. 
You log it and stripmine it all to hell. Then you come up here to enjoy our 
country." Over the years I've heard many comments along those lines.
 
True, there are individuals in Canada who have devoted their lives to 
preserving the land and there are, as most of us know all too well, greedy people 
tearing apart the last remaining shreds of unspoiled country in the United 
States. But fair is fair, and the bottom line is that Canadians should take stock of 
their own environmental situation before gleefully casting aspersions 
America's way.

Forty years of being an inveterate road bum, traveling back roads on a skinny 
budget, fishing malarial bogs, inadvertently canoeing class V whitewater, 
hiking nonexistent trails bound for nowhere, and unavoidably staying on top of 
environmental issues in Canada has provided me an ongoing opportunity to see 
disturbing change in a land of incredible splendor and abundance ? one peopled 
with some truly remarkable, generous, and creative individuals. But in the last 
five years, these destructive shifts in direction have been seismic, both 
metaphorically and literally.

Land Under Siege

The notion that Canada is the great white sustainable north is not wholly 
without merit. On the Environmental Sustainability Index, developed by Columbia 
and Yale Universities, Canada is ranked fourth and the United States 45th. 
Canada allows industrial hemp production, while the United States prohibits it, 
and is also a signatory to the U.S.-shunned Kyoto Treaty on global warming.

But when it comes to allowing extractive industries to run rampant, Canada 
may be king. From Fort Nelson in northern British Columbia to Rocky Mountain 
House in central Alberta to the vast Tintina Trench region in the southern Yukon 
and over east to Yellowknife on Great Slave Lake in the Northwest Territories, 
the landscape is under siege. The extraction industries are running the show, 
tearing, blasting, sucking, and cutting every diamond, gold nugget, drop of 
oil, chunk of coal, and stick of timber they can access. If it's of value, 
these industries intend to have it.

What's going down in western Canada puts the devastation being visited on 
states like Montana, Wyoming, and West Virginia look mild by comparison. What are 
obviously horrendous clearcuts or devastating open-pit coalmines in the U.S. 
West are everyday situations in Canada too. Both countries are mining their 
natural resources at an alarming rate.

Canadian provincial campgrounds are filled to the brim with late-model 
pickups tricked out with all the options and pulling expensive fifth wheelers and 
pricey speedboats, ATVs, and jet skis. The Cypress Hills section along the 
Alberta-Saskatchewan border, the setting for Wallace Stegner's book Wolf Willow, 
are now so overrun as to resemble a scene from National Lampoon's Vacation. 
Housing developments in cities such as Calgary and Edmonton stretch for miles with 
thousands of quarter-million-dollar homes. 

All of this comes not only from the jobs provided by these corporations but 
also from royalties paid by the industry based on the amount of a given mineral 
extracted from a province. In Alberta, this figure exceeds $6 billion 
annually just for coal. The money is flowing in direct proportion to the abundance of 
the oil coming from countless wells hammered into the Canadian countryside. 
The old phrase "a chicken in every pot" has been updated in the northland to 
"an oil pumpjack in every yard."</content>

</doc>
