<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Aug 14 13:42:27 2003</date>
  <content>
Man charged with assaulting girlfriend; killing kitten


BELLEVUE -- A 25-year-old Bellevue man has been charged with first-degree 
animal cruelty, a felony, for killing his girlfriend's 6-week-old kitten in 
what prosecutors said was a drunken rage.

Arturo "Art" Federico was also charged on Wednesday with fourth-degree 
assault, a misdemeanor. King County prosecutors said he pushed his 
20-year-old girlfriend around, choked her and then locked her out of the 
apartment they shared.

He is being held at the King County Jail in lieu of $50,000 bail, Dan 
Donohoe, spokesman for the King County Prosecutor's Office, said Wednesday.

Federico was arrested about 3:30 a.m. Sunday, shortly after he ran from the 
apartment as police arrived, said Bellevue police spokeswoman Marcia 
Harnden.

A K-9 officer and a police dog, Bosco, gave chase. They caught Federico in a 
cemetery behind the apartment building, Harnden said. Bosco bit Federico's 
head during the arrest, so he was taken to Overlake Hospital Medical Center 
for stitches.

Federico's girlfriend told police that he began drinking around 10 p.m. 
Saturday, according to court documents. An hour later, she saw him "hold the 
kitten in both hands and throw the kitten down (on the bed) with what 
appeared to be all of his strength," then pick up the cat and throw it down 
again.

When she confronted him, he "began to yell (that) the kitten had scratched 
his eye," she told police. Twenty minutes later, Federico began pushing and 
choking her before locking her out of the apartment.

She was able to get back inside an hour later, only to find her kitten, Mr. 
Sampson, dead.

Federico previously had threatened to kill the kitten, she told police. The 
kitten had suffered other injuries. Federico explained to her that he'd 
accidentally opened a door on the cat, and in another instance, the kitten 
had jumped into an oven.
</content>

</doc>
