<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Aug 19 13:06:36 2003</date>
  <content>

Sept. 26, Alicia Silverstone will make her debut in a new NBC series called 
"Miss Match," which the network hopes will permeate the fashion consciousness 
much in the manner of "Sex and the City," on HBO. Like that series, "Miss 
Match" counts Darren Star as one of its creators and covers the subjects of lust, 
love, misery and renewal, set in a world of overpriced drinks.In the series, 
Ms. Silverstone plays a Los Angeles divorce lawyer who inadvertently begins 
acting as a matchmaker to her clients. For diversion, her character spends 
evenings at a stylish bar modeled after Les Deux Caf?s in Hollywood, which means 
that her wardrobe requirements extend far beyond courtroom tweeds.In fact, 
wardrobe requirements turn out to be fairly complicated. In real life, Ms. 
Silverstone is a vegan whose politics prohibit a great deal more than fur. "She will 
not wear wool," said Roberta Haze, the show's costume designer and a veteran of 
"Sex and the City" and "Veronica's Closet." "It has something to do with the 
way the sheep are treated. Alicia gave me some of the literature explaining it 
all." Silk is also verboten. "But I don't know the whole story with the 
silkworms yet," Ms. Haze said. She has bought Ms. Silverstone stretch-cotton suits 
from Dolce &amp; Gabbana and a corduroy jacket from Fred Segal. Like many animal 
rights activists, Ms. Silverstone is leather-averse, so it has been 
particularly challenging for Ms. Haze to keep her attractively shod. "There are synthetic 
shoes, of course, but there aren't many I like looking at," she said.Ms. Haze 
has worked around the problem, though, offering the star the option of 
vintage shoes from Decades on Melrose Avenue. Because the production of those shoes 
violated animal welfare so long ago, Ms. Silverstone's thinking goes, they are 
permitted through a grandfather clause."She isn't demanding," Ms. Haze said. 
"She brings all of her own special food to the set. I think she's a very 
spiritual girl."  

</content>

</doc>
