<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Jun 10 15:52:03 2004</date>
  <content>
 The summer barbecue season is upon us. What better time to revisit the
 topic of mad cow disease? Before you plop that slab of Ol' Bossie on the
 grill, before you slather up that rack of beef ribs with Joe Bob's
 Country BBQ sauce, take a moment to think about what you will be eating.

Several months ago, this column went into some detail about the
possibility that mad cow disease (or BSE) may have already infected
America's food supply. Knappster took considerable grief from my
carnivorous friends who now regard me as a pinko, semi-vegetarian cow
sympathizer. A few of them growled and complained about their God-given
right to swallow chewy flank steak, to guzzle gristle, ravage ribs,
masticate bull testicles, to kill and eat anything with four or more
legs. They suspect that I raised the mad cow issue as part of a
surreptitious animal welfare campaign.

Admittedly, there are animal welfare issues involved. The things that are
done to docile cows in the name of hamburger are mind boggling and
revolting. However, the more pressing issue for humans is the health
question. Is the American beef supply reasonably safe and free of BSE?
Since my last article on this topic, several disturbing things have
happened.

Anyone remember Dave Louthan? He's the guy who discovered the first
American mad cow case back in December. A few weeks later, Louthan was
fired from his job at a Washington meat plant where he had worked for
four years.

The reason Dave was fired is because he dared to tell reporters
that--contrary to official pronouncements--the mad cow in question had
been ground up into hamburger and had already been eaten by consumers.
More chilling, he told people that the BSE-infected cow was not a
so-called downer cow, but, rather, had been up and walking around when it
was slaughtered. The reason this is so scary is that America's first line
of defense against BSE cattle is to weed out downer or disabled cows, to
keep them from becoming dinner. The USDA requires very little BSE
testing, so it is up to the meat packers to pick out the sick animals and
keep them out of the food chain. 



----------
</content>

</doc>
