<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Apr 26 10:39:08 2004</date>
  <content>

Lawmakers must put more teeth into the Animal Welfare
Act 

   A massive law enforcement sting operation in Barrow
County last week thrust the scourge of cockfighting
out of the shadows and into the forefront of public
attention.
   The April 18 raid on a Hancock Bridge Road farm
resulted in 238 arrests on misdemeanor charges of
animal cruelty and gambling. A couple leasing the
farm, Larry Otis Fleming Jr. and Misty Fleming, were
charged with felony-grade animal cruelty and gambling.
   Law enforcement officials believe the farm was a
venue for cockfights and dog fights with pit bull
terriers on most Sundays. The sting was the result of
an eight-month investigation by a handful of local,
state and federal police agencies.
   Many of those arrested were Mexican immigrants
hailing from states throughout the Southeast,
according to news reports. While legal in Mexico,
cockfighting is banned in the United States in every
state except Louisiana and New Mexico.
   In addition to seizing more than $130,000 in cash
during last week's bust, Barrow County officials also
took custody of nearly 140 fighting roosters and six
dogs.
   It was the second such raid on a major gambling and
animal fighting ring in Northeast Georgia this year.
More than 100 people were arrested in Newton County
during a dog-fighting sting in January.
   Illegal animal fighting is not a new phenomenon,
but in the past, it has been limited to small,
transient operations. The stings in Barrow and Newton
counties uncovered the illegal practice on a much
larger scale - more gamblers, more animals and more
money.
   Because animal fighting is often considered a
gateway crime - one which fosters other illegal
activities, such as drug and weapons trafficking - the
appearance of such large and brazen operations in our
region should be of concern to residents and public
officials.
   Not only do we need to fully enforce existing laws
against animal fighting, but these statutes should
also be reviewed to ensure they meet our needs.
   One area of federal law has been targeted for
reinforcement by law enforcement officials, animal
rights activists and poultry industry representatives.
They believe federal penalties outlined in the Animal
Welfare Act's fighting provisions aren't stiff enough
to prevent violations or encourage prosecution.
   Legislation now before Congress would help toughen
this regulation by increasing imprisonment terms from
one year to two. Supporters say the heightened
penalties are particularly important to curb the
illegal interstate transportation of dogs and birds
for fighting. The bill also would prohibit the
interstate sale or shipping of the razor-sharp spurs
attached to the legs of cockfighting birds.
   Though this measure has been in the works for
years, it has not been acted on yet in this Congress.
The delay certainly is not for lack of support. More
than 51 senators and 196 representatives are listed as
sponsors, and there are indications the Bush
administration also may back it.
   A recent endorsement by the National Chicken
Council, a poultry industry group, greatly improved
the legislation's chances. According to a statement on
the council's Web site, the bill will help reduce the
dangers associated with the unregulated trade of
fighting birds. The council believes the interstate
transport of these birds can lead to the spread of
avian diseases, such as Newcastle disease, an outbreak
of which could cripple the poultry industry.
   So far, Georgia's Sens. Zell Miller and Saxby
Chambliss and Rep. Max Burns have not signed on to
this valuable legislation. When this bill comes to a
vote, we hope our members of Congress will strongly
support it. If not, they need to be prepared to
explain why.
   Given the potential benefits to law enforcement as
well the extra protection afforded to Georgia's
valuable poultry industry, it's hard to fathom any
reason our leaders would oppose it.
    

</content>

</doc>
