<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Feb  8 11:46:23 2004</date>
  <content>

It's not hard to spot some pampered pets. They sport jaunty plaid coats or 
elaborate rainbow harnesses, or wear hats that match their owners. They are 
spoken to only in baby talk, and get their nails done more often than the crew of 
"Queer Eye for the Straight Guy"

But for every Shitzu in a beanie, there are hundreds of other coddled 
creatures who live in the lap of luxury, though they remain unseen and unsung. Their 
owners spend thousands of dollars a year on pet supplies to keep their 
"babies" in fine things, but don't necessarily think of themselves as excessive. 
In fact, many of them don't fit the stereotype of the socialite with her pug 
in a Prada bag. They are our friends and neighbors, coworkers and our family 
members. They are also the proud parents of truly pampered pets.

According to a 2003-04 survey conducted by the American Pet Products 
Manufacturers Association, 62 percent of Americans are pet owners, and they spent $31 
billion dollars last year on pet care, not including medical care. One out of 
three households has at least one dog or cat, and one-third of small animal 
owners consider their pets to be children or family members.

Terri Nicholas of Corvallis didn't always own a menagerie. It really happened 
to her slowly. Her children were grown and had moved out, and were making 
families of their own. The house was a little empty. So Bailey the ferret moved 
in.

Nicholas learned to love ferrets when her daughter was living at home, and 
when daughter and ferret moved out, she decided to get one of her own. Bailey 
was the first, and six years later is the beloved eldest pet, but she certainly 
wasn't the last.

Camille was a pregnant, ill stray cat who wandered into Nicholas' life one 
rainy Christmas Eve. It took a lot of medical care to get Camille into good 
health and spirits, but she's now the queen of Nicholas' household.</content>

</doc>
