<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Nov 25 20:40:38 2003</date>
  <content>
MOGO Zoo's celebrity resident is now on public display after 30 days in 
quarantine.
Ijuma the giraffe became an instant idol during his road trip from the Sydney 
docks to his new Eurobodalla Shire home last month.
His transporter trailer literally stopped traffic along the Princes Highway, 
with countless motorists and bystanders taking the opportunity to gawk at the 
18-month-old giraffe.
Now visitors to Mogo Zoo will be able to enjoy watching the purebred male 
Rothschild in the open.
Ijuma is gradually being acclimatised to the wide-open spaces and will soon 
be able to roam the African Plain area of Mogo Zoo with the zebra, oryx and 
ostrich.
Head keeper Phil Whelan, who hand fed the giraffe during its eight-day voyage 
from New Zealand, said Ijuma had taken all the changes in his stride.
"He's been fine," Mr Whelan said. 
"He's got a beautiful temperament, if he was a horse you could call him 
bomb-proof."
Mogo Zoo owner Sally Padey said Ijuma was given a clean bill of health from 
quarantine officers this week, signalling the end of a massive operation to 
re-house the giraffe in Australia.
"This has been the biggest thing we have ever done," Mrs Padey said.
"It has cost us $20,000 plus just to get him here, what with shipping, 
quarantine fees etc.
"We really have to say a very big thankyou to the Coachhouse Resort for all 
the help that they gave us in bringing him to Mogo Zoo.
"Over the years, the support that has been shown to us from the businesses in 
Batemans Bay has been truly amazing."
Mrs Padey is smitten with Ijuma's eyes.
"I think if half the models in the world had eyes and lashes like he has they 
would be worth even more squillions," she said. "He just has the most 
beautiful eyes."
And she's expecting him to be big hit with visitors.
"A lot of people have been asking about him," she said, "he created so much 
interest with his trip down here.
"People have been able to catch glimpses of him [in his shed] but now he is 
out on display and we hope to have a female coming for him in the near future."
</content>

</doc>
