<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue May 25 11:40:55 2004</date>
  <content>

On March 2nd, California state Senator Rico Oller lost
a competitive, three-way Republican primary for the
U.S. House seat for the 3rd Congressional district
that sweeps from the suburbs of Sacramento through the
Sierras and to the border of Nevada.  With a late
surge, former Attorney General Dan Lungren edged out
Oller by about 2,500 votes.  There were several
decisive factors in the race, but one of them surely
was Oller’s appalling record on animal welfare issues
and a concerted campaign by animal protection
advocates to short-circuit his run for the House.

During his eight years in the state legislature, Oller
had opposed some 20 animal protection bills, including
measures to strengthen laws against dogfighting and
cockfighting, to provide elemental care standards for
dogs on puppy mills, and to require that antifreeze
contain a bittering agent to prevent accidental
poisoning of pets and children.  In addition, Oller is
himself an enthusiastic bear hunter, specializing in
hunting with hounds.  A typical hound hunter chases a
bear with a pack of radio-collared dogs and drives the
bear into a tree, shooting the animal at point-blank
range – a practice that even most hunters find
loathsome. 

Humane USA, the national political action arm of the
humane movement, mounted an independent expenditure
campaign against Oller that made use of mailings,
radio advertisements, and the dozens of volunteers who
went door-to-door in the district.  Polling work done
by humane organizations had revealed that most voters
– regardless of party – find animal fighting,
high-tech hound hunting of bears, the mistreatment of
dogs on puppy mills, and other forms of animal abuse
to be repugnant.  In the end, the independent
expenditure campaign -- combined with a complementary
effort by the Republican Mainstreet Partnership that
focused on other aspects of Oller’s background --
acquainted voters in the district with Oller’s record
and caused them to look to other candidates.

Since its founding in 1999, Humane USA has singled out
a number of candidates who have exhibited deplorable
records on animal protection.  A notable target was
Georgia’s outspoken U.S. Representative Bob Barr (R). 
Barr had been among just three dozen or so legislators
who had voted against legislation pushed principally
by Republican lawmakers to ban the commercial sale of
videos depicting illegal acts of animal cruelty,
including so-called “animal crush” videos, in which
women in high-heeled shoes stomp small animals to
death for the sexual gratification of viewers.  Humane
USA made an issue of this vote in his 2002 race
against veteran Rep. John Linder (R-GA), and helped
cement the view that Barr, like Oller, was too extreme
and did not deserve to serve in public office.  

</content>

</doc>
