<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Jan 19 15:15:27 2004</date>
  <content>
Shifting dogs
December 2003: Networking and transportation have always been a critical part of the rescue process, especially in low-population breeds and those without well-distributed foster homes. It's not unusual for a purebred dog in a Nebraska shelter to be driven to a rescue service in Chicago that has an available foster home. Arranging transportation to permanent adoptive homes is also common. 

For the most part, these transports involve one or two dogs at a time, from a shelter to a rescue service, from one rescue to another, or from a rescue to a pre-approved adoptive home. The latter is becoming more common as the Internet helps breed rescue groups in different areas do reference and home checks for one another. About two-thirds of the messages posted on rescue email lists are requests for home checks and transport arrangements for individual dogs.

Also assisted by the Internet, entire groups devoted to transport have been created. Manned by volunteers unable to foster dogs themselves but wanting to help in other ways, the best known and most professional of these groups is the Canine Underground Railroad (CUR). CUR volunteers must meet strict membership criteria, undergo background checks, and provide references. The dogs transported must also meet a standard of temperament and health, and have had pre-travel medical care such as vet exams, vaccinations, and spay or neuter. 

On the increase, however, are transport programs that are literally cleaning out shelters in one part of the country and bringing dogs en masse for placement in another. This practice began about 10 years ago when New York's North Shore Animal League began retrieving mixed breed puppies from rural shelters in southern states and bringing them north for placement. There was, the shelter alleged, a shortage of puppies in New York thanks to aggressive spay/neuter programs and reduced breeding. NSAL provided financial grants in exchange for puppies so the shelters could establish their own spay/neuter programs. This philosophy soon spread to other large shelters in the northeast that began making treks down south to relieve their own shortages. 

</content>

</doc>
