<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 18 10:02:48 2004</date>
  <content>
Recent policy changes at the Houston Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to 
Animals create an interesting dilemma for the community: What to do with 
homeless dogs and cats? The board of directors for a public charity determines the 
mission and policies of an organization. The Spay-Neuter Assistance Program, 
or SNAP, for example, has chosen to focus solely on spaying and neutering of 
dogs and cats as its mission, as opposed to animal sheltering and adoption 
programs. The HSPCA has decided it is no longer able to care for stray animals and 
instead it is going to focus its time and resources on the re-homing of owned 
pets, humane education, animal rescues and animal cruelty investigations. 
Prior to the policy change at the HSPCA, every one of the five animal 
sheltering agencies in Houston was 
already filled to capacity with homeless dogs and cats. The effect of the 
HSPCA policy shift will be to cause stray animals who would have been normally 
admitted (and euthanized) at the HSPCA to either be turned loose on the 
streets, where they will certainly multiply and most likely die from injury or 
disease, 
or to be admitted and euthanized at one of Houston's other animal sheltering 
agencies. 
The problem is not that the HSPCA has changed its policy. Rather, the problem 
is that there are very simply too many dogs and cats and not enough homes for 
them all. It's not a matter of "more" animals being euthanized. It's just a 
matter of which agency will be responsible for the destruction of homeless 
animals. 
The control of stray animals (and the diseases they spread, such as rabies) 
is clearly a function of government and its public health programs, not a 
function of private animal sheltering agencies. If the city of Houston and Harris 
County did more to prevent the breeding of cats and dogs and the proliferation 
of homeless puppies and kittens in the first place, there would be less of a 
need to destroy homeless animals in our community. </content>

</doc>
