<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Apr  4 13:06:06 2004</date>
  <content>
When Temple Grandin surveyed slaughterhouses in 1996, only 36% of the
plants were doing a good job shocking the animals senseless before slaughter.

Many had animals falling on slippery floors, mooing or squealing in pain,
while being repeatedly whacked with cattle prods.

Now, her system of measuring key indicators of stress and pain has
revolutionized cattle and pork processing plants, including Madison-based
Odom's Tennessee Pride Sausage, which has a slaughterhouse in Arkansas.
...
Companies such as McDonald's are counting the number of falls, the amount
of mooing and the number of animals stunned correctly, all in an attempt
to ensure a better end for the animals.

''There is no question in my mind that handling is dramatically better
compared to the 1990s,'' said Janet Riley, a senior vice president of
public affairs and professional development at the American Meat Institute.

Even animal rights groups applaud the changes.

''Just the fact that these slaughterhouses are doing audits is a big step
in the right direction,'' said Dan Shannon, a campaign coordinator for the
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals, which advocates diets without
meat or dairy products. ''But the audits are only eliminating the very
worst of the abuses. These animals still suffer. They're still terrified,
and they're still being abused in a number of ways.''
...
The improvements in the pork and beef industry have redirected some
attention from them to the poultry industry, which is exempt from the
humane slaughter law.

People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals, known for its shock
campaigns, has begun a ''bloody bucket'' campaign, handing out buckets
filled with fake blood and bones to children dining in KFC restaurants.

Many more chickens, an estimated 8 billion of them this year, will be
eaten in the United States than pigs or cows, further giving reasons for
the animal-rights activists to go after the poultry industry.</content>

</doc>
