<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Dec 22 14:11:22 2003</date>
  <content>
    A federal judge's decision to ban snowmobiles in Yellowstone and Grand 
Teton national parks is a victory for those who rightly believe that our 
national parks should be protected from polluters so that all Americans can 
enjoy their beauty.
    U.S. District Judge Emmet Sullivan in Washington, D.C., was wise to halt 
action by the National Park Service to reverse a Clinton-era rule that would 
gradually remove the noisy, exhaust-spewing machines from the parks over two 
years.
    The snowmobile industry lobbied the Park Service long and hard to get 
the ban overturned, arguing that snowmobile riders have a right to motor 
through Yellowstone and that manufacturers could produce less-polluting 
machines.
    The Park Service argued that allowing 950 snowmobilers a day in 
Yellowstone and 400 in Grand Teton would balance the agency's dual mission 
of protecting the park while allowing visitors to use it.
    None of those arguments swayed the judge, who deftly cut to the core of 
the debate in noting that the Park Service's primary job, "rarely . . . 
trumped by other considerations," is to conserve the pristine natural beauty 
of the parks.
    The air and noise pollution from snowmobiles are unkind to national 
parks and to all the people who manage to see them without ruining the 
experience for others. According to the Environmental Protection Agency, a 
single, unregulated two-stroke snowmobile engine can emit as much pollution 
as nearly 100 automobiles. Models that manufacturers said would emit fewer 
pollutants have turned out to be more powerful and sometimes even dirtier 
and noisier.
    Americans who want their national parks to remain places of natural 
beauty and tranquility oppose snowmobile traffic. More than 90 percent of 
the public opinion gathered by the Interior Department during the last 
comment period was against allowing snowmobiles in Yellowstone. Four former 
Park Service directors who served under both Republican and Democratic 
presidents urged Interior to enforce the ban.
    Those who say the ban limits winter park access to skiers and snowshoers 
are ignoring the continuing operation of snow coaches that carry 10 people 
at a time. Coach passengers -- including the elderly, families and those 
with disabilities -- can view scenery not enshrouded in a polluted haze and 
watch animals not bothered by the noise from hundreds of snomobiles.
    And it's not as if the ban would eliminate the machines from hundreds of 
miles of snowmobile trails just outside the parks.
    National parks should be accessible to all, but granting special access 
to snowmobilers destroys important qualities the parks were created to 
protect. So they must go.

</content>

</doc>
