<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Wed Dec  3 16:07:35 2003</date>
  <content>
A surface mine might not seem like an ideal elk habitat. 
But because of the recovery efforts of two local mines, elk herds, 
sharp-tailed grouse and a variety of other animals are thriving at reclaimed mine sites 
In Moffat County.
Last year, the United States Department of the Interior named Trapper Mine 
one of the three best examples of mined land reclamation in the 25-year history 
of the federal surface mining laws.
Colowyo Coal Company, LLC was also honored last year for its deployment of 
innovative state-of-the-art technology, using global positioning systems (GPS) 
to improve efficiency and accuracy of spoil grading activities.
Collin Scott, environmental expert at Colowyo, said that a herd of 500 to 
1,500 elk usually winter on their reclaimed land, and sharp-tailed grouse, 
populations of which have declined precipitously over the western U.S. range, have 
been documented as making a rapid population increase at Trapper Mine.
The animals' habitat has been created by an expensive, time consuming mine 
reclamation process.
Mining companies are legally obligated to restore mined land to original 
conditions once operations are finished. 
"Reclamation is a process that begins before the first shovel full of dirt 
has been removed," Scott said.
Mines need permits to dig, and to get a permit, mine operations must develop 
a reclamation plan. Scott said the plan means taking inventory and studying 
the soil, vegetation and wildlife of the intended mine area.
Mining operations must bond their work, in the event that they default on 
their obligation to reclaim the land. Trapper Mine recently bonded new mining 
land for $25 million.
Earth moving is 75 percent of reclamation work, Scott said. That means 
backfilling mined areas and then grading the backfill. The goal is to blend the 
disturbed area into the surrounding area as best as possible.</content>

</doc>
