<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Fri Dec  5 07:54:53 2003</date>
  <content>With the trail growing cold, the FBI yesterday announced
it is offering a $50,000 reward for information leading to the arrest of
Terra Linda High graduate Daniel Andreas San Diego, who is wanted in
connection with two East Bay bombings linked to animal rights causes.

Also yesterday, authorities released newly unsealed search warrant
affidavits in which the FBI spells out much of its case against San Diego.

Among new information revealed is that one of the bombs had nails attached
to act as potentially lethal or maiming shrapnel. No one was injured in
the bombings.
...
"My wife and I do not believe that he is responsible for the conduct with
which he is charged," said an emotional San Diego, reading from a
statement while his wife stood at his side on a rain-soaked plaza at the
San Francisco Civic Center yesterday afternoon. "Nevertheless, we
recognize that the government has brought a serious charge, and it must be
addressed by our son. While we know Andreas must be frightened, we hope he
will come forward and confront this accusation, knowing that we will stand
by him throughout this ordeal."
...
An animal rights group calling itself Revolutionary Cells claimed
responsibility for the explosions and said the two companies were targeted
because of their ties to New Jersey-based Huntingdon Life Sciences, which
conducts drug and chemical experiments on animals for other firms.
...
The FBI searched computers and hard drives at San Diego's home, apparently
looking for the electronically posted messages taking responsibility for
the bombing, but officials said yesterday they could not make a direct link.
...
While his parents yesterday said their son is "a thoughtful, responsible
young man" the FBI considers him a threat.

"We believe he is a dangerous individual," Traver said, noting San Diego
has a handgun registered to him that has not been found. "He has
accomplished two bombings, and he had a truckload of material to do it
again. Whatever his cause, he is passionate about it. He will try and bomb
again somewhere, and he has upped the ante with the use of shrapnel." </content>

</doc>
