<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 11 17:09:44 2004</date>
  <content>                                                 
Dear Dog and Cat,                                                         

       When I say to move, it means to go someplace else, not switch 
positions with each other so there are still two of you in the way.                 

       The dishes with the paw print are yours and contain your food.  The 
other dishes are mine and contain my food.                                      

       Please note that placing a paw print in the middle of my plate and 
food does not stake a claim for it becoming your food and dish, nor do I find 
that aesthetically pleasing in the slightest.                             

       The stairway was not designed by NASCAR and is therefore not a 
racetrack.  Beating me to the bottom is not the object.  Tripping me doesn't help 
either, as I fall faster than you can run.                                

        I cannot buy anything bigger than a king size bed.  I am very sorry 
about this.  Do not think I will resort to sleeping on the sofa to ensure your 
comfort.  Look at videos of dogs and cats sleeping.  They can actually curl up 
into a ball.  It is not necessary to sleep perpendicular to each other 
stretched out to the fullest extent possible.                       

       Please note that sticking tails and tongues out to maximize space used 
is nothing but sarcasm.                                                      

       My compact discs are not miniature frisbees.                           
   

      For the last time, there is not a secret exit from the bathroom.  If, 
by some miracle, I beat you there and manage to get the door shut, it is not 
necessary to claw, whine, try to turn the knob, or get your paw under the edge 
and try to pull the door open.                                       

      When I exit this room, I will come out the same door I entered.  In 
addition, I have been using bathrooms for years.  Canine and/or feline attendance 
has never been necessary.  
</content>

</doc>
