<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Jan 11 14:31:42 2004</date>
  <content>
Marion the Barbarian has the best nickname among the 
15 gray wolves.

Marion is docile with her human handlers. She is outgoing and loves to chew 
shoelaces. But she is a terror to the wolves around her. She has bitten every 
wolf and driven some from the pack. She spends large amounts of time pacing in 
her pen. She is the queen.

Male wolves fight for fun, but female wolves, especially super alpha females 
like Marion, fight for life-and-death, volunteer Rebecca Bailia-Sisk said.

She offered that tidbit to a group of wolf-loving tourists during a 45-minute 
walking tour at Wolf Park, a combination zoo-research center with hand-raised 
wolves that are socialized to humans.

The park is now closed for the season (it reopens May 1), but during these 
off-season months, visitors can attend the center's very popular 90-minute wolf 
howls/lectures on Saturday nights. It is chilling to hear the howls, yelps and 
moans up close. (There is, by the way, less howling in the summer.)

The 75-acre facility seems strangely out of place surrounded by cornfields 
and soybeans near Lafayette in the flat farmlands of northwest Indiana, 130 
miles southeast of Chicago.

The center--it gets 20,000 visitors a year--is generally considered one of 
the best wolf centers in the country, along with the International Wolf Center 
in Ely, Minn.

During the season (May 1-Nov. 30), Wolf Park's walking tour of a quarter-mile 
takes you along a gravel path to view the wolves, along with four foxes, 21 
bison and one coyote. But the wolves--ambassador animals--are the big 
attraction.

The park specializes in wolf behavioral research, especially reproductive and 
interpack social behavior. Each wolf pack has its own rank and social 
structure.

The still-wild wolves demonstrate standard behaviors with the aid of human 
interpreters as part of Wolf Park lectures on wolf social structure, 
communication, behavior, handling methods and wolf research.

In addition, the center offers an array of multiday workshops with serious 
wolf study and wolf photography.
</content>

</doc>
