<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Dec 30 10:07:14 2003</date>
  <content>There is a story about a disgruntled farm wife who could never
be satisfied and she was known to put a slant on situations to gain
sympathy. Unhappy with her son who farmed on 50/50 shares with her, she
told family members, "He got a whole cow to butcher and I only got half a
cow. He is robbing me."

Not thinking through what she said, the family was furious at this son for
robbing his mother. Finally, someone woke up and asked, "What happened to
the other half of your cow?" The farm wife knew she had been caught and
sheepishly had to admit she didn?t need a whole cow and had sold the other
half.

In the fast pace we live, we choose not to take the time to "think" about
what we hear or read. We jump to our own conclusions based on the media
spin that forms the thoughts of the nation not thinking to question what
happened to the "other half." 
...
What really causes BSE? Apparently no one knows for certain. Most believe
it is from the feed supplement. However, Mark Purdy, an organic dairy
farmer from Somerset, England has a different theory.

Purdy refused to spray his cattle with organophosphates, a chemical
required by the British government to be used to fight the warble fly.
Purdy went to court to challenge the order and he was exempted from using
the spray on his farm. BSE was not found in Purdy?s herd. Purdy studied
the disease when it hit England and argues that mad cow disease is not
caused by a virus but is a result of organophospate pesticides and toxic
mineral overload.

Purdy believes the combination of milk replacer given calves and
organophosphates used to spray the cattle for the warble fly creates a
combination that produces extreme accumulations of manganese in the brain.
...
PETA is reported to be buying stock in meat processing companies and
restaurants such as Outback Steakhouse and Applebee's Restaurants. PETA
reportedly owns shares of Denny?s and Chili?s parent, Brinker
International as well as meat processing companies such as Hormel Foods,
Tyson Foods and Pilgrim?s Pride, according to The Meating Place.</content>

</doc>
