<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sun Jan 11 19:19:08 2004</date>
  <content>In 20 years of specialising in wild cuisine, chef He Dazhong said 
he has prepared at least 300 different types of exotic animals for the dining 
table.
He gave a brief recipe for the most common way of preparing civet cat: After 
the animal is killed and gutted, it is dipped into boiling water. The meat is 
fried in 200 deg C oil before stir-frying it with a special fragrant ye wei 
sauce which tastes slightly salty. If done right, civet cat has a unique 
fragrance and a 'dry, crunchy, fresh and sweet' taste, he said.
Customers are charged by the weight of the meat they order. At the Huang Pu 
Jiang Hotel, where chef He works, the dish can go for about 400 yuan (S$82) for 
1kg of civet cat meat.
Other popular ways of preparing wild cuisine include stewing or boiling the 
exotic animals for soup. Guangdong residents, especially in the rural areas, 
also prepare wild cuisine in their own homes.
Construction supervisor Chen Ming said he had his first taste of ye wei when 
he was seven years old.
He said game in general tastes best when caught in the wild, preferably 
boiled for soup. He has tucked into rodents, owls, even a cobra, though not civet 
cats.
Experts and ordinary residents alike say ye wei is rarely eaten, except 
during the winter months, when the exotic animals are thought to give a person's 
health a much-needed boost.
Chef He disagrees. He said: 'I don't think ye wei has any health benefits at 
all. The taste is unusual, but the effect, if any, is only psychological.'
Then why has he been in the trade for two decades? He answered: 'Because 
there is a demand.' -- Chua Chin Hon 

Vendors spend their time playing pool, knitting or complaining to visiting 
journalists how bad business is.
'I don't even have enough money for the trip back to my parents' home in 
Hunan,' said a stall helper.
Officials have seized thousands of civet cats and other exotic animals from 
markets such as Xinyuan, restaurants and breeding farms since China confirmed 
its first Sars case in six months last Monday.p Across town, in the northern 
outskirts of Guangzhou, the rows of up-market wild game restaurants have 
removed all signboards hawking exotic animals, or ye wei, as it is known here.</content>

</doc>
