<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 15:44:00 2003</date>
  <content>
 "BGH-treated milk is safe because it is
 indistinguishable from normal milk."

 Executive Branch Report on rbGH, February 9, 1994
 ________________________________

 "Milk from cows given supplemental bovine somatotropin is the
 same as any other milk... Unfortunately, a few fringe groups are
 using misleading statements and blatant falsehoods as part of a
 long-running campaign to scare consumers about a perfectly safe
 food."

 Statement of C. Everett Koop on Genetically engineered milk,
 February 6, 1994
 ________________________________

 "Five independent authorities, the Food and Drug Administration
 (FDA), National Institutes of Health (NIH), World Health
 Organization (WHO), the Journal of the American Medical
 Association (JAMA), and ex-Surgeon General C. Everett Koop had
 found rbGH-treated milk to be indistinguishable from
 normal milk."

 Monsanto (manufacturer of rbGH) Press Release, June, 1992
 ________________________________

 "Recombinant rbGH treatment produces an increase in the
 concentration of IGF-I in cow's milk."

 FDA review of genetically engineered milk SCIENCE,
 8/24/90, Vol 249
 ________________________________

 "After somidobove (rbGH) injection, mean IGF-I levels in the
 treated milk are always higher than those found in the controls."

 World Health Organization Report Geneva,
 Switzerland, June, 1992
 ________________________________

 "Levels of IGF increase in milk after cows are treated with rbGH."

 December, 1990 National Institutes of Health Assessment of Bovine
 Somatotropin
 ________________________________

 "A strong positive association was observed between IGF-I
 levels and prostate cancer risk."

 Science, vol. 279. January 23, 1998
 ________________________________

 "Insulin-like growth factor (IGF)-I, a mitogenic and
 antiapoptotic peptide, can affect the proliferation of
 breast epithelial cells, and is thought to
 have a role in breast cancer."

 The Lancet, vol. 351. May 9, 1998
 ________________________________

 "Insulin-like growth factors (IGFs), in particular IGF-I
 and IGF-II, strongly stimulate the proliferation of a variety
 of cancer cells, including those from lung cancer. High plasma
 levels of IGF-I were associated with an increased risk of lung
 cancer. Plasma levels of IGF-I are higher...in
 patients with lung cancer than in control subjects."

 Journal of the National Cancer Institute, vol. 91, no. 2.
 January 20, 1999.
 ________________________________

 "Insulin-like growth factor-1 (IGF-1) is expressed in many
 tumor cell lines and has a role in both normal cell proliferation
 and in the growth of cancers.

 Cancer Gene Ther, 2000 Mar, 7:3
 ________________________________

 "The insulin-like growth factor (IGF) system is widely involved
 in human carcinogenesis. A significant association between high
 circulating IGF-I concentrations and an increased risk of lung,
 colon, prostate and pre-menopausal breast cancer has recently
 been reported. Lowering plasma IGF-I may thus represent an
 attractive strategy to be pursued..."

 Int J Cancer, 2000 Aug, 87:4, 601-5
 ________________________________

 "...serum IGF-I levels increased significantly in the milk
 drinking group, but was unchanged in the control group."

 Journal of the American Dietetic Association,
 vol. 99, no. 10. October 1999



</content>

</doc>
