<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Apr 27 15:10:41 2004</date>
  <content>


Greetings to all Animal Protection Organizations.   
                
This project is about to close  and I need everyone who supports humane
education in our nation's
 schools to write a short note on letterhead if possible stating your
 support.  It can even be done via email now.  There are 3,000 animal
 related organizations in America and I'd hoped to have a majority. 
 So far, I've gotten just over 875 and clearly will not hit my goal by
 May 1 but would certainly like to have 1,000 letters if possible. 
 This will open doors for your organization as well since each state
 governor, each state legislative body and each state board of
 education will have a copy of your letter and be made aware of your
 efforts.
 
 We have one week left. Please send your letters and share this with
 others. Thank you so much.
 America CARES Coalition is an active participation of groups and
 individuals who 'think outside the box' in order to see the necessary
 improvements in today's animal protection efforts.
 
 
 
 
              
             Dear Animal Rights, Animal Protection and Animal Welfare
 organizations, Teachers and Parents,
 
             1-America CARES will do the actual mailing
 
             2-Your organization only need to send a letter via email
 to be included
 
             3-Read the cover letter below and see a sample letter of
 what we hope yours will say.
              
             "Recognizing that each individual organization would
 ultimately hope for the implementation of humane education programs
 in our nation's schools as well as the elimination of all political
 aspects that have prevented our efforts from moving further towards
 our goals, the America CARES Coalition has taken on the following
 project.  Realizing that each organization has their own goals and
 objectives that should be pursued in the way they see fit, this
 letter is only to show the 50 states' governors, legislators and
 board of educations, that we (all animal welfare, animal rights and
 animal protection organizations regardless of size) can stand
 together on one issue in agreement.  The signatures will be listed by
 organizational name in an alpha numerical order so as not to give any
 single participant extra 'weight' or notoriety among the remaining
 signatures.  We also realize that there is so much more that needs to
 be said, done and done in a variety of ways, but this letter is
 specifically written in very simple terms to eliminate the political
 wrangling as well as to show them, and well as ourselves, that it is
 possible for everyone to agree on something in a very public display
 of unity towards our nation's schools and the implementation of
 humane education  into the curriculum by the year 2010. By sending a
 simple letter with a definitive statement, this will show the vast
 number of voters and citizens that truly have an interest in seeing
 humane education included into our nation's schools. It is a letter
 to affect change. Each organization should continue to pursue their
 noble efforts in the way they have successfully established prior to
 this.  How each state implements this is the individual states'
 decision.   This will provide all organizations an opportunity to
 pursue the states with their ideas of how it could be included and
 under given guidelines guidelines."
            

</content>

</doc>
