<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov  3 09:12:51 2003</date>
  <content>Whether it’s family pets left behind in a flood or livestock hit with a 
disease, adverse impacts on animals during disasters affects the quality of 
life for humans. That’s the message articulated by veterinarian and 
internationally known animal health consultant Sebastian Heath during a 
recent presentation at the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture on 
the consequences of disasters on animal and human health.

According to Heath, who authored the book "Animal Management in Disasters," 
the fate of livestock during disasters or infectious disease outbreaks also 
has implications for human health and welfare. An example is foot and mouth 
disease. "It really wasn’t until the (2001) outbreak of foot and mouth 
disease in the United Kingdom that the federal government really started 
paying attention to animals and disasters, and really started thinking about 
the tremendous consequences that livestock could have on communities in 
general," Heath says.

He states impacts of an animal infectious disease such as foot and mouth are 
not just on animal health, but on social and financial systems as well. An 
example is the strong connection between livestock and feed grains. "For 
every 100,000 cattle we would kill or would go off feed because of foot and 
mouth disease, the global corn supply would increase by 8%. That means that 
for every 100,000 animals that would go off feed here in the U.S., the 
global corn price would come down. That could have serious implications for 
developing countries and other corn and soybean producing countries," Heath 
adds.

Heath explains we should develop serious and meaningful farm-based security 
programs to prevent the spread of animal infectious diseases. He also notes 
we, as a society, need to start looking at animal disease control within the 
broader context of hazard preparedness generally, and establish a continuum 
of preparedness for all kinds of disasters.

</content>

</doc>
