<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Sep 29 15:14:46 2003</date>
  <content>
Ten people are thought to have died during the past three
years from the side effects of over-the-counter drugs, such
as cold medications and hair-loss remedies, a health
ministry report revealed Friday.
About 1,200 cases of people dying from side effects of
medicines prescribed by hospitals are reported annually.
But
this is the first time the ministry has disclosed the
number
of deaths linked to over-the-counter drugs.
The figures were compiled by pharmaceutical manufacturers
and submitted to the Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare.
According to the report, three men died in 2000 after using
RiUP, a hair-loss remedy manufactured by Taisho
Pharmaceutical Co. The product contains minoxidil, which
can
stimulate hair growth when applied topically to the scalp.
A causal link between the three deaths and the product has
yet to be confirmed, according to the manufacturer's report
to the ministry.
Soon after RiUP hit shelves in 1999, complaints began
rolling in saying it caused heart palpitations and chest
pains. Following the reports, Taisho Pharmaceutical added a
label to the product's package in late 1999, warning people
suffering from angina or high blood pressure to take care
when using the product.
One woman, who was suffering from cirrhosis of the liver,
also died after taking Shosaikoto, a Chinese medicine said
to bolster liver functions. The woman died of interstitial
pneumonia, likely triggered by the drug.
The remaining six people died from anaphylactic shock-a fit
brought on by an allergic reaction-or severe skin disorders
after taking medication for colds or rhinitis-nasal
irritation and inflammation.
``Although the risk of developing side effects from
over-the-counter medicines is fairly low, there are a few
cases of grave side effects,'' a ministry official said.
``Please read the instructions (provided with the medicine)
carefully and stop using the product and consult a
physician
if you develop strange symptoms.''

A federal judge said Procter &amp; Gamble's
advertising for its over-the-counter heartburn drug strayed
too far from the truth with claims that it would provide 24
hours of relief.
Judge John E. Sprizzo said a week ago that he agreed with
the claims of a joint venture by Johnson &amp; Johnson and
Merck
&amp; Co., which said P&amp;G was cheating in its ads for Prilosec
OTC, an over-the-counter version of Prilosec, a heartburn
and ulcer drug. In a written ruling made public Friday,
Sprizzo explained why he granted a preliminary injunction
to
block the ads, which he concluded were "literally false."
He said one pill of Prilosec OTC, introduced nationwide
this
month, does not provide actual relief until up to four or
five hours after it is ingested, despite the company's
claims that it provides relief for a full 24 hours. Sprizzo
rejected P&amp;G arguments that the advertisement was true
because the relief lasts for 24 hours once it begins. "'One
pill. 24 Hours. Zero Heartburn,' simply does not equal 'One
pill. Wait five hours. Only then Zero Heartburn for the
next
24 hours,'" the judge wrote. P&amp;G did not immediately return
calls for comment.
Prilosec was once the world's best selling prescription
drug, generating over $6 billion in sales in 2000. However,
Prilosec's manufacturer, AstraZeneca, lost its patent on
the
drug last year.
</content>

</doc>
