<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Apr  8 16:23:44 2004</date>
  <content>
In his quest to make Montgomery County the no-kill capital of Texas and 
eradicate pet overpopulation, animal advocate Bruce Dailey is seeking help. 
 
Dailey recently formed NYPS (Neuter Your Pet Inc.), a spay/neuter nonprofit 
organization. He is searching for an experienced veterinarian, volunteers to 
distribute fliers and more animal-loving individuals to fill the board of 
directors.
Located on the corner of Texas 105 and Old Highway 105 in Cut and Shoot, NYPS 
will offer low-cost or free spay/neuter services in an effort to control the 
pet population and as an alternative to the "catch and kill" procedure 
outlined in the Montgomery County Animal Ordinance.
Owners who allow their pets to frequently propagate, laws that don't strictly 
enforce registration or mandatory neutering contribute to the crisis, Dailey 
said.
The surplus animals are routinely destroyed simply because they exist. The 
Montgomery County Animal Ordinance allows destruction of animals several days 
after being captured. There were 496 dogs and 155 cats euthanized in January, 
and 444 dogs and 219 cats in February.
"Out of 10,485 animals that were killed last year alone, if you took those 
poor animals and stretched them out two feet apart down the road, it would 
stretch out four miles," said Dailey, who turned 83 Monday. "Four miles of dead 
cats and dogs just last year. This is what NYPS is trying to do: We're trying to 
reverse that. Instead of catching and killing nine, we want to catch and 
neuter nine."
Getting information out to the public is one of the top priorities -- and 
biggest hurdles. Roughly 30,000 fliers need to be distributed countywide, and 
Dailey urges any prospective volunteers to contact NYPS at (936) 264-2323 and 
leave a message.
Finding an experienced vet and getting the equipment needed is another 
stumbling block. He did not receive any response to a recent ad requesting a 
veterinarian.</content>

</doc>
