<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 10 12:07:00 2003</date>
  <content>
Gretta and Ravi Hunjan, of Denver, are making all the necessary preparations 
for the arrival of their new baby in a few weeks, but mixed with their joy is 
a real concern for how 2 ?-year-old Zoey will respond.
"Zoey is our first 'child,' and she's completely the center of our 
attention," Gretta says. "We can't explain to her what's happening, and we're worried 
she'll feel jealous and neglected and may even try to hurt the baby somehow."
Zoey is a dog, a Lab mix that, Gretta says, "needs a lot of attention."
Such concern is neither unusual nor misplaced. Many dogs serve as surrogate 
children, and just as wise parents take steps to prepare older children for the 
arrival of a new sibling, so do they take steps to prepare the family pet as 
well.
Bastyr suggests playing a recording of baby sounds to help acclimate the 
dog. "When a baby comes there will be a lot of new sounds they haven't heard 
before," Bastyr says. "Especially screaming. They may mistake the baby's screams 
for a distress cry, which could make them engage in some predatory behavior."
Once the baby is born, bring home something with the baby's and mom's scent, 
Bastyr advises. Let the dog sniff it, and give him a treat.
When mom comes home from the hospital, Bastyr advises greeting the dog first, 
without the baby. After five to 10 minutes, bring the baby in and give the 
dog lots of praise and treats. "Then let the dog sniff and lick the baby's feet 
to get that first little taste," she says. "They'll be curious."
But never, ever leave even the best-behaved dog alone with a baby even for a 
few seconds, she warns.
Finally, there's the issue of the diapers. There's no polite way to say this, 
but just remember to keep the diaper pail secure and tightly locked at all 
times, lest your dog be tempted to help himself to a tasty treat. That's not 
just disgusting, it's also possibly harmful to the dog, as he could choke and 
possibly suffocate on a disposable diaper.
</content>

</doc>
