<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Thu Mar 18 05:13:54 2004</date>
  <content>nlike the football team, these Detroit lions looked like winners, 
even after a 1,500-mile, 30-hour ride from Motown to Texas in moving vans. 
Two aging lions formerly known by pet names Nikkia and Sheba sniffed around 
their new 3/8-acre enclosure Wednesday. 
They crept along its chain-link fences, and napped amid its rocks, trees and 
grass. 
If all goes well, the two Asian-African hybrid females, 20 and 18, will live 
another five to 10 years at Wildlife Rescue and Rehabilitation, a nonprofit 
refuge with about 500 animals. 
The two new guests, and two young African adults, a female and a mane-less, 
neutered male, were released into their new homes, secured by a 9-foot 
electrified fence, Wednesday morning. 
Their new environment includes jaguars, emus and a wooded hillside. Just 30 
miles from San Antonio, they'll have little human interaction, if sanctuary 
founder and executive director Lynn Cuny has her way ? again. 
In 1977, Cuny began taking in wild animals in her San Antonio back yard on 
Clower Street. 
Now, as the refuge nears completion of its move from Boerne to a 187-acre 
site near Kendalia, it is taking in its first lions, 400- to 600-pound 
meat-eaters. 
"This is part of the puzzle of creating a new sanctuary," Cuny said of the 
four lions from the Belle Isle Zoo, a branch facility associated with the 
Detroit Zoo. 
The younger cats were pets before living in a zoo. 
As a cub, the female was malnourished. In 1997, police found the male in a 
car's back seat ? and that's neglect, even in the Motor City. 
Detroit Mayor Kwame Kilpatrick cut funding for the 13-acre Belle Isle Zoo in 
2002. 
A lawsuit filed by the Detroit City Council to restore funding failed, and 
most of the zoo's 160 animals have since been moved to other zoos or 
sanctuaries. 
The four lions lived in a grassy enclosure at Belle Isle, but will have more 
room in Texas, said Scott Carter, director of conservation and animal welfare 
with the Detroit Zoological Institute, which donated $26,000 for the lions' 
new home. </content>

</doc>
