<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Tue Jun  8 08:49:37 2004</date>
  <content>

Below is a list of Ringling's false ad claims from PETA:

According to Ringling's latest ad campaign, "All our newborns come with a
lifetime guarantee." The Ringling ad goes on to claim that its
captive-breeding program is somehow helping endangered Asian elephants.
Ringling must believe that there is a sucker born every minute because
PETA has evidence that the ads are pure fantasy. Government documents
show that Ringling's elephants suffer abuse and die prematurely, that the
circus has been cited for more than 100 deficiencies in animal care, and
that most of its elephants were captured in the wild. PETA is calling on
the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to yank the bogus ads.

False Claim #1: "All our newborns come with a lifetime guarantee."
Reality: Ringling forcibly removes still-nursing baby elephants from
their mothers, causing trauma, harm, and even death. This barbaric
practice has contributed to the deaths of two baby elephants and to the
painful injuries of two others.

?
Ringling paid $20,000 to settle U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)
charges of failing to provide veterinary care to a dying baby elephant
named Kenny. Kenny was forced to perform despite obvious illness and was
found dead in his stall in a pool of bloody diarrhea.  ? Benjamin drowned
while trying to escape the pokes and prods of a handler chasing him with
a bullhook. Even though elephants are excellent swimmers, Benjamin had
never had the opportunity to learn how to swim from his mother.  ? When
taken from their mothers, Doc and Angelica suffered painful injuries as
they struggled in terror against ropes tightly binding their legs in a
futile attempt to rejoin their mothers. The ropes left raw wounds on
their legs.
Ringling trumpets the births of "15 bundles of joy" at its breeding
compound since 1992. In fact, four of the 15 births that Ringling is
taking credit for occurred at Busch Gardens, not Ringling's Elephant
Conservation Center, and belonged to an elephant trainer named Roman
Schmitt.

</content>

</doc>
