<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Sat Jan 31 22:15:54 2004</date>
  <content>

We have always lived with animals. Early settlers came into the area with 
horses or oxen, some of which pulled wagons over the difficult terrain. Dogs came 
too, alerting settlers to strangers, sometimes accompanying hunters. 
The earliest concern about animals appears in the minutes of the towns where 
laws were passed concerning pigs: Were they to be free boarders or would they 
be contained? 
Free boarding pigs were, of course, easier for the owner as the animals 
rooted around for food themselves, feasting on fallen nuts, roots and other 
edibles. Free ranging pigs, however, could also pose a threat to neighboring garden 
patches and sometimes to small children. In the Village of Ithaca, pigs were to 
be contained, although cows roamed the streets well into the 1820s. In the 
Town of Ulysses, pigs were allowed to roam and householders fenced garden plots 
to keep the destructive animals out. 
Care of animals was generally left up to the owners until the 1880s, when the 
Society for the Prevention of Crime, led by Professor Jones and Director 
Marsh, began a campaign to "clean up" Ithaca. Their concern included wayward 
youth, irresponsible fathers, young girls who walked along Aurora Street, and the 
treatment of animals. The SPC provided the spark that led to what we now know 
as the SPCA -- the Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals. 
An important aspect of animal care was animal training. We wanted the animals 
that lived with us, especially dogs, to behave well, and not to disturb or 
annoy our neighbors. Few people in the 20th century kept cows or pigs in the 
city, but many had dogs and their behavior became a concern. People didn't want 
dogs leaping out and frightening children or visitors. We began to think of 
dogs as well-behaved, home-tending family members. 
To become our ideal, dogs needed training. 
</content>

</doc>
