<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Nov 17 09:31:58 2003</date>
  <content>
Pets like these need a foster or adoptive home. 
A few volunteers are needed to help save some Triangle dogs' lives.
While the Durham Animal Protection Society is improving its shelter, 54 dogs 
need temporary homes through foster care or adoption.
Renovations will help the quality of life for the animals in the long run but 
if they can't find homes while the work is going on, the alternatives are not 
good.
There are more than 100 dogs that the APS of Durham routinely shelters at any 
one time. But beginning early next month, half of the dogs and puppies won't 
have any place to stay while a renovation project continues. That could mean a 
terrible outcome for some of these animals.
?Unfortunately we do have to humanely euthanize dogs that do not get placed 
into homes,? said Durham APS Manager Jennifer Sherian.
But the folks at the Durham APS always have the best interest of the dogs at 
heart. That's the whole reason for this million-dollar expansion and 
renovation project.
"We'll be able to house more animals with indoor/outdoor runs,? Sherian 
continued. ?Right now, because of the overpopulation that we're seeing we're having 
to house animals on both sides, meaning the animals do not have the luxury of 
sleeping and eating in one side of their run and urinating and defecating in 
the other side. It makes it very difficult for them. Just quality of life will 
be increased."
As part of the changes, the floors will be resurfaced and sealed and the 
walls will be repainted. Better facilities will also help fight disease, making 
for better efficiency and safety for both the staff and animals.
But without foster parents or more adoptions, many of these animals will have 
to pay the ultimate price for these improvements.
"It's just a very trying time with having to find homes whether through 
adoption or through fostering to place these animals during renovation, Sherian 
said. ?It's very stressful."
She adds if you can't help by adopting one of these Durham animals, the next 
best thing is to make sure pets are spayed and neutered. That will help fight 
this overcrowding at all shelters in the region.

</content>

</doc>
