<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>  <date>Mon Oct  6 15:05:44 2003</date>
  <content>


Kirkpatrick Sale referred to me and the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society 
in
his Sept. 29 commentary on the Earth Liberation Front, "These Elves Are Up
to More Than Mischief." He wrote that "ecotage," or eco-sabotage, began in
this country in 1977 when
I founded the Sea Shepherd Conservation Society. Sea Shepherd operates
outside of the U.S. primarily, and the organization has undertaken only one
action within the territory of the U.S., a completely legal opposition to
illegal whaling by the Makah tribe in
Washington state in 1998 and 1999.

The Sea Shepherd Conservation Society has been established as an
international marine wildlife conservation organization for almost three
decades. We don't commit crimes, and we do not support the use of criminal
tactics in our activities. We specialize in intervention against illegal
activities that exploit marine wildlife in international waters, where we
are empowered to intervene in accordance with the U.N. World Charter for
Nature. I resent the implication that our legal intervention against
high-seas poaching,
sea turtle poaching, illegal whaling, illegal drift nets and long lines and
the unlawful killing of baby seals can be connected to illegal crimes of
arson and sabotage committed by unknown perpetrators whom I don't know and
don't care to know. The least Sale could
have done was pick up a phone to question me directly or refer to
http://www.seashepherd.org 
These Elves Are Up to More Than Mischief
  The 'terrorist' fringe of the environmental movement is likely to cause
only destruction, not progress.

By Kirkpatrick Sale


The Earth Liberation Front's war to "stop the exploitation of the natural
world" has been escalating in recent weeks. A condominium complex being
built in San Diego was destroyed Aug. 1, SUV/Hummer dealerships in Los
Angeles County and Sante Fe, N.M., were attacked in August and early
September, and last week six homes under construction were torched, again 
in
San Diego County. Altogether the cost is estimated at $54 million, the most
extensive damage in any two months since ELF began its campaign of economic
sabotage in 1996.

The FBI calls all of this "domestic terrorism" and has even designated ELF
as the nation's No. 1 domestic terrorism threat. But ELFers-or elves, as
they sometimes call themselves-are not typical terrorists; they 
specifically
declare themselves to be "against harming any animal, human or nonhuman."
Their actions are aimed only at property, and in this they stand in a long
tradition of sabotage as political and economic protest, going back at 
least
as far as the Luddites in 19th century Britain. It's a tradition, though,
that does not provide much support for the idea that they will achieve 
their
goals, however much destruction they enact.

ELF's main goal is to inflict financial damage on property owned by people
seen, as an ELF statement has it, as "profiteering from the destruction and
exploitation of the natural environment" - whether by urban sprawl, the
motivation for the San Diego attacks, or air pollution, as with the 
Hummers.
Thus they hope to hit corporations, and the government agencies that aid
them, in "their pocketbooks," stopping specific eco-transgressions in the
short run but ultimately bringing down "capitalism and the mind-set that
allows it to exist." So far they claim to have inflicted more than $100
million worth of damage in eight years, which must seem a significant 
figure
to them, though it represents only a small part of the net worth of the
corporations they target and doesn't seem to be doing away with sprawl,
pollution or corporate capitalism.

Their second purpose is to encourage more people to take similar direct
action. "More and more actions need to be taken," an ELF statement says, 
"to
create an actual movement that continues to grow to successfully stop the
destruction of life." ELFers are not much interested in making people aware
of the abstract issues of development or deforestation or trying to help
mainstream environmental groups push through reforms, all of which they
scorn. "With one night's work," as they put it, "a few individuals can
accomplish what years of legal battles and millions of dollars most likely
did not."

And that really is all that ELF is: people deciding on their own, singly or
in small groups, to sabotage a target in their neighborhood that has
symbolic environmental meaning. It is not an organization. It doesn't have 
a
headquarters or officers or members, and it doesn't hold meetings or
marches. (It does, as seems inevitable these days, have a Web site.) Anyone
who wants to go out and set fire to an SUV dealership and then spray paint
"ELF" on the wreckage is an ELFer, and the motivation will be presumed to 
be
environmental and not, say, revenge or the insurance money.

This style of activism was borrowed from a group called the Animal
Liberation Front, which began in Britain in the mid-1970s and spread to the
United States, possibly by some of the same people.

Environmental sabotage - "ecotage," as it is sometimes called, or
"monkeywrenching" - goes back in this country at least to 1977, when Paul
Watson broke from Greenpeace to start the Sea Shepherd Conservation 
Society,
which has taken credit for incapacitating illegal fishing ships and
inflicting $2 million worth of damage to a whale-processing plant in
Iceland. And for a decade after its founding in 1980, Earth First!, like
ELF, encouraged anonymous ecotage, but it downplayed it in the early 1990s
because as a group with offices and meetings, it was too open to police
attention.

Thus the way was open for a group like ELF. It struck first in October 1996
in Oregon, where locks were glued shut and buildings spray-painted at
McDonald's outlets and a PR firm for Weyerhaeuser and Hyundai and a U.S.
Forest Service pickup truck was torched. More than 70 actions took place
across the country over the next seven years, perhaps the most spectacular
being the $25-million arson in October 1998 at a ski resort being built in
Vail, Colo., over fierce local environmental opposition. If ELF's goal,
however, is nothing less than the eradication of the capitalist system, it
is unlikely that ecotage will be the means. The problem is not with its
analysis, for indeed this is a system that depletes and exploits the 
Earth's
resources with scant regard for byproducts of pollution or extinction or
climate change. But - moral considerations aside - it is hard to see how
local economic sabotage can be an effective method of change.

ELFers may imagine that people will become outraged enough at our present
undoubtedly catastrophic assault on the Earth's environment to set fire to
SUV dealerships across the country, but the historical record shows little
reason to believe that this would stop the production of those cars, much
less destroy the Detroit manufacturers or the economic system itself.

Of course when your target is, essentially, Western civilization, it is 
hard
to know what strategy would work.
</content>

</doc>
